<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 November on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 November on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Behind New Species Swiss-Made</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/behind-new-species-swiss-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 09:35:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/behind-new-species-swiss-made/</guid>
      <description>e-BioDiv: data liberation, a first look  At today’s meeting of the Swiss Systematics Society, the species of the year — [a species discovered and described by a Swiss scientist](https://swiss-systematics.ch/en/new_species_swiss_made_20219 — will be selected.
Currently 89 species have been listed out of 31 publications, of which 69% are open access and 31% closed access, and the Revue Suisse de Zoologie is the most prolific journal. New species are hardly ever the only taxonomic treatment of a publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nov 8-12, 2021. Biohackathon Europe, Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the Biohackthon Europe. Each November ELIXIR organizes BioHackathon Europe, which brings together bioinformaticians from around the world. The event takes place in different locations around Europe. The BioHackathon offers an intense week of hacking, with over 160 international participants who work on diverse and exciting projects. The week starts with a half-day symposium to introduce these projects, and is followed by five days of hacking with one sole aim: coding to address problems in bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nov 5th, 2021. SSSDay 2021, Musée de Zoologie Lausanne</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the SSSDay organised by the Swiss Systematics Society (SSS) to answer questions regarding the Swiss universities funded eBiodiv project and the EU Horizon 2020 funded BiCIKL project. The event is hosted by the Musée de Zoologie Lausanne.
Schedule</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
