<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mission on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/mission/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mission on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:59:15 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/mission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plazi Mission</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:59:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/mission/</guid>
      <description>Plazi is a non-profit organisation founded in 2008 to promote the free accessibility of scientific data, in particular taxonomic treatments and images.&#xA;What are taxonomic treatments? A taxonomic treatment is the scientific description of a biological species, i.e. an animal species, a plant species, a fungus or a bacterium. If, for example, an unknown animal species is discovered today, a single individual of this species is selected, the so-called holotype. The species is then given a name that has not been used before and formed according to predefined rules, it is described scientifically and the description is published.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was macht Plazi?</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/mission-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:59:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/mission-de/</guid>
      <description>Plazi ist eine 2008 gegr체ndete Non-Profit-Organisation, die sich f체r die freie Zug채nglichkeit wissenschaftlicher Daten, insbesondere taxonomischer Treatments und Bilder, einsetzt.&#xA;Was sind taxonomische Treatments? Ein taxonomisches Treatment ist die wissenschaftliche Beschreibung einer biologischen Art, also einer Tierart, einer Pflanzenart, eines Pilzes oder eines Bakteriums. Wird heute beispielsweise eine noch nicht bekannte Tierart entdeckt, so wird ein einzelnes Individuum dieser Art ausgew채hlt , der sogenannte Holotype. Die Art wird dann mit einem bisher nicht verwendeten, nach vorgegebenen Regeln gebildeten Namen bezeichnet, sie wird wissenschaftlich beschrieben und die Beschreibung publiziert.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
