<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Activities on Plazi</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/</link><description>Recent content in Activities on Plazi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stage.plazi.org/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1 Million Treatments</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/1-million-treatments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/1-million-treatments/</guid><description>Over the next years, Plazi’s goal is to link 1 Million taxonomic name usages with their corresponding treatments. This will allow to bridge the gap from the general use of scientific names with the underlying taxonomic literature. It will provide a direct, citable link to the section in scientific articles that include the treatment and the implicit and explicit link to external resources.
The treatments are a unique sources for objects (i.</description></item><item><title>Bouchout Declaration</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/bouchout-declaration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/bouchout-declaration/</guid><description>The purpose of the Bouchout Declaration is to help make digital data about our biodiversity openly available. It offers members of the biodiversity community a way to demonstrate their commitment to open science.
As signatories, we encourage an overarching approach to Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management which is based on the following fundamental principles:
The free and open use of digital resources about biodiversity and associated access services; Licenses or waivers that grant or allow all users a free, irrevocable, world-wide, right to copy, use, distribute, transmit and display - the work publicly as well as to build on the work and to make derivative works, subject to proper attribution consistent with community - practices, while recognizing that providers may develop commercial products with more restrictive licensing.</description></item><item><title>Lectures</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/lectures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/lectures/</guid><description>Egloff W, Agosti D 2016. Legal and Ethical Reasons for Free and Open Biodiversity Information. XXV International Congress of Entomology (ICE 2016), Orlando, USA, 25-30 September, 2016 (Session 156 , Part 0672) doi: 10.5281/zenodo.165975
Agosti, D 2016. Where do we come from, where do we go to? 20 years of Open Access to biodiversity knowledge. XXV International Congress of Entomology (ICE 2016), Orlando, USA, 25-30 September, 2016 (Session 647 , Part 4332).</description></item><item><title>Legal Issues</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/the-blue-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/the-blue-list/</guid><description>Plazi is involved with its legal expertise in clarifying legal conditions for access and reuse of scientific information and developping principles on the legal interoperability of research data. In that persepctive, Plazi contributed to the following activities:
Analysis of European copyright and database law referring to the open exchange of scientific information [1] for Pro-iBiosphere (2014) ; Elaboration of a data sharing policy and a data sharing agreement [2] for the EU BON project (2014); Elaboration of principles on the legal interoperability of research data by the RDA-CODATA Interest Group (2015/2016).</description></item><item><title>The Blue List</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/legal-issues/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/activities/legal-issues/</guid><description>An impediment to open sharing of biological content is uncertainty as to whether and how intellectual property rights apply to biodiversity information. To clarify the situation, and in collaboration with the Global Names project, Plazi organized a workshop in Tempe, Arizona in April 2013 in which we brought together providers and users of taxonomic information, data managers, and Intellectual property Rights lawyers from Europe and the USA. The perspectives of interested parties were submitted via a SNARL (Scientific Names Attributes, Rights and Licensing) wiki.</description></item></channel></rss>