<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 18:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Biodiversity Literature Repository — Open By Design</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</guid>
      <description>Conference: SciDataCon—IDW 2022
Location: Seoul, S Korea &amp;amp; Virtual
Date and Time: 7-8:30 AM UTC, June 6, 2022
Session: Data Collaborations Across Boundaries
Abstract: The Open Definition version 2.1 prescribes four conditions for openness of a work &amp;ndash;
 it must be published under an open license or be in the public domain, it must be accessible easily and at no more than the cost of reproduction, preferably be downloadable via the internet it must be readily readable by a computer, and it must be available in an open format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcadia Fund supports Plazi in its endeavor to rediscover known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:25:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</guid>
      <description>The Swiss-based Plazi NGO has received a grant of EUR 1.5 million from Arcadia Fund – a charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin – to further develop its Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) established in collaboration with Zenodo, the open science repository hosted and managed by the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), and the open-access scholarly publisher and technology provider Pensoft.
Source: Eurekalert
  Figure left: A figure extracted from a scholarly article and made accessible via BLR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einen Einblick und Einstieg in die versteckte Vielfalt der 2021 publizierten Hymenopteren</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</guid>
      <description> Program Presentation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberation of data from taxonomic treatments</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:50:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will present its groundbreaking approach to the &amp;ldquo;liberation&amp;rdquo; of data from taxonomic treatments within scholarly publications at the World Biodiversity Forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will provide the lecture Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense except in the light of treatments at the conference of the Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections (SPNHC).
The goal of taxonomic literature is to describe taxonomic diversity as a result of charting the Earth&amp;rsquo;s biological diversity. As research adds to our knowledge, our understanding of taxa increases with additional published results. This is how it has happened since the standard publications by Linnaeus in 1753 and 1758 in the format of taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of text about a particular taxon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Known Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will provide a keynote lecture Discovering known biodiversity at the Empowering Biodiversity Research conference.
Abstract: We will take you on a journey into the world of biodiversity data standards and tools and will inform you on the latest developments in the world of Biodiversity Informatics, both internationally and locally. What is the state of the art in initiatives like GBIF, LifeWatch and DiSSCo, etc and how can we let them work for us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to taxonomic treatments mentioned in press releases</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</guid>
      <description>At year-end, it is common to review the past year’s highlights as we (Plazi) too did, highlighting a few of the almost 9000 species discovered in 2021. A few of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading taxonomic institutions did so as well with their recent discoveries. Since we are interested in not just finding about the species discovered but also learning more in detail about them, we decided to test how easy it was to locate their original taxonomic treatments in the scientific papers that described the species mentioned in the press releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Species of 2021</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/12/new-species-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 21:40:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/12/new-species-2021/</guid>
      <description>In 2021 Plazi provided access to the taxonomic treatments and figures of 8848 new species, 647 new genera and 27 new families discovered as part of 11391 changes in taxonomic status in 2021, published in 4420 articles from 95 journals. Here we present a small selection of 12 spectacular species with links to their complete taxonomic treatment. Since we can only protect what we know, we want people to have free access to taxonomic data, always and everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating genes sequences with data from herbarium sheets and publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/annotating-gene-sequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:40:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/annotating-gene-sequences/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: A snapshot of a published table showing the GenBank accession numbers and localities for the 507 individuals representing 61 species of Cladocera and 19 of Copepoda used in this study. DOI: https://doi.org/10.11646/zootaxa.1839.1.1     Figure 2: The same table as in Figure 1 extracted by TreatmentBank. Full table available in HTML and JSON formats.    Linking molecular data to taxonomic names and their extensive taxonomic treatments represents a fundamental component in biodiversity assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind New Species Swiss-Made</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/behind-new-species-swiss-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 09:35:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/behind-new-species-swiss-made/</guid>
      <description>e-BioDiv: processing data liberation  At today’s meeting of the Swiss Systematics Society, the species of the year — a species discovered and described by a Swiss scientist — will be selected.
Currently 89 species have been listed out of 31 publications, of which 69% are open access and 31% closed access, and the Revue Suisse de Zoologie is the most prolific journal. New species are hardly ever the only taxonomic treatment of a publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biohackthon Europe</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the Biohackthon Europe. Each November ELIXIR organizes BioHackathon Europe, which brings together bioinformaticians from around the world. The event takes place in different locations around Europe. The BioHackathon offers an intense week of hacking, with over 160 international participants who work on diverse and exciting projects. The week starts with a half-day symposium to introduce these projects, and is followed by five days of hacking with one sole aim: coding to address problems in bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSSDay Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the SSSDay organised by the Swiss Systematics Society (SSS) to answer questions regarding the Swiss universities funded eBiodiv project and the EU Horizon 2020 funded BiCIKL project. The event is hosted by the Musée de Zoologie Lausanne.
Schedule</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberating material citations as a 1st step to better data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/10/liberation-first-step-toward-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 14:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/10/liberation-first-step-toward-quality/</guid>
      <description>Our colleague Prof. Roderick Page recently wrote about quality issues with the data we are extracting from scientific literature and making available for anyone to use anywhere for any purpose. We are thankful for Rod&amp;rsquo;s insightful and helpful criticism. In this post (and several others to come), we explain material citations and other data that we extract, address the data quality issues — why they exist, what we are doing about them — and why the extracted data are still important and useful despite the inherent errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MaterialCitation accepted as a new TDWG Darwin Core standard</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-accepted-as-a-new-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-accepted-as-a-new-term/</guid>
      <description>On August 25, the new term request by Plazi for a new term for “a reference to or citation of one, a part of, or multiple specimens in scholarly publications” went through the public review process and resulted in the ratified term and in the Quick Reference Guide.
The original term name materialCitation has been changed to follow Darwin Core convention of using upper camel case for Class names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the world of biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</guid>
      <description>As we continue to connect people and biodiversity data globally by virtual means in these globally uncertain times, TDWG 2021 will be composed of symposia, workshops, contributed oral and poster presentations, demos, and discussions, as well as keynotes and social events. The Interest/Task Group working sessions will be held separately during the month following the virtual conference (November 2021). TDWG Symposia and TDWG Schedule
Oct 20, 8:30PM CET SYM18 Discovering known biodiversity: Digital accessible knowledge Session Type: Symposium (no unsolicited presentations considered)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</guid>
      <description>October 21, 2021: Beijing, China Plazi together with Data Futures, MNHN France, SIB Switzerland and CERN Switzerland will present the lecture &amp;ldquo;Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data.
Abstract: We report progress towards automatically transforming existing analyses of scientific literature into annotations based on W3C&amp;rsquo;s Web Annotation Data Model (WADM). Case studies are presented from the life sciences, and social sciences and humanities, in which these developments have led to the creation of new unrestricted data services for the research community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight is 20x20000</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/hindsight-is-20x20000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 12:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/hindsight-is-20x20000/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago we set off on a journey, guided by a philosophy that scientific data trapped in scholarly articles should be free, powered by the creativity and hardwork of a small team scattered around the globe, and supported by Arcadia Fund that decided to invest in our vision. Earlier this month we completed that journey, by all measures, a success. We liberated more data than we set out to liberate, we ended up with more partners than we started with, and we empowered more publications and publishers than three years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Accessible Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/digital-accessible-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/digital-accessible-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Digital Accessible Knowledge, in the context of Plazi, describes data fit for use to understand the global biodiversity, to create a list of all known species on planet Earth, data that is machine-actionable and ready for use by anybody, anyhwere at any time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBiodiv Launch</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</guid>
      <description>At the Naturhistorisches Museum in Bern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BHL and Plazi partnership</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/bhl-and-plazi-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/bhl-and-plazi-partnership/</guid>
      <description>BHL and Plazi have agreed to collaborate to create a workflow from existing literature to liberate digital accessible data to its reuse in GBIF. This includes the following steps:
 Find, digitize, and provide access to biodiversity-related documents with basic metadata and scanned images for each and every page Text recognition that allows efficient conversion and processing downstream Provide access at publication level, including standard, citable URLs from the scholarly communication ecosystem (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and Statistics</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/data-and-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/data-and-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Treatment Statistics and Article Statistics Introduction
This is an analysis and mining tool for the data contained in TreatmentBank. Access is provided at article and treatment level.
Select fields, explore and download Plazi treatment and article data and statistics in multiple formats. Selected fields turn from gray to green. Data on all materials (cited specimens) are available through the “Materials Citations Data” domain; these data are summarized by treatment in the “Materials Data” domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop data mining and extraction</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/desktop-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/desktop-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>GoldenGATE editor versions The GoldenGATE Document Editor is a visual editor for marking up documents in XML. It is designed to do most of the markup automatically; manual work is reduced to correcting the output of automated components. For these corrections, there are many specialized dialogs and document views, which display the required information in a concise fashion and provide high-level assistance to the user. In addition, the editor provides assistance for editing and marking up documents manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden Gate</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/golden-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/golden-gate/</guid>
      <description>Golden Gate is a family of software including a server, an editor, a web-based editor, and web-services. Golden Gate uses the Image Markup File (IMF) format for data storage, archival and exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Markup File (IMF)</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/image-markup-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/image-markup-file/</guid>
      <description>Image Markup File (IMF) is a file format used to store and exchange annotations made to a PDF reliably. IMF is an open source format. The file is based on a star schema with a series of CSV, PNG and the source file enclosed in a .ZIP file.
IMF can be created, opened with the open source editor GoldenGate, from where the parts can be exported as XML, or Darwin Core Archives or uploaded to TreatmentBank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocellus</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/ocellus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/ocellus/</guid>
      <description>Ocellus is a frontend to the Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) community with images on Zenodo, taxonomic treatments in TreatmentBank, and citations on RefBank. Ocellus depends on Zenodeo, a nodejs API that queries, analyzes and aggregates results from these various repositories via a single, unified interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schemas and Ontologies</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/schemas-and-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/schemas-and-ontologies/</guid>
      <description>TaxPub TaxPub is an extension to the U.S. National Library of Medicine/National Center for Biotechnology Information Journal Article XML Document Type Definition (DTD) providing domain-specific markup for taxonomic information in articles published in the area of biological systematics. TaxPub is described in detall in the article TaxPub: An Extension of the NLM/NCBI Journal Publishing DTD for Taxonomic Descriptions (See also TaxPub Documentation).
Currently, the following journals use TaxPub:
 Biodiversity Data Journal Cytogenetics Deutsche Entomologische Zeitschrift International Journal of Myriapodology Journal of Hymenoptera Research Mycokeys Nature Conservation Neobiota Nota Lepidopterologica Phytokeys Subterranean Biology Zookeys Zoosystematics and Evolution  TaxonX Taxonx is a XML schema for encoding taxonomic literature in order to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synospecies</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/synospecies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/synospecies/</guid>
      <description>SynoSpecies is a tool developed by FactsMission AG to leverage the RDF data provided by Plazi. The RDF data of all treatments is stored in an AllegroGraph triple store allowing SPARQL queries over the data. Synospecies allows manually writing and submitting such queries in the advanced mode and send such queries in the background when using the easier interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Treatment?</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/what-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/what-treatment/</guid>
      <description>The Plazi TreatmentBank deals with scientific, published, biosystematic literature documenting and describing all the world’s ca 1.9 Million known species in an estimated corpus of more than 500 Million published pages. The cited publications in Plazi are all available at the Biodiversity Literature Repository at Zenodo/CERN.
Treatments are well-defined parts of articles that describe the particular usage of a scientific name by an author at the time of the publication. In other words, each scientific name has one or more treatments, depending on whether there exists only an original description of a species, or there are subsequent re-descriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenodeo</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/zenodeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/zenodeo/</guid>
      <description>Zenodeo is a nodejs-based REST API to CERN&amp;rsquo;s Zenodo.
      const search = function(e) { const q = document.getElementById(&#39;q&#39;) const search_results = document.getElementById(&#39;search_results&#39;) fetch(`https://test.zenodeo.org/v3/treatments?q=${q.value}`) .then(function(response) { if (!response.ok) { throw new Error(&#39;HTTP error, status = &#39; + response.status); } return response.json(); }) .then(function(response) { search_results.innerHTML = `Zenodeo search results ${JSON.stringify(response, null, 4)}` }) e.stopPropagation() e.preventDefault() } window.onload = function(e) { const searchBtn = document.getElementById(&#39;searchBtn&#39;) searchBtn.addEventListener(&#39;click&#39;, search) }()  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>For questions, suggestions, contributions, please contact us via email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pardosa zyuzini, Kronestedt, Torbjörn &amp; Marusik, Yuri M., 2011</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/treatment-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/treatment-example/</guid>
      <description>Dashboard Here  Taxonomy Distribution Map Specimens Downloads Version History  Kronestedt, Torbjörn &amp;amp; Marusik, Yuri M., 2011, Studies on species of Holarctic Pardosa groups (Araneae, Lycosidae). VII. The Pardosa tesquorum group, Zootaxa 3131, pp. 1-34: 25-28
   scientific name Pardosa zyuzini     status sp. nov.   publication ID http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.399649   persistent identifier http://treatment.plazi.org/id/730087F2-1E00-FF81-FF61-FC34FDA561A5   treatment provided by Plazi (2016-04-12 02:05:59, last updated by Leidenlab19 2019-12-06 14:06:18)    Treatment Pardosa zyuzini sp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biodiversity Literature Repository</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/biolit-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/biolit-repo/</guid>
      <description>Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) is a Zenodo-community to share publications related to bio-systematics. It has been initiated by Plazi, Pensoft and Zenodo at CERN.Its goal is to provide open access to publications cited in publications or in combination with scientific names and to provide in collaboration with Zenodo a digital object identifier (DOI) to the publications to enable citation of the publications, including direct access to its digital representation. Its focus is on thematic corpora, such as particular taxonomic groups, eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioWikiFarm</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/biowikifarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/biowikifarm/</guid>
      <description>Biowikifarm is a shared technical platform supporting a number of mediawiki installations used by a large number projects in biological research for open content publishing. The primary purpose of the shared platform is to be able to maintain the published data and information in a long term sustainable way, to work more efficiently and distribute administrative and maintenance work among several partners. Furthermore, the biowikifarm operates a shared media repository, enabling synergies in re-using media content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeds</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/resources/feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/resources/feeds/</guid>
      <description>Plazi offers RSS feeds for extracted treatments and updates via Twitter
 Notification  RSS-feed (html) RSS-feed (XML)   Twitter  Plazi Treatment Repo Plazi    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/privacy/</guid>
      <description>This privacy policy sets out how Plazi uses and protects any information that you give Plazi” when you use this website.
Plazi is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.
Plazi may change this policy from time to time by updating this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RefBank</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/refbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/refbank/</guid>
      <description>RefBank is a website where you can search for bibliographic references. No registration is required (everyone can upload and edit). Results can be converted in different styles and formats. It serves as the “dirty bucket” of references and source for “clean buckets” such as the references in the Biodiversity Literature Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReFindit</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/refindit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/refindit/</guid>
      <description>ReFindit provides an easy search function, based on a simple interface, which also collates and sorts the results from the search engines for presentation to the user to read and with the option to refine the results presented or submit a new search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schemas and Ontologies</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/resources/schema-and-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/resources/schema-and-ontologies/</guid>
      <description>TaxPub TaxPub is an extension to the U.S. National Library of Medicine/National Center for Biotechnology Information Journal Article XML Document Type Definition (DTD) providing domain-specific markup for taxonomic information in articles published in the area of biological systematics. more
TaxonX Taxonx is a XML schema for encoding legacy taxonomic literature in order to identify taxonomic treatments and lover level textual data such as scientific names, localities, morphological characters, and bibliographic citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bibliography of Life</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/resources/bol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/resources/bol/</guid>
      <description>The Bibliography of Life (BoL) is a contribution towards building a reference bibliography for biodiversity with direct citable, open access to digital object of bibliographic references.
Biodiversity Literature Repository  Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) is a Zenodo-community to share publications related to bio-systematics. It has been initiated by Plazi, Pensoft and Zenodo at CERN.Its goal is to provide open access to publications cited in publications or in combination with scientific names and to provide in collaboration with Zenodo a digital object identifier (DOI) to the publications to enable citation of the publications, including direct access to its digital representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment Data Access</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/treatment-data-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/treatment-data-access/</guid>
      <description>Access to Plazi Treatments  What is a treatment? What is a DarwinCore Archive? The Darwin Core Archive used by Plazi Treatment Data representation in Plazi   Plazi API  Obtaining a list of all the treatments available from Plazi HTTP GET - RSS HTTP GET - ZIP Archive HTTP GET - Page displaying Treatment HTTP GET - generic XML HTTP GET - TaxonX   List of Plazi&amp;rsquo;s available DwC-Archives from GBIF API  HTTP GET - JSON   Appendix: Darwin Core Archive Content Further reading Downloads Support and Questions Version  Access to Plazi Treatments What is a treatment?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TreatmentBank</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/treatmentbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/treatmentbank/</guid>
      <description>TreatmentBank is a resource that stores and provides access to the treatements and data therein.
 Latest Treatments        const search = function(e) { const q = document.getElementById(&#39;q&#39;) const search_results = document.getElementById(&#39;search_results&#39;) //const tb = &#39;https://tb.plazi.org/GgServer/search?fullText.matchMode=prefix&amp;fullText.ftQuery=&#39; + q.value fetch(`https://test.zenodeo.org/v3/treatments?q=${q.value}`) .then(function(response) { if (!response.ok) { throw new Error(&#39;HTTP error, status = &#39; + response.status); } return response.json(); }) .then(function(response) { let res = &#39;Treatments search results&#39; response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/statistics/</guid>
      <description>This is an analysis and mining tool for the data contained in TreatmentBank. Access is provided at article and treatment level. Documentation is available.
The user can select fields and download Plazi treatment data in multiple formats. Selected fields turn from gray to green. Data on all materials (cited specimens) are available through the “Materials Citations Data” domain; these data are summarized by treatment in the “Materials Data” domain. Select the relevant operation (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TreatmentBank API</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/treatmentbank-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/treatmentbank-api/</guid>
      <description>What is a treatment? The Plazi TreatmentBank [1] deals with scientific, published, biosystematic literature. It is the literature documenting and describing all the world’s ca 1.9 Million known species in an estimated corpus of over 500 Million published pages. The cited publications in Plazi are all available at the Biodiversity Literature Repository [2] at Zenodo/CERN.
Treatments are well defined parts of articles that define the particular usage of a scientific name by an author at a given time (the publication) [3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization Tools</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/visualization-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/data-apis-tools/visualization-tools/</guid>
      <description>All the data extracted from the taxonomic literature is available for visualization. For that Plazi offers a tool to create a number of Google Charts. Please read the documentation on using the visualization tools and an overview of the available fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>All our publications are published under open licenses. If you are unable to locate a copy, please contact us and we will be happy to send it to you.
2022  Fawcett S, Agosti D, Cole SR, Wright CF 2022. Digital accessible knowledge: Mobilizing legacy data and the future of taxonomic publishing. Bulletin of the Society of Systematic Biologists 1(1): 1-12. doi Penev L, Koureas D, Groom Q, Lanfear J, Agosti D, Casino A, Miller J, Arvanitidis C, Cochrane G, Hobern D, Banki O, Addink W, Kõljalg U, Copas K, Mergen P, Güntsch A, Benichou L, Benito Gonzalez Lopez J, Ruch P, Martin CS, Barov B, Hristova K (2022) Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library (BiCIKL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The digital age and the tragedy of not knowing what we know about biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/not-knowing-what-we-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/not-knowing-what-we-know/</guid>
      <description>One of the big challenges in biology - how many species are on planet Earth, where do they live and what do they do - is increasingly relevant in the age of the biodiversity crisis. In the digital age this turns awkward, because it becomes obvious that we do not even know what we know about biodiversity. Whilst the libraries have been the undisputed source of knowledge in the analogue age, having hard copies in libraries does not serve the needs anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biowikifarm</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/services/biowikifarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/services/biowikifarm/</guid>
      <description>biowikifarm.net is a shared technical platform supporting a number of mediawiki installations used by a large number projects in biological research for open content publishing. The primary purpose of the shared platform is to be able to maintain the published data and information in a long term sustainable way, to work more efficiently and distribute administrative and maintenance work among several partners. Furthermore, the biowikifarm operates a shared media repository, enabling synergies in re-using media content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi Members</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/members/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti
Taxonomic literature, systematics and conservation
President Plazi
Director Plazi GmbH
Research Associate
Naturhistorisches Museum, Bern
Berne, Switzerland
agosti@plazi.org  Klemens Böhm
Member of Board (2008-)
Professor
Lehrstuhl für Systeme der Informationsverwaltung
Karlsruher Institute of Technology
Karlsruhe, GERMANY
boehm@kit.edu  Terry Catapano
Lead developer of TaxonX XML schema and Taxpub Extension of the NLM/NCBI JATS DTD
Vice-President Plazi
Columbia University
New York, USA
catapano@plazi.org  Hong Cui
Natural language processing, character modeling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>materialCitation as a new class submitted to TDWG Darwin Core standard</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-submitted-as-a-new-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-submitted-as-a-new-term/</guid>
      <description>Specimens are a critical basis for taxonomic research. They are cited in taxonomic treatments and other works. Increasingly these material citations are extracted from publications and submitted as part of data sets to GBIF and reused in studies.
As of today, GBIF includes 33,393 datasets derived from taxonomic publications and 415,858 material citations which are labeled as occurrences. 335 publications reuse this data. An estimate of 45,000 species are only represented in GBIF through material citations from publications, mainly covering new species that are extracted from the literature just after the publishing time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Issues</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/services/legal-issues-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/services/legal-issues-menu/</guid>
      <description>Over the next years, Plazi’s goal is to link 1 Million taxonomic name usages with their corresponding treatments. This will allow to bridge the gap from the general use of scientific names with the underlying taxonomic literature. It will provide a direct, citable link to the section in scientific articles that include the treatment and the implicit and explicit link to external resources.
The treatments are a unique sources for objects (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</guid>
      <description>Zenodo Zenodo, Plazi and Pensoft collaborate in developing the Biodiversity Literature Repository as an open access repository to articles and liberated open FAIR data including figures and taxonomic treatments related to biodiversity. A customized access is provided for all its content via the BLR website and to images via Ocellus.
read more
GBIF Plazi joined GBIF 2001 and is since 2015 an associate participant of GBIF. Plazi provides occurrences liberated and extracted from the scientific literature, especially from treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bouchout Declaration</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/services/bouchout-declaration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/services/bouchout-declaration/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of the Bouchout Declaration is to help make digital data about our biodiversity openly available. It offers members of the biodiversity community a way to demonstrate their commitment to open science.
As signatories, we encourage an overarching approach to Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management which is based on the following fundamental principles:
 The free and open use of digital resources about biodiversity and associated access services; Licenses or waivers that grant or allow all users a free, irrevocable, world-wide, right to copy, use, distribute, transmit and display - the work publicly as well as to build on the work and to make derivative works, subject to proper attribution consistent with community - practices, while recognizing that providers may develop commercial products with more restrictive licensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ongoing and past projects</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/projects/</guid>
      <description>Current Projects Arcadia 2022-2025 The grant will help build on the momentum created in the first Arcadia supported project (years 2018-2021) by: (1) leading the data extraction effort and building a critical mass of FAIR scientific data and related tools involving the community; and (2) establishing a long lasting, self-sustaining research infrastructure.
 BiCIKL (EU) Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library (BiCIKL) is building the Biodiversity Knowledge Hub (BKH). more</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new GBIF Plazi data issue feedback loop</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/data-issue-feedback-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/data-issue-feedback-loop/</guid>
      <description>Plazi’s goal is to discover known biodiversity, and make it widely available using the tools available in the digital age. This means liberating data hidden in libraries, and more recently, and increasingly hidden in the PDF-prison, paywalls and unstructured text.
The grand challenge is an estimated 500 Million published pages of scholarly biodiversity related publications, and 17,000 annually new discovered and described species with a multiple of annotations on already known species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blue List</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/services/the-blue-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/services/the-blue-list/</guid>
      <description>An impediment to open sharing of biological content is uncertainty as to whether and how intellectual property rights apply to biodiversity information. To clarify the situation, and in collaboration with the Global Names project, Plazi organized a workshop in Tempe, Arizona in April 2013 in which we brought together providers and users of taxonomic information, data managers, and Intellectual property Rights lawyers from Europe and the USA. The perspectives of interested parties were submitted via a SNARL (Scientific Names Attributes, Rights and Licensing) wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/lectures/</guid>
      <description>Lectures by Plazi team members are available at BLR and SlideShare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses of Data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/services/uses-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/services/uses-of-data/</guid>
      <description>Publications on-going Publications using GBIF datasets including Plazi mediated datasets
2017 Hugo W, Hobern D, Kõljalg U, Ó Tuama É, Saarenma H 2017. Global Infrastructures for Biodiversity Data and Services. In: Walters M and Scholes RJ (eds.), The GEO Handbook on Biodiversity Observation Networks, doi: 10.1007/978-3-319-27288-7_11)
2016 Alonso LA, Agosti D 2016. Ants. In: Larsen TH (ed.) 2016. Core Standardized Methods for Rapid Biological Field Assessment. Conservation International, Arlington, VA. pp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story behind Plazi</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</guid>
      <description>Placidus a Spescha was not only one of the first alpinists and naturalists but was also deeply committed to the ideals of the Enlightenment. He often ran afoul of his superiors who felt he neglected his priestly duties in favor of his scientific pursuits. Worse yet, he further upset the status quo through his sympathy and support of the French in the follow-up of the wars spurred by the French Revolution which brought invading French and Austrian troops into his home, Disentis, in the Vorderrhein Tal in Switzerland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClickUp supporting Plazi with task management system </title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/clickup-supporting-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/clickup-supporting-plazi/</guid>
      <description>Managing collaborations involving multiple locations, time zones and complementing operations is challenging. As an example, Plazi liberates data from scholarly publications by making it, in collaboration with Zenodo at CERN, findable, citable reusable for anybody, anywhere, at any time. This process happens in multiple locations in Europe, Brazil and North America. The increasingly automated processes are based on agile programming. The maintenance and improvement of high quality data requires an additional amount of time critical interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for an interim review of Plazi’s Covid-19 related activities</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/time-for-an-interim-review-of-plazis-covid-19-related-activities/3e26b3bc95a4b39f0a2a9d7fccee8b19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/time-for-an-interim-review-of-plazis-covid-19-related-activities/3e26b3bc95a4b39f0a2a9d7fccee8b19/</guid>
      <description>Three months ago we started with Pensoft an effort (see also press release) to contribute to a better understanding of the SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2) aka corona virus that led to the global COVID-19 pandemic, and in the followup joined the CETAF-Covid-19 task force. With the end of the three months long taskforce we present here our view. A multimedia presentation by the knowledge base task force sub group has been streamed on July 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The taxonomic treatments from Linnaeus’ Systema Naturae, 1758, 10th edition, liberated</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/linnaeus-systema-naturae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/linnaeus-systema-naturae/</guid>
      <description>Taxonomic treatment. The taxonomic treatment is a well defined part of a publication about a particular taxon, in this case of the honey bee Apis mellifera, described by Linnaeus 1758 on page 576-577. It is based on the implicitly cited specimens in his reference collection.
A milestone in the development of modern biology was the introduction of the standardization resulting from comparative and reference works. This led to a rapidly growing corpus of knowledge by learning from, referencing of, and building on previous work, today known as the data life cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended collective licence agreement between Plazi and ProLitteris: Plazi adopts to revised copyright law in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/agreement-between-plazi-and-prolitteris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/agreement-between-plazi-and-prolitteris/</guid>
      <description>On the 1st of April, 2020, a new copyright law was enacted in Switzerland. Amongst other revision points, it declares an extension of the protection of photographs by applying the notion of work to non-individual photographs, provides for a new copyright exception for the use of copyrighted works for purposes of scientific research, and introduces extended collective licenses as a new instrument for collective copyright regulation. As the Plazi workflow is organised and ruled by Swiss copyright law, Plazi had to adapt to these legal amendments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi and Pensoft launch an initiative to provide access to scholarly published data about Coronavirus hosts</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/coronavirus-hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/coronavirus-hosts/</guid>
      <description>Read the Eurekalert! and Knoweldge Speak release.
The COVID-19 pandemic presumably started with the escape of the Coronavirus from its bat host to humans. To understand the original host, it is important to have access to relevant scientific knowledge about these organisms. The scientific results from charting the world’s biodiversity reside in a vast corpus, which is often “imprisoned” by paywalls, copyright laws or trapped in formats unfavorable to text and data mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Role of Open Science in Charting Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/open-science-charting-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/open-science-charting-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>A striking example of the impact of open access on the usage of scientific publications. Around 2000 antbase.org, co-funded by the Atherton-Seidal Foundation at the Smithsonian Institution provided open access to the entire ant taxonomic literature. Within a very short time, this resource has been used world wide. DOI: 10.5281/zenodo.1343376
Following discussions on Taxacom list server on the value on Open Science, here some points to consider.
The situation has changed regarding open access and open science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 new species added to GBIF during the first Plazi training course at the Congresso Brasileiro de Zoologia</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/first-plazi-training-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/first-plazi-training-course/</guid>
      <description>Plazi Minicurso at the Congresso Brasileiro de Zoologia, March 1, 2020
Taxonomic literature is an almost untapped resource of data covering our scholarly knowledge of biodiversity. This includes an estimated 500 Million printed pages and is augmented annually with over 17.000 taxonomic treatments of species new to science. This data represents in fact an incredibly rich citation network, albeit with most of the citations implicit, only understandable by extensive domain expertise, and often with an insurmountable time required to follow up chasing the cited resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Der geplante Lichtbildschutz Artikel (Art 2 Abs. 3bis) behindert Forschung und IT-Industrie</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/lichtbildschutz-artikel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/lichtbildschutz-artikel/</guid>
      <description>Am kommenden Montag (21.1.2019) berät die Kommission for Wissenschaft, Bildung und Kultur (WBK) des schweizerischen Ständerates die Revision des Urheberrechtsgesetzes. Nach dem jetzigen Revisionsentwurf sollen in Zukunft auch Fotografien, welche keinen individuellen Charakter haben, wie Werke der Kunst und der Literatur geschützt werden. Wir sind der Meinung, dass durch eine solche Bestimmung der wissenschaftlichen Lehre und Forschung, und letztlich unserer IT Industrie und Gesellschaft, erheblicher Schaden zugefügt wird, und zwar aus den folgenden Gründen:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training for building and reusing your corpus of mineable taxonomic literature</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/mineable-taxonomic-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/mineable-taxonomic-literature/</guid>
      <description>Visualization of data liberated from 22 published articles in the journals Zootaxa and PLoS ONE during the training course at Leiden University&amp;rsquo;s Integrative Taxonomy course.
The taxonomic literature is a rich, high quality, and largely untapped source of biodiversity knowledge. Taxonomy helps us recognize species and map their distributions through text descriptions, images, and records of when and where they have been observed. These are the data we need to answer questions that are relevant to our world today, like setting conservation priorities and anticipating the effects of climate change on biodiversity and ecosystem functions that affect the lives of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need BLR to store scholarly taxonomic articles?</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/blr-scholarly-taxonomic-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/blr-scholarly-taxonomic-articles/</guid>
      <description>When Jérôme Constant published yesterday his taxonomic article on eurybrachid planthopper insects in the European Journal of Taxonomy, its data became immediately accessible as FAIR and open access data in TreatmentBank including taxonomic treatments, and the Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) as an article and figures.
This data is also at the same moment reused by GBIF to describe the dataset aka article, to list all its material citations, provide the taxonomic treatments for the included species, which is especially valuable for those new to the sciences or an individual occurrence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schnappschüsse und das Urheberrecht (Snapshots and copyright law)</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/schnappschuesse-urheberrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/schnappschuesse-urheberrecht/</guid>
      <description>The Thursday November 29, 2018 (doi) issue of the Neue Zürcher Zeitung includes a “Gastkommentar” by me (Donat Agosti) arguing that the proposed insertion of an article protecting any kind of photographs of three dimensional objects in the revised copyright law of Switzerland is misguided (Art. 2 al.).
In the sciences, illustrations, including photographs, play a crucial role. They are one among many types of research data, and are used to visually document and compare results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provenance – another look at taxonomic treatments and names</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/provenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/provenance/</guid>
      <description>When an &amp;lsquo;ex banker&amp;rsquo; - Tim Robertson - meets an &amp;lsquo;ex taxonomist&amp;rsquo; - Donat Agosti - this can be very inspiring, especially when they discover that they share rather unexpectedly more than they ever expected. So, what is it?
Both share data lineages. The banker has bank accounts that are created, mutated and that have at a given time a certain value. The taxonomist has species that are described, mutated and at a given time have a certain name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZooKeys 10th anniversary</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/zookeys-10th-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/zookeys-10th-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Zookeys at 10
Happy Birthday Zookeys, and congratulations to Pensoft, its innovator and publisher.
Today’s 10th anniversary of Zookeys is a great day for biodiversity. The discoveries reported in the press release and celebrated in the 770th issue of the journal are magnificent and open access, unlike the big bulk of taxonomic articles.
The real and unreported impact of Zookeys, its sister Biodiversity Data Journal and the many other natural history journals hosted by Pensoft is neither reported by Pensoft, widely recognized by the taxonomists nor the wider scientific community: The revolution caused, and enabled by, the technical changes adopted in the publishing of Zookeys and the subsequent journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi and BLR receive €1.1 million from Arcadia Fund to open up new biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/arcadia-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/arcadia-fund/</guid>
      <description>Visual search results from the Biodiversity Literature Repository. Each of the images provides access to the taxonomic treatment of the species or the source article. Only figures from scholarly publications are provided.
Plazi has received a grant of EUR 1.1 million from Arcadia – the charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin – to liberate data, such as taxonomic treatments and images, trapped in scholarly biodiversity publications.
The project will expand the existing corpus of the Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR), a joint venture of Plazi and Pensoft, hosted on Zenodo at CERN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 years of Plazi. On expedition to discover the known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/10-years-of-plazi-on-expedition-to-discover-the-known-biodiversity/2136104073c3aabdebe6c5067d767a52/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/10-years-of-plazi-on-expedition-to-discover-the-known-biodiversity/2136104073c3aabdebe6c5067d767a52/</guid>
      <description>This is the view of Donat Agosti, cofounder of Plazi.
In 1992, I wrote an article in the followup of the Rio Earth Summit in the Swiss newspaper Neue Zürcher Zeitung titled “Brauchen wir zu wissen, wie viele Arten es gibt?» Now, 2018, we are still discussing this question, and I am still convinced we should. Should, because we still don’t know know the answer. But must, because of the rapidly increasing, unprecendented loss of biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 years of Plazi. On expedition to discover the known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/10-years-of-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/10-years-of-plazi/</guid>
      <description>This is the view of Donat Agosti, cofounder of Plazi.
In 1992, I wrote an article in the followup of the Rio Earth Summit in the Swiss newspaper Neue Zürcher Zeitung titled “Brauchen wir zu wissen, wie viele Arten es gibt?» Now, 2018, we are still discussing this question, and I am still convinced we should. Should, because we still don’t know know the answer. But must, because of the rapidly increasing, unprecendented loss of biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200.000 deposits at the Biodiversity Literature Repository!</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/200000-deposits-at-blr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/200000-deposits-at-blr/</guid>
      <description>Ocellus: Search term &amp;ldquo;Perlidae&amp;rdquo;. All the images are provided with a link to the source.
The wealth of data encapsulated in scientific publications is a well-guarded secret. The recent discussions around Open Access are centered around open access to the articles, and thus little effort is made to build an index, for example, of all the illustrations therein. This is even more astounding in descriptive sciences, such as biological taxonomy, dealing with discovering and describing the world’s biological diversity, where each article includes an average of 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pensoft and Plazi join forces to expedite building the OpenBioDiv</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/building-openbiodiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/building-openbiodiv/</guid>
      <description>Pensoft - Plazi project to produce semantically enhanced data
Open Science is based on open data. Data per se is not copyrighted and thus freely accessible. However it is kept in well maintained prisons, such as hard disks on a scientist’s desk to large password protected databases to publications that lost all their semantic structure in transition from a scientists lab to the publishers print shop. To paraphrase, scientist do all to loose structure in their data in publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2018</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/happy-new-year-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/happy-new-year-2018/</guid>
      <description>2017 has been a productive year at Plazi.
 9,601 articles have been processed from 173 different journals resulting in 82,082 taxonomic treatments, 62,958 scientific figures uploaded to the Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR), including 314,881 bibliographic references of which 37,120 have a digital object identifier (DOI). The 3,177 articles published in 2017 that we mined for data included one new family, 330 new genera and 5,145 new species, and a total of 30,091 taxonomic treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
