<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 18:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BHL and Plazi partnership</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/bhl-and-plazi-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 17:38:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/bhl-and-plazi-partnership/</guid>
      <description>Today BHL announced a &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/15QbYAuOyGkpS68YWlfpj0rdsZrl_oTWA/view&#34;&gt;partnership&lt;/a&gt; with Plazi BLR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/partners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wikidata
Plazi [https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q7203726] initiated in Wikidata
[https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Wikidata:Main_Page] accesss to treatments
[https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Property:P1992] and data included therein, and
through this provides access to all the treatments hold in TreatmentBank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;read more [http://plazi.org/cooperation/projects/wikidata/]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zenodo
Zenodo and Plazi collaborate in developing the Biodiversity Literature
Repository
[http://plazi.org/cooperation/resources/biblio&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The digital age and the tragedy of not knowing what we know about biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/the-digital-age-and-the-tragedy-of-not-knowing-what-we-know-about-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:19:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/the-digital-age-and-the-tragedy-of-not-knowing-what-we-know-about-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>One of the big challenges in biology - how many species are on planet Earth,
where do they live and what do they do -  is increasingly relevant in the age of
the biodiversity crisis. In the digital age this turns awkward, because it
becomes obvious that we do not even know what we know about biodiversity. Whilst
the libraries have been the undisputed source of knowledge in the analogue age,
having hard copies in libraries does not serve the needs anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/contribute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Help us in our mission to liberate dagta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute reviews via writing a blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute good vibes via telling your friends about us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for checking us out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This privacy policy sets out how Plazi uses and protects any information that
you give Plazi” when you use this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plazi is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you
to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this
website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with
this privacy statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plazi may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should
check this page from time to time t&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>For questions, suggestions, contributions, please contact us via email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schemas and Ontologies</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/resources/schemas-and-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/resources/schemas-and-ontologies/</guid>
      <description>TaxPub, TaxonX and Treatment Ontology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TreatmentBank</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/resources/treatmentbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/resources/treatmentbank/</guid>
      <description>Scientists describe and communicate the discovery of new biological species with taxonomic treatments that are bound to the names used to refer to these taxa. Often they are very rich in content and increasingly linked to external resources. TreatmentBank is a resource that stores and provides access to the treatements and data therein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/api-and-tools/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:54:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/api-and-tools/api/</guid>
      <description>API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses of Data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/about/uses-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 12:37:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/about/uses-of-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;on-going&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.gbif.org/resource/search?contentType=literature&amp;publishingOrganizationKey=7ce8aef0-9e92-11dc-8738-b8a03c50a862&#39;&gt;Publications using GBIF datasets including Plazi mediated datasets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2017&lt;/h3&gt;Hugo W, Hobern D, Kõljalg U, Ó Tuama É, Saarenma H 2017. Global</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi Members</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/about/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 12:27:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/about/members/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donat Agosti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klemens Böhm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terry Catapano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Cui&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>materialCitation as a new class submitted to TDWG Darwin Core standard</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-as-a-new-class-submitted-to-tdwg-darwin-core-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:37:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-as-a-new-class-submitted-to-tdwg-darwin-core-standard/</guid>
      <description>Specimens are a critical basis for taxonomic research. They are cited in taxonomic treatments and other works. Increasingly these material citations are extracted from publications and submitted as part of data sets to GBIF and reused in studies.
As of today, GBIF includes 33,393 datasets derived from taxonomic publications and 415,858 material citations which are labeled as occurrences. 335 publications reuse this data. An estimate of 45,000 species are only represented in GBIF through material citations from publications, mainly covering new species that are extracted from the literature just after the publishing time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new GBIF Plazi data issue feedback loop</title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/a-new-gbif-plazi-data-issue-feedback-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/posts/a-new-gbif-plazi-data-issue-feedback-loop/</guid>
      <description>Plazi’s goal is to discover known biodiversity, and make it widely available using the tools available in the digital age. This means liberating data hidden in libraries, and more recently, and increasingly hidden in the PDF-prison, paywalls and unstructured text.
The grand challenge are an estimated 500 Million published pages of scholarly biodiversity related publications, and 17,000 annually new discovered and described species with a multiple of annotations on already known species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/activities/bouchout-declaration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.github.io/plazi.org/activities/bouchout-declaration/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of the Bouchout Declaration is to help make digital data about our biodiversity openly available. It offers members of the biodiversity community a way to demonstrate their commitment to open science.
As signatories, we encourage an overarching approach to Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management which is based on the following fundamental principles:
The free and open use of digital resources about biodiversity and associated access services; Licenses or waivers that grant or allow all users a free, irrevocable, world-wide, right to copy, use, distribute, transmit and display the work publicly as well as to build on the work and to make derivative works, subject to proper attribution consistent with community practices, while recognizing that providers may develop commercial products with more restrictive licensing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
