<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jan 29, 2022 Schweizer Hymenopterologen Tagung, Bern, CH</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</guid>
      <description> Program Presentation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 26-July 1, 2022. World Biodiversity Forum, Davos, Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:50:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will present its groundbreaking approach to the &amp;ldquo;liberation&amp;rdquo; of data from taxonomic treatments within scholarly publications at the World Biodiversity Forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 5-10, 2022. SPNHC, Edinburgh, UK</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will provide the lecture Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense except in the light of treatments at the conference of the Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections (SPNHC).
The goal of taxonomic literature is to describe taxonomic diversity as a result of charting the Earth&amp;rsquo;s biological diversity. As research adds to our knowledge, our understanding of taxa increases with additional published results. This is how it has happened since the standard publications by Linnaeus in 1753 and 1758 in the format of taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of text about a particular taxon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 24-25, 2022. Empowering Biodiversity, AfricaMuseum, Tervuren, Belgium</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will provide a keynote lecture Discovering known biodiversity at the Empowering Biodiversity Research conference.
Abstract: We will take you on a journey into the world of biodiversity data standards and tools and will inform you on the latest developments in the world of Biodiversity Informatics, both internationally and locally. What is the state of the art in initiatives like GBIF, LifeWatch and DiSSCo, etc and how can we let them work for us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nov 8-12, 2021. Biohackathon Europe, Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the Biohackthon Europe. Each November ELIXIR organizes BioHackathon Europe, which brings together bioinformaticians from around the world. The event takes place in different locations around Europe. The BioHackathon offers an intense week of hacking, with over 160 international participants who work on diverse and exciting projects. The week starts with a half-day symposium to introduce these projects, and is followed by five days of hacking with one sole aim: coding to address problems in bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nov 5th, 2021. SSSDay 2021, Musée de Zoologie Lausanne</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the SSSDay organised by the Swiss Systematics Society (SSS) to answer questions regarding the Swiss universities funded eBiodiv project and the EU Horizon 2020 funded BiCIKL project. The event is hosted by the Musée de Zoologie Lausanne.
Schedule</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oct 18-22, 2021. TDWG 2021 — Virtual Annual Conference</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</guid>
      <description>As we continue to connect people and biodiversity data globally by virtual means in these globally uncertain times, TDWG 2021 will be composed of symposia, workshops, contributed oral and poster presentations, demos, and discussions, as well as keynotes and social events. The Interest/Task Group working sessions will be held separately during the month following the virtual conference (November 2021). TDWG Symposia and TDWG Schedule
Oct 20, 8:30PM CET SYM18 Discovering known biodiversity: Digital accessible knowledge Session Type: Symposium (no unsolicited presentations considered)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oct 21, 2021. 17th Int&#39;l Conference on Digital Preservation, Beijing, China</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</guid>
      <description>October 21, 2021: Beijing, China Plazi together with Data Futures, MNHN France, SIB Switzerland and CERN Switzerland will present the lecture &amp;ldquo;Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data.
Abstract: We report progress towards automatically transforming existing analyses of scientific literature into annotations based on W3C&amp;rsquo;s Web Annotation Data Model (WADM). Case studies are presented from the life sciences, and social sciences and humanities, in which these developments have led to the creation of new unrestricted data services for the research community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 17th 2021: Launch eBiodiv</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</guid>
      <description>At the Naturhistorisches Museum in Bern.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
