<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:11:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomic Treatments as Open FAIR Digital Objects</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/fair-digital-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:11:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/fair-digital-objects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>400 Years of Botanical Collections – Implications for Present-Day Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/divisive-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/divisive-power/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Divisive Power of Citizenship, one of our Institute’s SNSF-funded project, concludes this year with its closing international conference on 22/23 September 2022 in Basel, Switzerland. This event will offer a broad platform for debate about citizenship in a global context, addressing scholars working in the fields of Global History, Asian Studies, International Law and Digital Humanities, at a time of terrifying topicality.
The central themes of discussion will be expat communities in Asia, and civil internment camps during the Second World War in Asia, which have been rarely studied until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>400 Years of Botanical Collections – Implications for Present-Day Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/400-years-of-botanical-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/400-years-of-botanical-collections/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Bauhin’s pioneering Flora of Basel „Catalogus Plantarum circa Basileam sponte nascentium“ exactly 400 years ago is a precursor to the artificially identified beginning of taxonomic publishing with Linnaeus Systema plantarum … 1753. Indeed, botanical publishing existed far before Linnaeus’, however his contribution has not only been the Latin Binomen, but the highly structured way he published the taxonomic treatments for each species, and to cite previous works. In the digital age, this kind of structuring of the information and the existing implicit citation links allows building the biodiversity knowledge graph, opening up the entire corpus of taxonomic treatments imprisoned in publications by providing it in a format that can be found and reused, cited and linked to data referenced in the publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do we not know – quantifying data gaps and biases in knowledge of bat co-roosting</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/what-we-dont-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 13:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/what-we-dont-know/</guid>
      <description>Improved understanding of co-habitation of roosts by multiple species of bats is essential for estimating the risks of zoonotic disease transmission. However, ecological data on roosting environments, species richness, bat-bat interactions, viral infections, and other species interactions are scattered throughout the literature, making them difficult to study on a global scale. The research scope for most roost studies has been narrow, focusing on roost type, bat abundance, and locality data while failing to investigate interspecific roosting interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Biodiversity Literature Repository — Open By Design</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</guid>
      <description>The Open Definition version 2.1 prescribes four conditions for openness of a work &amp;ndash;
it must be published under an open license or be in the public domain, it must be accessible easily and at no more than the cost of reproduction, preferably be downloadable via the internet it must be readily readable by a computer, and it must be available in an open format. It is clear that openness is not just a matter of sticking an open license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einen Einblick und Einstieg in die versteckte Vielfalt der 2021 publizierten Hymenopteren</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</guid>
      <description> Program Presentation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberation of data from taxonomic treatments</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:50:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will present Beyond the Print and PDF Prison: Data About Biodiveristy Want to be Free, showcasing Plazi’s groundbreaking approach to the liberation of data from taxonomic treatments within scholarly publications at the World Biodiversity Forum.
Abstract: Most of what scientists discovered about biodiversity and published, totaling a corpus of an estimated 500 million printed pages stacked up in our libraries and more recently, in digital format, is not known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will provide the lecture Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense except in the light of treatments at the conference of the Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections (SPNHC).
The goal of taxonomic literature is to describe taxonomic diversity as a result of charting the Earth&amp;rsquo;s biological diversity. As research adds to our knowledge, our understanding of taxa increases with additional published results. This is how it has happened since the standard publications by Linnaeus in 1753 and 1758 in the format of taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of text about a particular taxon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Known Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>We will take you on a journey into the world of biodiversity data standards and tools and will inform you on the latest developments in the world of Biodiversity Informatics, both internationally and locally. What is the state of the art in initiatives like GBIF, LifeWatch and DiSSCo, etc and how can we let them work for us? We have invited some very interesting international speakers and will inform you on the progress made by these projects in Belgium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biohackthon Europe</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the Biohackthon Europe. Each November ELIXIR organizes BioHackathon Europe, which brings together bioinformaticians from around the world. The event takes place in different locations around Europe. The BioHackathon offers an intense week of hacking, with over 160 international participants who work on diverse and exciting projects. The week starts with a half-day symposium to introduce these projects, and is followed by five days of hacking with one sole aim: coding to address problems in bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSSDay Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will participate in the SSSDay organised by the Swiss Systematics Society (SSS) to answer questions regarding the Swiss universities funded eBiodiv project and the EU Horizon 2020 funded BiCIKL project. The event is hosted by the Musée de Zoologie Lausanne.
Schedule</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the world of biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</guid>
      <description>As we continue to connect people and biodiversity data globally by virtual means in these globally uncertain times, TDWG 2021 will be composed of symposia, workshops, contributed oral and poster presentations, demos, and discussions, as well as keynotes and social events. The Interest/Task Group working sessions will be held separately during the month following the virtual conference (November 2021). TDWG Symposia and TDWG Schedule
Oct 20, 8:30PM CET SYM18 Discovering known biodiversity: Digital accessible knowledge Session Type: Symposium (no unsolicited presentations considered)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</guid>
      <description>We report progress towards automatically transforming existing analyses of scientific literature into annotations based on W3C&amp;rsquo;s Web Annotation Data Model (WADM). Case studies are presented from the life sciences, and social sciences and humanities, in which these developments have led to the creation of new unrestricted data services for the research community. We discuss the cross- domain potential of annotation infrastructure for releasing scientific facts reported in research literature from copyright restrictions, and demonstrate the utility of common standards-based preservation and discovery methods in disparate activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBiodiv Launch</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</guid>
      <description>At the Naturhistorisches Museum in Bern.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
