<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:39:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disentis Roadmap: A decadal roadmap for liberating global biodiversity knowledge from literature (introduction)</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/disentis-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/disentis-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;time: 11 am CET&#xA;Presenter: Donat Agosti (Plazi), Laurence Bénichou (MNHN)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published biodiversity research—ranging from species descriptions and traits to distributions, interactions, and drivers of change—remains largely locked in inaccessible literature and electronic resources. This constitutes a major barrier to scientific progress and evidence-based policy. Making biodiversity knowledge openly available through connected, curated, and digitally accessible knowledge bases is both a pressing challenge and a critical opportunity for the global research and policy communities.The Disentis Roadmap emerged from a symposium held in Disentis, Switzerland, in August 2024, which assessed the impact of the 2014 Bouchout Declaration on Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management and identified strategic priorities for the coming decade. As of May 25, 2025, the Roadmap has been signed by 97 individuals and institutions. Discussions were grounded in existing workflows for data liberation, involving a collaborative effort among key stakeholders: publishers (CETAF, Muséum national d’Histoire naturelle Paris, Pensoft), Plazi, the Biodiversity Literature Repository at Zenodo, the Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF), ChecklistBank, and the Biodiversity PubMedCentral hosted by the Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics Library Services (SiBILS). These efforts include the automated conversion and reuse of 198 biodiversity journals, resulting in substantial outputs from 95,000 publications such as Open Findable, Accessible, Interactionable, and Reusable (FAIR) 760,000 taxonomic treatments, 630,000 figures, and 1,7 million material citations. Additional input has been the extensive digitization of the Biodiversity Heritage Library (BHL) and a large number of individual scientists and research groups. Use cases have informed the process, including literature reuse for Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) reporting, mining of biotic interactions at Biodiversity PMC, the Global Mountain Biodiversity Assessment, and the expansion of ChecklistBank at GBIF.This presentation introduces the Disentis Roadmap and concludes with a blueprint outlining how its ambitious goals can be achieved through technical innovation and coordinated organizational action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Biodiversity Discovery Through Innovative Technologies</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/accelerating-biodiversity-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/accelerating-biodiversity-discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;time: 8:45am (Bogotá)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Presenter: Rudolf Meier (MfN), Authors Donat Agosti (Plazi), Amrita Srivathson (MfN)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of Earth’s biodiversity remains unknown: only about 20% of species are formally described, while the remaining 80% remain undescribed. Over the past 250 years, biodiversity research has generated an enormous “analog backlog” of publications and collections, but creating more analog data in an era of machine learning and digital infrastructures is counterproductive. This talk presents a vision for digitally native species discovery and description that integrates hyperdiverse insect research with innovative technologies including high-throughput DNA barcoding on nanopore sequencers, robotic specimen handling and imaging, and artificial intelligence for data extraction and species description. Preliminary species hypotheses generated with cost-effective megabarcoding are validated with targeted morphological research, then translated into species descriptions using AI-assisted tools. In the process, each specimen that is processed becomes the anchor for structured digital records on Zenodo containing sequences, images, metadata, and traits. This ensures that data are FAIR-compliant—interlinked, transparent, reproducible, and immediately reusable for conservation and ecological monitoring. By prioritizing scalability and interoperability, the approach accelerates biodiversity discovery while producing species descriptions that are both human- and machine-readable. In doing so, the vast “dark taxa” of insects can become visible and tractable, enabling biodiversity research, monitoring, and conservation in a truly digital age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Taxonomic Splits Matter for Bat Biodiversity and Viral Risk Analyses</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/why-taxonomic-splits-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:49:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/why-taxonomic-splits-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;time: 10:45am (Bogotá)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Presenter: Nathan Upham (ASU)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Aja Sherman (Bat Eco-Interaction Project), Nancy Simmons (AMNH), Kendra Phelps (UoM), Anna Willoughby (UoG), Quentin Groom (Meise Botanic Garden), Donat Agosti (Plazi), DeeAnn Reeder (BU), Jorrit Poelen (RIIS), Connor Burgin (UoNM)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy is generally viewed as external to ecology, a fixed framework rather than a variable that needs tuning to understand its impact on inferences. However, since taxonomy is a human-imposed perspective rather than something innate, biodiversity scientists have the responsibility to quantify its impact on derived knowledge. Here we study how the 35% increase in recognized bat species (Chiroptera) since 1993 has impacted our knowledge of bat-virus interactions and, in turn, inferences of viral spillover risk to humans. We focus on change in the geographic concepts of bat species globally due to taxonomic splits between two periods: (i) 2008-2020 using IUCN range maps (based on Mammal Species of the World, 3rd edition) relative to Mammal Diversity Database (MDD) v1.2 range maps; and (ii) 2020-2023 comparing MDD v1.2 to newly produced v1.11 maps. We then intersect these conceptual changes with known bat-virus interactions from databases to assess their impact upon risks of cross-species viral transmission. We find that taxonomic splits affected 248 bat species across both periods (185 and 63 species, respectively), which has impacted 16.9% of currently recognized bat species globally. Those taxonomic splits have rendered ambiguous 3,249 bat-virus interactions — 21.9% of all digitally known observations — since these data are indexed by host species name rather than observation location, which leads to ambiguity when species are split. We discuss high-throughput solutions for accurately translating the taxonomy of these data, and the impact of inaction upon estimates of viral spillover risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collaborative Workflow to Expand Taxonomic Coverage in the Catalogue of Life eXtended Release through Plazi-Mediated Data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/a-collaborative-workflow-to-expand-taxonomic-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/a-collaborative-workflow-to-expand-taxonomic-coverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;time: 4:55 pm (Bogotá)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Presenter: Camila Plata (COL)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Donat Agosti (Plazi), Markus Döring (COL), Diana Hernández-Robles (COL), Guido Sautter (Plazi), Felipe Lorenz Simões (Plazi), Olaf Bánki (COL)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Catalogue of Life (COL) compiles species names across all taxonomic groups in collaboration with taxonomic communities. Keeping up to date with newly described taxa remains a challenge for both COL and its network. To address this and help close long-standing taxonomic gaps, an enhanced assembly process has been developed over the past two years. As a result, the recently launched Catalogue of Life eXtended Release integrates data from over 27,000 sources. Here, we detail Plazi’s contribution and the collaboration between the two initiatives.Approximately 26,000 papers processed by Plazi, originating from journals such as the EJT, Zootaxa, and PhytoKeys among other 190, are integrated. This has been critical for addressing gaps, particularly in the highly diverse insect groups, which is not fully covered by dedicated taxonomic communities. Plazi mediated data contributes around 90,000 unique names from which over 60% represent insect names, and 5% of names of species described in the last 5 years.Plazi and COL have worked together for the past two years to create a workflow to maximize gap coverage. This collaboration includes the use of the Catalogue of Life Data Package (ColDP) standard, data quality checks, adding treatment citations, improved classification accuracy, enhanced completeness, reduced inaccuracies in treated data and ChecklistBank enhancements. Currently, checklists derived from the journals cited above are integrated into Catalogue of Life in under two weeks, significantly improving data availability for COL’s usage.As vetted catalogues continue to contribute species, Plazi’s relative share decreases, and priority shifts to those authoritative sources. We are testing a feedback loop in which COL’s constituent checklists evaluate Plazi’s mediated data. This helps taxonomists integrate newly described species into their checklist and uncover recurring issues, which are promptly addressed to ensure higher-quality releases and better workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberation of Data training session: How to liberate data from publications and how to reuse it</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/how-to-liberate-data-from-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:43:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/how-to-liberate-data-from-publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Presenters: Donat Agosti (Plazi), Laurence Bénichou (MNHN), Chris le Coquet (MNHN), Markus Döring (GBIF/COL), Julia Giora (Plazi), Emilie Pasche (SIBiLS/HESGE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course offers a deep dive into the processes of annotating, structuring, and sharing biodiversity data extracted from scientific literature. The session will begin with an online theoretical introduction, providing an overview of the current state of biodiversity literature, the move towards the liberation of taxonomic data and the new opportunities this offers. This will be followed by two days of hands-on, in-person training focused on practical workflows for structuring, annotating, and circulating biodiversity data from scientific publications. Participants will explore how to annotate biodiversity datasets, ensuring they are properly formatted for reuse, and how to facilitate the sharing and circulation of these datasets within the scientific community. Trainees will also learn how to access and reuse data for their own research needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberating and re-use of data imprisoned in scientific literature</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/liberating-and-reuse-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/liberating-and-reuse-of-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;time: 2 pm Bogotá&#xA;Presenter: Donat Agosti (Plazi), Laurence Bénichou (MNHN)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biodiversity research results are contained in the ever-growing corpus of scientific publications, traditionally stored in, or provided through, academic libraries. Access to this literature can be difficult in terms of both findability and accessibility. In the digital age, this barrier can and should be lifted by opening publications to machine access, ensuring the data they contain adheres to the FAIR principles. This workshop provides a hands-on demonstration of the existing workflows to liberate data from legacy publications, as well as to publish in a semantically-enhanced way and to reuse the data. It will also highlight the benefits and opportunities provided by accessible, semantically-enhanced literature in the biodiversity domain.&#xA;The workshop will have three parts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data infrastructures Panel</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/data-infrastructures-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/10/data-infrastructures-panel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;time: tba (CET)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Research data infrastructures handle and structure the rising amount of scientific data. They are connected beyond borders and scientific domains. Today, they act as powerful enablers for AI innovations in science and beyond. Resilience has become a major requirement in securing Europe’s digital sovereignty. In order to secure resilience and sustainability of research data infrastructures, this table highlights their legal, technical and social conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening FAIR Biodiversity Data Engagement in South America</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/04/strengthening-biodiversity-data-engagement-in-s-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:20:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/04/strengthening-biodiversity-data-engagement-in-s-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Julia Giora, Juliana M. Wingert&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From March 25 to 28, the Plazi team was at the Universidad Nacional de Colombia, in Bogotá, delivering two courses for the scientific community. We brought together 56 participants from 17 academic and research institutions, including researchers, curators, and undergraduate and graduate students.&#xA;The courses offered hands-on training on the use of infrastructures for extracting and mining data in digital repositories, and fostered rich exchanges and discussions around the reuse of biodiversity data based on FAIR data principles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biodiversity Knowledge in the Digital Era: Free Access and Reuse of Scientific Data (Course)</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/12/biodiversity-knowledge-in-digital-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/12/biodiversity-knowledge-in-digital-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-conocimiento-de-la-biodiversidad-en-la-era-digital-libre-acceso-y-reutilización-de-datos-científicos&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;El conocimiento de la biodiversidad en la era digital: libre acceso y reutilización de datos científicos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Julia Giora, Juliana M. Wingert&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the great challenges of science is to facilitate the construction and availability of knowledge. In the digital age, knowledge about biodiversity is found mainly in scientific publications, which can be uploaded to various repositories or databases. To provide information to these repositories, data must be transformed into machine-readable formats. Additionally, people need to be trained and equipped to access and use this data appropriately. Colombia is a country with great biodiversity and important research institutions that constantly produce scientific knowledge such as Universidad Nacional de Colombia (UNC), Universidad del Rosario, Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Universidad La Salle, Universidad de Los Andes, Universidad Jorge Tadeo, and Instituto Humboldt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three presentations at the Brazilian Meeting of Ichthyology</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/12/encontro-brasileiro-de-ictiologia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/12/encontro-brasileiro-de-ictiologia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;neotropical-ichthyology-e-zootaxa-análise-de-dados-liberados-e-disponibilizados-em-repositórios-online&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neotropical Ichthyology e Zootaxa: Análise de Dados Liberados e Disponibilizados em Repositórios Online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Neotropical Ichthyology and Zootaxa: Analysis of Data Released and Made Available in Online Repositories — Poster)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;espécies-ameaçadas-de-peixes-do-bioma-pampa-livre-acesso-às-descrições-originais-em-repositórios-de-dados-online&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Espécies Ameaçadas de Peixes do Bioma Pampa: Livre Acesso às Descrições Originais em Repositórios de Dados Online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Endangered Fish Species of the Pampa Biome: Open Access to Original Descriptions in Online Data Repositories — Oral Communication)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-taxonomia-integrada-aos-meios-digitais-como-facilitar-o-acesso-e-a-reutilização-de-dados-taxonômicos-pela-comunidade-científica&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Taxonomia Integrada aos Meios Digitais: como facilitar o acesso e a reutilização de dados taxonômicos pela comunidade científica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Integrating Taxonomy to Digital Media: how to facilitate access and reuse of taxonomic data by the scientific community — Course)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiodiversityPMC: The One Health Library (Poster)</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/biodiversitypmc-the-one-health-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/biodiversitypmc-the-one-health-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; all day&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Presenters:&lt;/strong&gt; Emilie Pasche, Julien Gobeill, Donat Agosti, Lyubomir Penev, Quentin Groom, Teodor Georgiev, Esteban Gaillac, Alexandre Flament, Déborah Caucheteur, Pierre-André Michel, Marie Kolsch, Anaïs Mottaz, Patrick Ruch&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One Health is a comprehensive and unified approach that recognises the close connection between the health of people, animals and whole ecosystems. While life and health sciences are widely represented in digital libraries such as PubMed Central, articles focussing on biodiversity, ecology or environmental sciences are relatively marginal. Addressing this critical gap, we introduce a novel Research Infrastructure named “BiodiversityPMC”, leveraging the Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics Literature Services (SIBiLS), which are already mirroring MEDLINE (over 36 million abstracts), PubMed Central contents (over 6 million full-text articles) and supplementary data files associated to scientific publications (over 6 million supplementary files including OCRized images and tables). The coverage of SIBiLS is expanded to encompass a broader range of biodiversity-related content, including environmental sciences and ecology. This involves indexing half a million taxonomic treatments and articles harvested from Plazi, and a growing set of full-text articles from journals in the field (e.g., Pensoft, European Journal of Taxonomy), which are not included into the original PubMed Central. To ensure comprehensive and standardized access, the contents are normalized using a large collection of life sciences terminologies and ontologies. Each instance of a term (or its synonym) is assigned a unique accession number, to support a semantically richer search experience. Of particular interest for the biodiversity communities, SIBiLS contents are normalized using ENVO (Environmental Ontology), ROBI (Relation Ontology Biotic Interactions), an enriched subset of RO (Relation Ontology), and LOTUS, a natural products database. Further, taxonomic names are normalized using both the NCBI Taxonomy and the Open Tree of Life, which include names from the Catalogue of Life. The resulting data graph contains more than 10 billion normalized descriptors. Access to BiodiversityPMC is facilitated through a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sibils.text-analytics.ch/search/&#34;&gt;new graphic user interface&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sibils.text-analytics.ch/api/&#34;&gt;an OpenAPI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sibils.text-analytics.ch/sparql/&#34;&gt;a SPARQL endpoint&lt;/a&gt;. BiodiversityPMC not only offers traditional search methods (access via keyword search), but also introduces innovative approaches for navigating the complex landscape of health and environmental sciences. An original question-answering interface can help provide new perspectives over the literature. BidoversityPMC stands out as a valuable resource proficient in addressing a wide spectrum of questions related to biodiversity in the broad sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do we get there? a 7* scheme of getting open FAIR publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/a-7-scheme-for-getting-fair-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/a-7-scheme-for-getting-fair-publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 2:30PM CEST&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Presenters:&lt;/strong&gt; Donat Agosti&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Research results are published as scientific articles. They represent an intricate network of citations and facts, representing the existing knowledge, as billions of statements. In biodiversity, this includes a corpus of an estimated 500 million pages. A small but growing part is published in a semantically enhanced open access format, but the overwhelming part is behind multiple barriers, from being print only to closed access portable document formats (PDFs). To make use of the emerging AI tools, this corpus needs to be made available in a machine actionable way. At least part of it has to be curated to serve as training material for AI and machine learning. The steps towards fully machine actionable data will be described in this presentation. Starting with print (), print with metadata (), to scan-based PDF with metadata (), text-based PDF with metadata (), ASCI – standard structured XML with metadata (), ASCI – XML with semantic enhancements and metadata () and ending with ASCI – XML with semantic enhancements, attributes and metadata (****). To serve the wider community, the publications have to be open access, infrastructures need to be expanded such as the Biodiversity Literature Repository to allow FAIRizing of data, including specific blocks of text such as taxonomic treatments, recommendations or illustrations, and vocabularies have to be developed and maintained to enable semantic enhancement in cases where they do not exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TreatmentBank: an automated workflow to convert biodiversity PDFs as input into Biodiversity PMC</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/treatmentbank-an-automated-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/treatmentbank-an-automated-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Donat Agosti&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several ELIXIR communities are designing text analytic solutions to perform various data curation tasks. The development of pre-trained and large language models is also helping non expert communities developing successful applications (e.g., triage, named-entity recognition, chatbots, search engines). The span of tasks can be relatively heterogeneous, ranging from well-established and common natural language processing tasks (e.g., named entity recognition, automatic text categorization) up to more complex curation support tasks (e.g., triage or question-answering, bi-directional linking between curated databases and publications). There is also a growing focus on converting and annotating publications, to expand the pool of FAIR data available for downstream tasks, as illustrated by the efforts of the Elixir Data Platform and several node and ELIXIR core data resources (e.g., BioStudies, EuropePMC).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Plazi to TaxonWorks</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/from-plazi-to-taxonworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2024/04/from-plazi-to-taxonworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Julia Giora, Donat Agosti&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We plan to share our experiment to use Plazi treament files to get new taxon names into TaxonWorks. Plazi will give us their perspective on what we did and ideas for future collaboration and what they plan to work on in the coming years. New to Plazi? &lt;a href=&#34;https://treatment.plazi.org/GgServer/summary/FFA0AE675753FFF9FFC5FFF1FFA9530C&#34;&gt;See this treatment&lt;/a&gt; for an example of how Plazi gets data out of publications into a format we can take advantage of for uploading to our database(s) via files or the Plazi API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harmonizing taxonomic resources is necessary for novel insights into bat roosting dataset</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/harmonizing-taxonomic-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 09:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/harmonizing-taxonomic-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Aja Sherman&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engaging the community in FAIR taxonomic data liberation: an overview of training resources at Plazi</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/engaging-the-community-in-fair-data-liberation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/engaging-the-community-in-fair-data-liberation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Julia Giora&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since 2008, swiss-based not-for-profit organization Plazi has been supporting and promoting the development of persistent and openly accessible digital taxonomic literature. To achieve this goal, Plazi makes use of in-house softwares for data mining and extraction from taxonomic publications, along with other partner institution tools and platforms, to liberate data on animals, plants, fungi, and more. In its mission to make taxonomic data FAIRly available to the community, Plazi has developed sets of training material and courses, which enables taxonomists, collection curators, students, technicians and others to participate in the process of taxonomic data liberation. The participation of several different members of the community is key as data requires deep curation, often very specific to a particular field. Most recently, Plazi led a virtual 2-day workshop as part of the MOBILISE ACTION in Europe, along with two 4-day in-person workshops in Brazil and South Africa. Participants are issued certificates which entitle them to extract data on their own, thus multiplying the output of FAIR data using Plazi’s workflow. Here, we present a summary of the current status of said training tools/material, the next steps in development, and how they can help more and more taxonomists, or enthusiasts, liberate data. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sEbOYL44gCSlENWCofvvx7f2hrSWsLHO/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matching material citations to occurrences: extending the biodiversity knowledge graph</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/matching-material-citations-to-occurrences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/matching-material-citations-to-occurrences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; Donat Agosti&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scholarly publications are the channel to communicate research findings based on the analysis of specimens and their traits. In an open science world, the link to the specimens together with the description of the methods involved should enable us to reproduce the results. Increasingly, taxonomic publications provide a section with structured or even semantically enhanced tables, including persistent digital identifiers of the specimens. These publications can be processed, reformatted as datasets of material citations that can be reused, for example by the Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF). In many cases these are the only representations of species in GBIF, but in other cases they complement specimens that have been submitted as preserved specimens. In this case, the presence of a material citation provides in return access to the knowledge about the specimen, or in other words, extends the biodiversity knowledge graph from a specimen to what is stated in the respective hosting taxonomic treatment, often far beyond by all the links that are embedded in it. Matching can be done automatically but in many cases depends on human curation. For this case a matching service developed with the Swiss eBioDiv and the European funded BiCIKL projects will be explained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining and Biodiversity Research Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/text-mining-and-biodiv-ri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/text-mining-and-biodiv-ri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The scientific knowledge on biodiversity is imprisoned in a daily growing corpus of hundred millions of pages of scientific publications. This knowledge is needed to better understand the dynamics and dimensions of the global biodiversity crisis, to understand the impact of climate change on the distribution of species or to understand the viral spillover from animals to humans. This knowledge is very difficult to access because it is unstructured, in printed formats, including portable data format (PDF), which are difficult to machine operate, or closed access. The power of access to millions of machine actionable articles in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc&#34;&gt;PMC&lt;/a&gt;, including millions of supplementary data files, or tens of millions of abstracts in PubMed and tools to annotate and mine and discover new facts is obvious. These tools could be used for TDM and annotations of biodiversity literature - but the PMC/PubMed equivalent has not been available for publications in the biodiversity domain, hence the need for a BiodiversityPMC!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new value of scientific publications in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/new-value-of-scientific-pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/new-value-of-scientific-pubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific publications are the means by which scientific knowledge is communicated. In botany as well as all biological sciences, each new species discovered is based on at least one publication including a protologue conformant to the International Code of Nomenclature for algae, fungi, and plants. A protologue is based on a standard vocabulary, including a material citation of the type specimen and its hosting institution, generally a figure with the diagnostic characters and a discussion of related species. Increasingly, DNA sequences are cited. The protologues are referenced in subsequent taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of a publications about one particular taxon, and implicit in taxonomic names. Together, these treatments cover the history of the names of the taxon (synonymy), are a very rich source for traits, distribution, and since they are based on physical specimens, an authoritative identification of these specimens. It is assumed that the corpus of biodiversity literature includes a daily growing corpus of 500 million pages, housed in the many libraries of natural history institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing: Extending the biodiversity knowledge graph</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/extending-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/extending-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A goal of natural history institutions is contributing to the understanding of biodiversity and disseminating this knowledge by becoming scientific publishers. Through this, they joined the growing field of scholarly publishing established in 1665 by the Journal des sçavans to publish work from the sciences. One of the characteristics of scientific publishing is to cite previous works and thus linking existing knowledge with new discoveries. To provide access to the growing corpus of publications, libraries began to index individual works. With the advent of the digital age, full text search and text and data mining provide access to the content using machines analysing large corpora of works. The development of the semantic web enabled creating a knowledge graph. A typical example is the growth of knowledge related to a species, including synonyms, cited specimens, figures or DNA sequences. During this symposium the state and recent developments of biodiversity publishing, linking and providing increased access to data by &lt;a href=&#34;https://pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Pensoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cetaf.org/&#34;&gt;CETAF&lt;/a&gt;-publishing group, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mnhn.fr/en&#34;&gt;MNHN Paris&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;, including over 50 journals in a semantic enhanced format, and supported by a series of projects (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ebiodiv.org/&#34;&gt;eBioDiv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia fund&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ouvrirlascience.fr/metostem-2/&#34;&gt;MétoSTeM&lt;/a&gt;) will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The BiCIKL toolbox to link biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/toolbox-to-link-biodiv-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/toolbox-to-link-biodiv-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will demonstrate tools and infrastructure from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; project to find and establish links between entities. These include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure to create and manage machine actionable persistent identifiers (PIDs) for digital specimens. This allows the creation and annotation of digital specimens as new actionable objects on the internet, which provide a surrogate for physical specimens.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openbiodiv.net/&#34;&gt;OpenBiodiv&lt;/a&gt; is a linked open data (LOD) knowledge graph extracted from the biodiversity literature. OpenBiodiv can discover hidden links, e.g., between authors, taxa, sequences, material citations, publications and others using general search, SPARQL (query language), user applications and API.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/&#34;&gt;TreatmentBank&lt;/a&gt; liberates data from within publications, and converts, enhances, links, stores, and disseminates it as findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable (FAIR) data. The API has been enhanced allowing better data linkages through identifiers, matching services, and avenues for annotation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/resources/sibils&#34;&gt;SIBiLS&lt;/a&gt; custom search services provide access to biomedical literature, including PubMed Central (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/&#34;&gt;PMC&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nlm.nih.gov/medline/index.html&#34;&gt;MEDLINE&lt;/a&gt;. It also provides access to half a million taxonomic treatments curated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt;. BICIKL has helped aggregate more publications, enabling the creation of an all-inclusive “One Health” library, the BiodiversityPMC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.checklistbank.org/&#34;&gt;ChecklistBank&lt;/a&gt; is an open data repository with a focus on taxonomy and nomenclature. It has tools for name matching, dataset comparison, and for linking taxonomic names from literature.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eBioDiv: linking specimens with literature, or to what is known about a specimen</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/linking-specimens-with-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 16:18:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/linking-specimens-with-literature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebiodiv.org/&#34;&gt;eBioDiv&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissuniversities.ch/en/topics/digitalisation/open-science/programme&#34;&gt;Swissuniversities&lt;/a&gt; funded project by a consortium of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hes-so.ch/en/homepage&#34;&gt;HES-SO&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34;&gt;SIB&lt;/a&gt; (Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics), Plazi, and the Natural History Museum of Bern (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nmbe.ch/de&#34;&gt;NMBE&lt;/a&gt;) with the goal to build a knowledge infrastructure to bring data in taxonomic literature together with physical specimens digitalized through projects funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://swisscollnet.scnat.ch/de&#34;&gt;SwissCollNet&lt;/a&gt;. The linking is based on that fact that specimen, the basis of taxonomic works, are cited formally in the publications as material citations. They can be made &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.go-fair.org/fair-principles/&#34;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt; (Findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable). The eBioDiv &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/&#34;&gt;matching service&lt;/a&gt; allows to discover the cited specimen, especially if the natural history institution uploaded them to the Global Biodiversity Information Facility &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt;. The link furthermore allows to follow-up from a specimen to what is known about it in the published literature. The complementing Horizon Europe funded project Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; allows further linking of a specimen to taxonomic names or gene sequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training course</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/01/training-biodiv-digital-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 16:18:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/01/training-biodiv-digital-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This hands-on and interactive training will give students and professionals of natural history institutions an opportunity to get informed about and practice the liberation and reuse of taxonomic data using digital platforms and repositories. Applicants need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/W14eqekgN1NYuB29A&#34;&gt;register online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiSSCo Futures 2023.</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/01/dissco-futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 12:57:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/01/dissco-futures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donat Agosti will participate in this event as part of the closing of the COST Mobilise project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDWG 2022</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/10/tdwg2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 12:57:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/10/tdwg2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;Enabling Published Taxonomic Data to Address the Biodiversity Crisis&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The use-case of Biodiversity Literature Repository and TreatmentBank&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date and Time:&lt;/b&gt; Oct 17, 2022, 2:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt; To understand the loss of species, a benchmark is needed, e.g. the status of biodiversity in 1992 when the Convention on Biological Diversity recognized biodiversity crisis to compare to its status in the successive year. Though we are far from knowning how many species there are on planet Earth, we keep track of their descriptions and number through the information kept in our libraries. Each species discovered is represented therein by at least one taxononic treatment. The library includes an estimated 500 million pages and is updated daily with an estimated 17–18,000 new species annually and over 100,000 treatments augmenting the knowledge of existing species. &lt;a href=&#34;https://biss.pensoft.net/article/91167/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Day on Open/FAIR Natural History Data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/09/glamhack-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 17:54:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/09/glamhack-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The Workshop Day on Open/FAIR Natural History Data is intended for curators, managers, and users of natural history collections in Switzerland. It serves as a forum to draw up an overview of the current situation regarding data management and digitization in Swiss institutions and sets the collections and their data in the wider context of the emerging ecosystem of open/FAIR natural history data with its various infrastructures, stakeholders, initiatives, usage scenarios, value-added services, and governance structures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomic Treatments as Open FAIR Digital Objects</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/fair-digital-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:11:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/fair-digital-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy is the science of charting and describing the worlds biodiversity. Organisms are grouped into taxa which are given a given rank building the taxonomic hierarchy. The taxa are described in taxonomic treatments, well defined sections of scientific publications (Catapano 2019). They include a nomenclatural section and one or more sections including descriptions, material citations referring to studied specimens, or notes ecology and behavior. In case the treatment does not describe a new discovered taxon, previous treatments are cited in the form of treatment citations. This citation can refer to a previous treatment and add additional data, or it can be a statement synonymizing the taxon with another taxon. This allows building a citation network, and ultimately is a constituent part of the catalogue of life. Thus treatments play an important role to understand the diversity of life on Earth by providing the scientific argument why group of organism is a new species, or a synonym, and the data provided will increasingly be important to analyze and compare whole genomes of individual genomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Copyright-Free Taxonomic Treatments as New Resources for Biodiversity Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/divisive-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/divisive-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Divisive Power of Citizenship, one of our Institute’s SNSF-funded project, concludes this year with its closing international conference on 22/23 September 2022 in Basel, Switzerland. This event will offer a broad platform for debate about citizenship in a global context, addressing scholars working in the fields of Global History, Asian Studies, International Law and Digital Humanities, at a time of terrifying topicality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The central themes of discussion will be expat communities in Asia, and civil internment camps during the Second World War in Asia, which have been rarely studied until now. An additional methodological component will investigate the potential of digital methods in this field, which will analyse the impact of access to precise data at scale relating to networks of foreign residents—addressing interferences with citizenship, statelessness and denaturalisation. The conference will also form the launch for new data resources which have been created during the course of the project, covering Foreign Residents in East Asia between 1863 and 1941.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>400 Years of Botanical Collections – Implications for Present-Day Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/400-years-of-botanical-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/400-years-of-botanical-collections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bauhin’s pioneering Flora of Basel „Catalogus Plantarum circa Basileam sponte nascentium“ exactly 400 years ago is a precursor to the artificially identified beginning of taxonomic publishing with Linnaeus Systema plantarum … 1753. Indeed, botanical publishing existed far before Linnaeus’, however his contribution has not only been the Latin Binomen, but the highly structured way he published the taxonomic treatments for each species, and to cite previous works. In the digital age, this kind of structuring of the information and the existing implicit citation links allows building the biodiversity knowledge graph, opening up the entire corpus of taxonomic treatments imprisoned in publications by providing it in a format that can be found and reused, cited and linked to data referenced in the publications. This provides access to all the published data about a specimen in a natural history collection, to trace back the history of a taxonomic name or the traits used to describe and deliminit the species. The Swiss based Biodiversity Literature Repository and TreatmentBank provide access to over 750,000 taxonomic treatments, over 1M material citations and are the largest data set provider to the Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF). This highly automated workflow has and continues to liberate data from over 70,000 publications, which are further converted to RDF and structured into Linked Open Data via the OpenBiodiv Biodiversity Knowledge Graph. At the same time new ways to structure publications so that their resident data can immediately be reused upon publication are being developed in collaboration with Pensoft publishers, the Muséum d’histoire naturelle, Paris and the CETAF publishing group. The Swiss NGO Plazi, Zenodo at CERN and SIBiLS at the Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics are involved in the EU Horizon 2020 project BiCIKL and the Swissuniversities funded project eBioDiv to develop ways to link data in publications to specimens, taxonomic names and genes and vice versa. This lecture will explain the concept and state of the art in taxonomic publishing, access and reuse of its data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do we not know – quantifying data gaps and biases in knowledge of bat co-roosting</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/what-we-dont-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 13:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/what-we-dont-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Improved understanding of co-habitation of roosts by multiple species of bats is essential for estimating the risks of zoonotic disease transmission. However, ecological data on roosting environments, species richness, bat-bat interactions, viral infections, and other species interactions are scattered throughout the literature, making them difficult to study on a global scale. The research scope for most roost studies has been narrow, focusing on roost type, bat abundance, and locality data while failing to investigate interspecific roosting interactions. To meet this need, we have collaboratively built an open-access dataset of ecological interactions (including co-roosting, trophic, anthropogenic, and parasitic) extracted from the literature to improve our understanding of roost dynamics on a global scale, and to elucidate the role of shared roosts in disease transmission. As of April 2022, &amp;gt; 11,500 interaction records involving &amp;gt; 360 bat species from &amp;gt; 137 countries encompassing a variety of habitats have been extracted from &amp;gt; 175 publications spanning from 1860-2020, all accessible via the Coronavirus-Host community at Zenodo. With this benchmark dataset of open-access digitized interaction data, tools, and workflows, we provide evidence of co-roosting events that we aligned with multiple ontologies (interaction terms, taxonomies, administrative regions) and phylogenies suitable for high-throughput analysis We followed open access and FAIR (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable) data principles for extracting data and choosing methodologies. We identify biases in the coverage of bat interaction records, suggest new tools for biodiversity informatics, and explore obstacles and opportunities in the mining of eco-interactions previously lost in the annals of scientific literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biodiversity Literature Repository — Open By Design</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Open Definition version 2.1 prescribes four conditions for openness of a work &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be published under an open license or be in the public domain,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be accessible easily and at no more than the cost of reproduction, preferably be downloadable via the internet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be readily readable by a computer, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be available in an open format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is clear that openness is not just a matter of sticking an open license. Openness has to be a fundamental goal and part of the design. This becomes all the more important for complicated endeavors such as scientific data that need to exist in a stable form far into the future (&amp;ldquo;forever&amp;rdquo;). At Plazi we have been extracting data from biodiversity literature and making it FAIR and open for more than a decade. To do this, we have built (or helped build) the tools, the procedures, the repositories, the standards, and the partnerships to extract, clean, archive and disseminate data for perpetuity. &lt;a href=&#34;https://punkish.org/Biodiversity-Literature-Repository/&#34;&gt;In this presentation&lt;/a&gt; we will share our experience building a lasting research infrastructure that is open by design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Einen Einblick und Einstieg in die versteckte Vielfalt der 2021 publizierten Hymenopteren</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1QSdEGwgAIH2_ntZ4sHtMRE26-PTeLF9r/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5916757&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberation of data from taxonomic treatments</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:50:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donat Agosti will present &lt;a href=&#34;https://wbf2022.abstractserver.com/program/#/details/presentations/173&#34;&gt;Beyond the Print and PDF Prison: Data About Biodiveristy Want to be Free&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing Plazi’s groundbreaking approach to the liberation of data from taxonomic treatments within scholarly publications at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbiodiversityforum.org/en/welcome-to-wbf-2022&#34;&gt;World Biodiversity Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Most of what scientists discovered about biodiversity and published, totaling a corpus of an estimated 500 million printed pages stacked up in our libraries  and more recently, in digital format, is not known. It is an amount of information that can not be processed by humans, but even machines can’t cope with it because the publications are either not scanned, or are behind paywalls, or in formats that machines can’t read at scale. It is a tragedy that in this digital age we can’t make use of this data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donat Agosti will provide the lecture &lt;em&gt;Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense except in the light of treatments&lt;/em&gt; at the conference of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://spnhc2022.com/about/&#34;&gt;Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections (SPNHC)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of taxonomic literature is to describe taxonomic diversity as a result of charting the Earth&amp;rsquo;s biological diversity. As research adds to our knowledge, our understanding of taxa increases with additional published results. This is how it has happened since the standard publications by Linnaeus in 1753 and 1758 in the format of taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of text about a particular taxon. Later, material citations were added, providing an explicit link to the material that led to the published research result. Each treatment has a nomenclatural section including the referenced taxonomic name representing the usage of a specific citable name. Thus, the taxonomic name Apis mellifera L, 1758 refers to the taxonomic treatment published by Linnaeus 1758 on page 576. Later usage of the name cites this treatment thereby adding new research to the scientific corpus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Known Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will take you on a journey into the world of biodiversity data standards and tools and will inform you on the latest developments in the world of Biodiversity Informatics, both internationally and locally. What is the state of the art in initiatives like GBIF, LifeWatch and DiSSCo, etc and how can we let them work for us? We have invited some very interesting international speakers and will inform you on the progress made by these projects in Belgium. During this conference we will build a bridge between Biodiversity informatics and its older relative “Bioinformatics” and investigate what a crossover of these two worlds can bring to Biodiversity Research. Genomic information meets digital taxonomy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biohackthon Europe</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/biohackathon-europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plazi will participate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://biohackathon-europe.org/index.html&#34;&gt;Biohackthon Europe&lt;/a&gt;. Each November ELIXIR organizes BioHackathon Europe, which brings together bioinformaticians from around the world. The event takes place in different locations around Europe. The BioHackathon offers an intense week of hacking, with over 160 international participants who work on diverse and exciting projects. The week starts with a half-day symposium to introduce these projects, and is followed by five days of hacking with one sole aim: coding to address problems in bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSSDay Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/11/sssday-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plazi will participate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal-cdn.scnat.ch/asset/4928d07d-53fe-59de-bbcf-463664a8a59a/Program%20SSSDay2021.pdf?b=25b8a4f9-7e85-5674-b05d-4571993988c3&amp;amp;v=01d816a3-4096-5079-adfe-684569ed9582_0&amp;amp;s=d9RZgAdsGUEetwPluJ-oURuGw5qLaefoeQUESYSd84S-I3A3ytMrGJCs6k3Y1BqjebskyyMkJ-mqF1BySozm0OMhcvAYlwG6x0yOK76iGixqf7yIk-NVXuzczTO-Uj7rIMy6sZ6WyeOLPRUW0CdudG4VfJyWDsxN5oWP7BagK8k&#34;&gt;SSSDay&lt;/a&gt; organised by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://swiss-systematics.ch/en/events/sss_day&#34;&gt;Swiss Systematics Society&lt;/a&gt; (SSS) to answer questions regarding the Swiss universities funded eBiodiv project and the EU Horizon 2020 funded &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; project. The event is hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zoologie.vd.ch/actuellement/&#34;&gt;Musée de Zoologie Lausanne&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://portal-cdn.scnat.ch/asset/4928d07d-53fe-59de-bbcf-463664a8a59a/Program%20SSSDay2021.pdf?b=25b8a4f9-7e85-5674-b05d-4571993988c3&amp;amp;v=01d816a3-4096-5079-adfe-684569ed9582_0&amp;amp;s=d9RZgAdsGUEetwPluJ-oURuGw5qLaefoeQUESYSd84S-I3A3ytMrGJCs6k3Y1BqjebskyyMkJ-mqF1BySozm0OMhcvAYlwG6x0yOK76iGixqf7yIk-NVXuzczTO-Uj7rIMy6sZ6WyeOLPRUW0CdudG4VfJyWDsxN5oWP7BagK8k&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the world of biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/tdwg-2021-virtual-annual-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we continue to connect people and biodiversity data globally by virtual means in these globally uncertain times, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tdwg.org/conferences/2021/&#34;&gt;TDWG 2021&lt;/a&gt; will be composed of symposia, workshops, contributed oral and poster presentations, demos, and discussions, as well as keynotes and social events. The Interest/Task Group working sessions will be held separately during the month following the virtual conference (November 2021). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tdwg.org/conferences/2021/session-list/&#34;&gt;TDWG Symposia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/17J5T0QdATdnrXgHWhguMErlSrfMo59qOCbss-R5whEU/edit#gid=1817747157&#34;&gt;TDWG Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;oct-20-830pm-cet-sym18-discovering-known-biodiversity-digital-accessible-knowledge&#34;&gt;Oct 20, 8:30PM CET SYM18 Discovering known biodiversity: Digital accessible knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session Type:&lt;/strong&gt; Symposium (no unsolicited presentations considered)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/digital-preservation-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We report progress towards automatically transforming existing analyses of scientific literature into annotations based on W3C&amp;rsquo;s Web Annotation Data Model (WADM). Case studies are presented from the life sciences, and social sciences and humanities, in which these developments have led to the creation of new unrestricted data services for the research community. We discuss the cross- domain potential of annotation infrastructure for releasing scientific facts reported in research literature from copyright restrictions, and demonstrate the utility of common standards-based preservation and discovery methods in disparate activities. We suggest that scientific treatments of literature using WADM annotation can lead to new mechanisms for access to and reuse of research data, and accelerate convergence with the FAIR Principles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eBiodiv Launch</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 21:03:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/launch-ebiodiv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the Naturhistorisches Museum in Bern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
