<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 16:04:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time for an interim review of Plazi’s Covid-19 related activities</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/time-for-an-interim-review-of-plazis-covid-19-related-activities/3e26b3bc95a4b39f0a2a9d7fccee8b19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/time-for-an-interim-review-of-plazis-covid-19-related-activities/3e26b3bc95a4b39f0a2a9d7fccee8b19/</guid>
      <description>Three months ago we started with Pensoft an effort (see also press release) to contribute to a better understanding of the SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2) aka corona virus that led to the global COVID-19 pandemic, and in the followup joined the CETAF-Covid-19 task force. With the end of the three months long taskforce we present here our view. A multimedia presentation by the knowledge base task force sub group has been streamed on July 17.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years of Plazi. On expedition to discover the known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/10-years-of-plazi-on-expedition-to-discover-the-known-biodiversity/2136104073c3aabdebe6c5067d767a52/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/10-years-of-plazi-on-expedition-to-discover-the-known-biodiversity/2136104073c3aabdebe6c5067d767a52/</guid>
      <description>This is the view of Donat Agosti, cofounder of Plazi.&#xA;In 1992, I wrote an article in the followup of the Rio Earth Summit in the Swiss newspaper Neue Zürcher Zeitung titled “Brauchen wir zu wissen, wie viele Arten es gibt?» Now, 2018, we are still discussing this question, and I am still convinced we should. Should, because we still don’t know know the answer. But must, because of the rapidly increasing, unprecendented loss of biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
