<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EBioDiv on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/ebiodiv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EBioDiv on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 11:25:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/ebiodiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>eBioDiv: linking specimens with literature, or to what is known about a specimen</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/linking-specimens-with-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 16:18:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/linking-specimens-with-literature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ebiodiv.org/&#34;&gt;eBioDiv&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissuniversities.ch/en/topics/digitalisation/open-science/programme&#34;&gt;Swissuniversities&lt;/a&gt; funded project by a consortium of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hes-so.ch/en/homepage&#34;&gt;HES-SO&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34;&gt;SIB&lt;/a&gt; (Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics), Plazi, and the Natural History Museum of Bern (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nmbe.ch/de&#34;&gt;NMBE&lt;/a&gt;) with the goal to build a knowledge infrastructure to bring data in taxonomic literature together with physical specimens digitalized through projects funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://swisscollnet.scnat.ch/de&#34;&gt;SwissCollNet&lt;/a&gt;. The linking is based on that fact that specimen, the basis of taxonomic works, are cited formally in the publications as material citations. They can be made &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.go-fair.org/fair-principles/&#34;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt; (Findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable). The eBioDiv &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/&#34;&gt;matching service&lt;/a&gt; allows to discover the cited specimen, especially if the natural history institution uploaded them to the Global Biodiversity Information Facility &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt;. The link furthermore allows to follow-up from a specimen to what is known about it in the published literature. The complementing Horizon Europe funded project Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; allows further linking of a specimen to taxonomic names or gene sequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
