<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>newsletter on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/newsletter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in newsletter on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:16:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Plazi Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/sebis-first-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/sebis-first-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>“Platypus” by Charles-Alexandre Lesueur released in Zoosystema, 43(21)   The platypus (Ornithorhynchus anatinus), sometimes referred to as the duck-billed platypus, is a semiaquatic, egg-laying mammal endemic to eastern Australia, including Tasmania. The platypus is the sole living representative of its family (Ornithorhynchidae) and genus (Ornithorhynchus), though a number of related species appear in the fossil record.
 Together with the four species of echidna, it is one of the five extant species of monotremes, the only mammals that lay eggs instead of giving birth to live young; they are all native to Australasia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to find out what we know</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/sebis-second-newsletter-extended/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/sebis-second-newsletter-extended/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Expand your knowledge by interlinking it to create a network of knowledge. In this months newsletter, we help you to find out how you enhance your publications, we present news from Plazi and show our latest publications and upcoming events.
Species of the Month  “Echiniscus Pardalis” by Peter Degma &amp; Ralph Oliver Schill released on Zoosystema, 2015.   The Echiniscus Pardalis is a new species of Tardigrada, it was collected on two moss samples in the Parco Naturale delle Alpi Marittime in northwestern Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anteater: The Plazi Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/_a-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/_a-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>“Giant Anteater” by Petr Kratochvil released CCO Public Domain Dedication   Anteater is a common name for the four extant mammal species of the suborder Vermilingua (meaning &amp;ldquo;worm tongue&amp;rdquo;) commonly known for eating ants and termites. The individual species have other names in English and other languages. Together with the sloths, they are within the order Pilosa.
  Wikipedia contributors. (2021, June 26). Anteater. In Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
