<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:06:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plazi on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/01/plazi-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:00:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2025/01/plazi-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-post&#34;&gt;First post&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On July 29, 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/plazi_species&#34;&gt;@plazi_species&lt;/a&gt; started on Twitter with the very first tweet; Caridina namdat - a freshwater shrimp from Vietnam. The post received 0 likes and 0 retweets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Caridina namdat - a freshwater shrimp from Vietnam&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/plazi_species/status/1420644565615366146&#34;&gt;Caridina namdat - a freshwater shrimp from Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this account was to showcase Plazi&amp;rsquo;s work to a wider audience through individual examples of newly discovered species whose treatments were integrated into Plazi’s TreatmentBank as FAIRdata.  The first post to break the 100-likes mark was posted on November 2, 2021 and showed Parosphromenus juelinae, a beautiful freshwater fish from Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching by ecoregions and biomes</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/12/searching-by-ecoregions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/12/searching-by-ecoregions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of the material citations extracted by Plazi contain geo-coordinates which opens up the way to searching for them by various geographic features along with the non-geographic attributes such as taxa. It is now possible to search for images that are a part of the treatments by ecoregions, biomes and realms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/ecoregions.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Ecoregions, biomes and realms from &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/records/10405991&#34;&gt;Olson, et. al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The World Wildlife Fund (WWF) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldwildlife.org/publications/terrestrial-ecoregions-of-the-world&#34;&gt;defines terrestrial ecoregions&lt;/a&gt; as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terrestrial Ecoregions of the World (TEOW) is a biogeographic regionalization of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s terrestrial biodiversity. Our biogeographic units are ecoregions, which are defined as relatively large units of land or water containing a distinct assemblage of natural communities sharing a large majority of species, dynamics, and environmental conditions. … Ecoregions represent the original distribution of distinct assemblages of species and communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling South African scientists to convert taxonomic publications into digitally accessible knowledge</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/training-s-african-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/training-s-african-scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/participants.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Group photo of the participants&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sanbi.org/&#34;&gt;SANBI &lt;/a&gt;(South African National Biodiversity Institute) conducted a training Course in Pretoria April 18 to 21, 2023, to teach local scientists how to facilitate the access and reuse of scholarly published taxonomic data by themselves as well as the scientific community at large.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course had the participation of 21 researchers, curators, technicians, and Postgraduate students from different South Africa&amp;rsquo;s biodiversity institutions and Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specimen - material citation matching service training course</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/specimen-material-citation-matching-service-training-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/specimen-material-citation-matching-service-training-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/participants.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Participants in the training course&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plazi’s first online two day training course “&lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity and Digital Media: linking material citations in publications to specimens&lt;/a&gt;” organized by Julia Giora and Jonas Castro has successfully ended. The Training school happened online from the 27th to the 28th of February 2023. It is part of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/&#34;&gt;series of training courses&lt;/a&gt; in which Plazi expects to teach interested parties how to use data preparation tools to become a data liberator. It was organized in collaborations with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobilise-action.eu/&#34;&gt;Mobilise COST Action&lt;/a&gt; – Mobilising Data, Policies and Experts in Scientific Collections – providing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobilise-action.eu/2023/01/24/plazi-mobilise-online-training-school-ts-announcement-27-28-feb-2023/&#34;&gt;Training School&lt;/a&gt; (TS) “&#xA;This hands-on and interactive training initiative gave the opportunity to 20 participants, from 11 countries, and representing 14 institutions of natural history research to get informed and exercised on the accessibility and reuse of taxonomic data using digital platforms and repositories.&#xA;The main theoretical topics addressed were the concept of findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://force11.org/info/the-fair-data-principles/&#34;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt;) and Plazi workflow, the repositories for taxonomic data, and an outlook on how to convert data from missing publications aiming a future of publishing according to FAIR data requirements. The practical activities were focused on the learning and use of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://prod.ebiodiv.org/&#34;&gt;eBioDiv Matching Service&lt;/a&gt;, with participants linking specimens in Global Biodiversity Information Facility (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt;) to materials citations extracted from scholarly publications and made available through Plazi&amp;rsquo;s TreatmentBank.&#xA;The development of tools and learning module is co-funded through &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the biodiversity knowledge graph</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 22:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discovery of species is based on specimens and communicated through taxonomic treatments described in and presented as parts of scientific publications. In an ideal world, this would allow us to ask questions such as “what is known about this specimen?” or “what does a gene sequence of a cited physical specimen look like?”, and the results would appear immediately on our computer screens in a format suitable for further analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arcadia supports Plazi in its endeavor to rediscover known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:25:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Swiss-based &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt; NGO has received a grant of EUR 1.5 million from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt; – a charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin – to further develop its &lt;a href=&#34;https://biolitrepo.org/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR)&lt;/a&gt; established in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;, the open science repository hosted and managed by the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), and the open-access scholarly publisher and technology provider &lt;a href=&#34;https://pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Pensoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/952793&#34;&gt;Eurekalert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/hero.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure left:&lt;/b&gt; A figure extracted from a scholarly article and made accessible via BLR. The image in preview mode can be downloaded inclusive of source in the metadata. Visible are links to other data elements from the article citing the figure, the source publication, a machine readable license and download alternatives. A deposit of a figure extracted from a scholarly article and made accessible via the Biodiversity Literature Repository. The image in preview mode can be downloaded inclusive of source in the metadata. On the right, there are links to other data elements from the article citing the figure, the source publication, a machine readable license and alternatives to download the data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.253091&#34;&gt;DOI: 10.5281/zenodo.253091&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access to taxonomic treatments mentioned in press releases</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At year-end, it is common to review the past year’s highlights as we (Plazi) too did, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/posts/2021/12/new-species-2021/&#34;&gt;highlighting a few of the almost 9000 species discovered in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. A few of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading taxonomic institutions did so as well with their recent discoveries. Since we are interested in not just finding about the species discovered but also learning more in detail about them, we decided to test how easy it was to locate their original taxonomic treatments in the scientific papers that described the species mentioned in the press releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Species of 2021</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/12/new-species-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 21:40:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2021/12/new-species-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2021 Plazi provided access to the taxonomic treatments and figures of 8848 new species, 647 new genera and 27 new families discovered as part of 11391 changes in taxonomic status in 2021, published in 4420 articles from 95 journals. Here we present a small selection of 12 spectacular species with links to their complete taxonomic treatment. Since we can &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; protect what we know, we want people to have free access to taxonomic data, always and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MaterialCitation accepted as a new TDWG Darwin Core standard</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-accepted-as-a-new-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-accepted-as-a-new-term/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 25, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-submitted-as-a-new-term/&#34;&gt;new term request&lt;/a&gt; by Plazi for a new term for “a reference to or citation of one, a part of, or multiple specimens in scholarly publications” went through the public review process and resulted in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dwc.tdwg.org/list/#dwc_MaterialCitation&#34;&gt;ratified term&lt;/a&gt; and in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dwc.tdwg.org/terms/#materialcitation&#34;&gt;Quick Reference Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original term name materialCitation has been changed to follow Darwin Core convention of using upper camel case for Class names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight is 20x20000</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/hindsight-is-20x20000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 12:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/hindsight-is-20x20000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/workflow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Workflow&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three years ago we set off on a journey, guided by a philosophy that scientific data trapped in scholarly articles should be free, powered by the creativity and hardwork of a small team scattered around the globe, and supported by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt; that decided to invest in our vision. Earlier this month we completed that journey, by all measures, a success. We liberated more data than we set out to liberate, we ended up with more partners than we started with, and we empowered more publications and publishers than three years ago. Data liberated by us is already being used by scientists to ask and answer new questions, to pursue new science – a true scientific data lifecycle in constant motion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BHL and Plazi partnership</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/bhl-and-plazi-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/bhl-and-plazi-partnership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/bhl-plazi.png&#34; alt=&#34;BHL and Plazi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biodiversitylibrary.org/&#34;&gt;BHL&lt;/a&gt; and Plazi have agreed to collaborate to create a workflow from existing literature to liberate digital accessible data to its&#xA;reuse in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt;. This includes the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Find, digitize, and provide access to biodiversity-related documents&#xA;with basic metadata and scanned images for each and every page&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Text recognition that allows efficient conversion and processing&#xA;downstream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Provide access at publication level, including standard, citable URLs from&#xA;the scholarly communication ecosystem (e.g. CrossRef DOIs, DataCite&#xA;DOIs)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Conversion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;into generic JATS XML or TEI including figures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;into PDFs with included text and stable URLs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liberate data from these biodiversity-related documents; identify,&#xA;semantically enhance, and link with external resources&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Names entities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Constituent text sections&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Figures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tables&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bibliographic references&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create and publish FAIR data on Zenodo, or other repositories&#xA;with the same capabilities, particularly those providing access&#xA;enabling reuse&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interact with targeted reuser of data for data and visualization&#xA;improvements (eg. GBIF, openBioDiv)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/15QbYAuOyGkpS68YWlfpj0rdsZrl_oTWA/view&#34;&gt;More about the partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The digital age and the tragedy of not knowing what we know about biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/not-knowing-what-we-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/not-knowing-what-we-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the big challenges in biology - how many species are on planet Earth, where do they live and what do they do -  is increasingly relevant in the age of the biodiversity crisis. In the digital age this turns awkward, because it becomes obvious that we do not even know what we know about biodiversity. Whilst the libraries have been the undisputed source of knowledge in the analogue age, having hard copies in libraries does not serve the needs anymore. Neither does the Portable Document Format (PDF), the currently most widespread publishing format and required by the Codes of nomenclature. None of them allows machines to access the facts in the estimated 500 Million pages of legacy publications. It requires a huge amount of scientists’ time to catalogue the content, for example to build the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.catalogueoflife.org/&#34;&gt;Catalogue of Life&lt;/a&gt;, a goal the latest since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/en/conferences/environment/rio1992&#34;&gt;Rio Earth Summit&lt;/a&gt; in 1992. But a catalogue itself isn’t enough because this does not allow to explore the many implicit links, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/news/beitrag/the-taxonomic-treatments-from-linnaeus-systema-naturae-1758-10th-edition-liberated/8f2fef3ef0a651ac80768c66436b24d1/&#34;&gt;taxonomic treatments&lt;/a&gt;, traits and specimens used to describe new or enhance the knowledge on existing species with additional data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>materialCitation as a new class submitted to TDWG Darwin Core standard</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-submitted-as-a-new-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/materialcitation-submitted-as-a-new-term/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Specimens are a critical basis for taxonomic research. They are cited in taxonomic treatments and other works. Increasingly these material citations are extracted from publications and submitted as part of data sets to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/publisher/7ce8aef0-9e92-11dc-8738-b8a03c50a862&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt; and reused in studies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of today, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt; includes 33,393 datasets derived from taxonomic publications and 415,858 material citations which are labeled as occurrences. 335 publications reuse this data. An estimate of 45,000 species are only represented in &lt;a href=&#34;https://gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt; through material citations from publications, mainly covering new species that are extracted from the literature just after the publishing time. This cuts short the time to enter taxonomic names and re-submit datasets to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new GBIF Plazi data issue feedback loop</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/data-issue-feedback-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/data-issue-feedback-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/gbif-plazi-feedback.png&#34; alt=&#34;Data Feedback&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plazi’s goal is to discover known biodiversity, and make it widely available using the tools available in the digital age. This means liberating data hidden in libraries, and more recently, and increasingly hidden in the PDF-prison, paywalls and unstructured text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grand challenge is an estimated 500 Million published pages of scholarly biodiversity related publications, and 17,000 annually new discovered and described species with a multiple of annotations on already known species.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClickUp supporting Plazi with task management system </title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/clickup-supporting-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/clickup-supporting-plazi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clickup.com/?utm_expid=.m0awzPKhRiaeu5QZBeY2YQ.0&amp;amp;utm_referrer=&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/clickup.png&#34; alt=&#34;ClickUp&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Managing collaborations involving multiple locations, time zones and complementing operations is challenging. As an example, Plazi liberates data from scholarly publications by making it, in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://home.cern/&#34;&gt;CERN&lt;/a&gt;, findable, citable  reusable for anybody, anywhere, at any time. This process happens in multiple locations in Europe, Brazil and North America. The increasingly automated processes are based on agile programming. The maintenance and improvement of high quality data requires an additional amount of time critical interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time for an interim review of Plazi’s Covid-19 related activities</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/time-for-an-interim-review-of-plazis-covid-19-related-activities/3e26b3bc95a4b39f0a2a9d7fccee8b19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/time-for-an-interim-review-of-plazis-covid-19-related-activities/3e26b3bc95a4b39f0a2a9d7fccee8b19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/custom-metadata.png&#34; alt=&#34;Custom Metadata&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three months ago we started with Pensoft an &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/news/beitrag/plazi-and-pensoft-launch-an-initiative-to-provide-access-to-scholarly-published-data-about-coronavirus-hosts/a842a012361dd7a7c96b87e21bce8653/&#34;&gt;effort&lt;/a&gt; (see also &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.pensoft.net/2020/04/07/plazi-and-pensoft-join-forces-to-let-biodiversity-knowledge-of-coronaviruses-hosts-out/&#34;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;) to contribute to a better understanding of the SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2) aka corona virus that led to the global COVID-19 pandemic, and in the followup joined the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cetaf.org/news/joint-cetaf-dissco-covid-19-task-force-call-contributions&#34;&gt;CETAF-Covid-19 task force&lt;/a&gt;. With the end of the three months long taskforce we present here our view. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gnywe5hiMLU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=4622&#34;&gt;multimedia presentation&lt;/a&gt; by the knowledge base task force sub group has been streamed on July 17.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The taxonomic treatments from Linnaeus’ Systema Naturae, 1758, 10th edition, liberated</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/linnaeus-systema-naturae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/linnaeus-systema-naturae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/taxonomic-treatment.png&#34; alt=&#34;Taxonomic treatment&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taxonomic treatment. The taxonomic treatment is a well defined part of a publication about a particular taxon, in this case of the honey bee Apis mellifera, described by Linnaeus 1758 on page 576-577. It is based on the implicitly cited specimens in his reference collection.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A milestone in the development of modern biology was the introduction of the standardization resulting from comparative and reference works. This led to a rapidly growing corpus of knowledge by learning from, referencing of, and building on previous work, today known as the data life cycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extended collective licence agreement between Plazi and ProLitteris: Plazi adopts to revised copyright law in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/agreement-between-plazi-and-prolitteris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/agreement-between-plazi-and-prolitteris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 1st of April, 2020, a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/news/beitrag/new-copyright-law-in-switzerland-empowers-scientific-research/5bda7d3847face91269c61a70665f0b7/&#34;&gt;copyright law&lt;/a&gt; was enacted in Switzerland. Amongst other revision points, it declares an extension of the protection of photographs by applying the notion of work to non-individual photographs, provides for a new copyright exception for the use of copyrighted works for purposes of scientific research, and introduces extended collective licenses as a new instrument for collective copyright regulation. As the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-2-53&#34;&gt;Plazi workflow&lt;/a&gt; is organised and ruled by &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/news/beitrag/new-copyright-law-in-switzerland-empowers-scientific-research/5bda7d3847face91269c61a70665f0b7/&#34;&gt;Swiss copyright law&lt;/a&gt;, Plazi had to adapt to these legal amendments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plazi and Pensoft launch an initiative to provide access to scholarly published data about Coronavirus hosts</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/coronavirus-hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/coronavirus-hosts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2020-04/pp-pap040720.php&#34;&gt;Eurekalert!&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.knowledgespeak.com/news/plazi-and-pensoft-partner-to-let-biodiversity-knowledge-of-coronaviruses-hosts-out/&#34;&gt;Knoweldge Speak&lt;/a&gt; release.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic presumably started with the escape of the Coronavirus from its bat host to humans. To understand the original host, it is important to have access to relevant scientific knowledge about these organisms. The scientific results from charting the world’s biodiversity reside in a vast corpus, which is often “imprisoned” by paywalls, copyright laws or trapped in formats unfavorable to text and data mining. For the majority of the world’s species, there exist only one or a few articles providing descriptions of the species or adding some additional observations. Even for well-known groups such as birds and mammals, access to primary taxonomic literature requires extensive and time-consuming specialist searches. Bats, suspected hosts of COVID-19 and other viruses such as Ebola, are particularly poorly covered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catalogueoflife.org/&#34;&gt;Catalogue of Life&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catalogueoflife.org/col/details/database/id/115&#34;&gt;ITIS&lt;/a&gt;, and most taxonomic information is locked within commercial closed-access books and scholarly articles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Role of Open Science in Charting Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/open-science-charting-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/open-science-charting-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1343376&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/plazi-slide.png&#34; alt=&#34;header image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A striking example of the impact of open access on the usage of scientific publications. Around 2000 antbase.org, co-funded by the Atherton-Seidal Foundation at the Smithsonian Institution provided open access to the entire ant taxonomic literature. Within a very short time, this resource has been used world wide. DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1343376&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.1343376&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following discussions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://taxacom.markmail.org/search/?q=%22open%20science%22#query:%22open%20science%22+page:1+mid:ucbqotjlenxk3ief+state:results&#34;&gt;Taxacom&lt;/a&gt; list server on the value on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fosteropenscience.eu/node/1420&#34;&gt;Open Science&lt;/a&gt;, here some points to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The situation has changed regarding open access and open science. The EU fully requires open access to anything they fund. No funds are awarded to any institution that will not accept a commitment to open access. Many of our institutions signed up the Bouchout Declaration on Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management and open access is for example a central part of the development of DiSSCo – the Distributed System of Scientific Collections in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 new species added to GBIF during the first Plazi training course at the Congresso Brasileiro de Zoologia</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/first-plazi-training-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/first-plazi-training-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/new-species.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Species&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plazi Minicurso at the Congresso Brasileiro de Zoologia, March 1, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taxonomic literature is an almost untapped resource of data covering our scholarly knowledge of biodiversity. This includes an estimated 500 Million printed pages and is augmented annually with over 17.000 taxonomic treatments of species new to science. This data represents in fact an incredibly rich citation network, albeit with most of the citations implicit, only understandable by extensive domain expertise, and often with an insurmountable time required to follow up chasing the cited resources. Plazi’s aim, together with the support of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://home.cern/&#34;&gt;CERN&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt; repository, is to liberate the imprisoned data and make it findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.force11.org/group/fairgroup/fairprinciples&#34;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Copyright Law in Switzerland Empowers Scientific Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2019/10/new-copyright-law-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 13:10:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2019/10/new-copyright-law-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Swiss Parliament adopted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parlament.ch/centers/eparl/curia/2017/20170069/Schlussabstimmungstext%201%20NS%20D.pdf&#34;&gt;new copyright law&lt;/a&gt; on 27 September, 2019. Amongst its many new elements, there is a large exception to copyright for the use of protected works for scientific research purposes (Art. 24d&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). This exception is compulsory and overrules any subsequent license agreements. It allows copying and reuse of copyrighted works for commercial or non-commercial scientific research, and refers to any work to which the researcher has lawful access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der geplante Lichtbildschutz Artikel (Art 2 Abs. 3bis) behindert Forschung und IT-Industrie</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/lichtbildschutz-artikel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/lichtbildschutz-artikel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Am kommenden Montag (21.1.2019) berät die Kommission for Wissenschaft, Bildung und Kultur (WBK) des schweizerischen Ständerates die Revision des Urheberrechtsgesetzes. Nach dem jetzigen Revisionsentwurf sollen in Zukunft auch Fotografien, welche keinen individuellen Charakter haben, wie Werke der Kunst und der Literatur geschützt werden. Wir sind der Meinung, dass durch eine solche Bestimmung der wissenschaftlichen Lehre und Forschung, und letztlich unserer IT Industrie und Gesellschaft, erheblicher Schaden zugefügt wird, und zwar aus den folgenden Gründen:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training for building and reusing your corpus of mineable taxonomic literature</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/mineable-taxonomic-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/mineable-taxonomic-literature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/visualization.png&#34; alt=&#34;Visualization&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visualization of data liberated from 22 published articles in the journals Zootaxa and PLoS ONE during the training course at Leiden University&amp;rsquo;s Integrative Taxonomy course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The taxonomic literature is a rich, high quality, and largely untapped source of biodiversity knowledge. Taxonomy helps us recognize species and map their distributions through text descriptions, images, and records of when and where they have been observed. These are the data we need to answer questions that are relevant to our world today, like setting conservation priorities and anticipating the effects of climate change on biodiversity and ecosystem functions that affect the lives of people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need BLR to store scholarly taxonomic articles?</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/blr-scholarly-taxonomic-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/blr-scholarly-taxonomic-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Jérôme Constant published yesterday his &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5852/ejt.2018.486&#34;&gt;taxonomic article&lt;/a&gt; on eurybrachid planthopper insects in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.europeanjournaloftaxonomy.eu/index.php/ejt/index&#34;&gt;European Journal of Taxonomy&lt;/a&gt;, its data became immediately accessible as FAIR and open access data in &lt;a href=&#34;http://treatment.plazi.org/GgServer/summary/FFECFFA1FF9D4B16FFB3FF95FFB7FFC3&#34;&gt;TreatmentBank&lt;/a&gt; including &lt;a href=&#34;http://treatment.plazi.org/id/26C5880F-0D15-409D-99C3-CA496382C6FE&#34;&gt;taxonomic treatments&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://biolitrepo.org/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity Literature Repository&lt;/a&gt; (BLR) as an article and figures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This data is also at the same moment reused by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt; to describe the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/dataset/0e26b0d8-14bc-46b2-aac6-feed5d62b2d8&#34;&gt;dataset&lt;/a&gt; aka article, to list all its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/occurrence/search?dataset_key=0e26b0d8-14bc-46b2-aac6-feed5d62b2d8&#34;&gt;material citations&lt;/a&gt;, provide the taxonomic treatments for the included &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/species/150668922&#34;&gt;species&lt;/a&gt;, which is especially valuable for those new to the sciences or an individual &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/occurrence/1949872163&#34;&gt;occurrence&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/news/beitrag/expanded-access-to-images-in-the-biodiversity-literature-repository/b86d1880198c5c7315c2d38ae3a82820/&#34;&gt;Ocellus&lt;/a&gt; is using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocellus.punkish.org/?q=olonia&amp;amp;page=1&#34;&gt;figures&lt;/a&gt; to index journals and provide a novel access to them. All the bibliographic references have been added to &lt;a href=&#34;http://refbank.org/&#34;&gt;Refbank&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the references in the article include a Digital Object Identifier &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.doi.org/&#34;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;, but most do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schnappschüsse und das Urheberrecht (Snapshots and copyright law)</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/schnappschuesse-urheberrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/schnappschuesse-urheberrecht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nzz.ch/meinung/bezahlschranken-fuer-fotos-ld.1433968&#34;&gt;Thursday November 29, 2018&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1682067&#34;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;) issue of the Neue Zürcher Zeitung includes a “Gastkommentar” by me (Donat Agosti) arguing that the proposed insertion of an article protecting any kind of photographs of three dimensional objects in the revised copyright law of Switzerland is misguided (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parlament.ch/centers/eparl/curia/2017/20170069/N1%20D.pdf&#34;&gt;Art. 2 al.&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the sciences, illustrations, including photographs, play a crucial role. They are one among many types of research data, and are used to visually document and compare results. Although in the current debate about access to research data in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snf.ch/de/derSnf/forschungspolitische_positionen/open_access/Seiten/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Switzerland&lt;/a&gt; and abroad the main focus is on open access to research articles, the movement is broadening to include open data and open science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provenance – another look at taxonomic treatments and names</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/provenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/provenance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When an &amp;rsquo;ex banker&amp;rsquo; - Tim Robertson -  meets an &amp;rsquo;ex taxonomist&amp;rsquo; - Donat Agosti - this can be very inspiring, especially when they discover that they share rather unexpectedly more than they ever expected. So, what is it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both share data lineages. The banker has bank accounts that are created, mutated and that  have at a  given time a certain value. The taxonomist has species that are described, mutated and at a given time have a certain name. Both of them have provenance, a documented lineage of data that includes the data origins, what happened to it and where it moves over time, a ledger in bankers term. It allows to trace the history, and in taxonomy it ought to allow to reproduce the history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZooKeys 10th anniversary</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/zookeys-10th-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/zookeys-10th-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zookeys.pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/zookeys.png&#34; alt=&#34;ZooKeys&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zookeys at 10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy Birthday &lt;a href=&#34;https://zookeys.pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Zookeys&lt;/a&gt;, and congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Pensoft&lt;/a&gt;, its innovator and publisher.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s 10th anniversary of Zookeys is a great day for biodiversity. The discoveries reported in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-07/pp-zc1070318.php&#34;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; and celebrated in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zookeys.pensoft.net/issue/1511/&#34;&gt;770th issue&lt;/a&gt; of the journal are magnificent and open access, unlike the big bulk of taxonomic articles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The real and unreported impact of Zookeys, its sister &lt;a href=&#34;https://bdj.pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity Data Journal&lt;/a&gt; and the many &lt;a href=&#34;https://pensoft.net/browse_journals&#34;&gt;other natural history journals&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Pensoft is neither reported by Pensoft, widely recognized by the taxonomists nor the wider scientific community: The revolution caused, and enabled by, the technical changes adopted in the publishing of Zookeys and the subsequent journals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plazi and BLR receive €1.1 million from Arcadia to open up new biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/arcadia-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/arcadia-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/visual-search-result.png&#34; alt=&#34;Visual Search Result&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual search results from the Biodiversity Literature Repository. Each of the images provides access to the taxonomic treatment of the species or the source article. Only figures from scholarly publications are provided.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plazi has received a grant of EUR 1.1 million from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt; – the charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin – to liberate data, such as taxonomic treatments and images, trapped in scholarly biodiversity publications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years of Plazi. On expedition to discover the known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/10-years-of-plazi-on-expedition-to-discover-the-known-biodiversity/2136104073c3aabdebe6c5067d767a52/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/news/beitrag/10-years-of-plazi-on-expedition-to-discover-the-known-biodiversity/2136104073c3aabdebe6c5067d767a52/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the view of Donat Agosti, cofounder of Plazi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1992, I wrote an article in the followup of the Rio Earth Summit in the Swiss newspaper Neue Zürcher Zeitung titled “Brauchen wir zu wissen, wie viele Arten es gibt?» Now, 2018, we are still discussing this question, and I am still convinced we should. Should, because we still don’t know know the answer. But must, because of the rapidly increasing, unprecendented loss of biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years of Plazi. On expedition to discover the known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/10-years-of-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/10-years-of-plazi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the view of Donat Agosti, cofounder of Plazi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1992, I wrote an article in the followup of the Rio Earth Summit in the Swiss newspaper Neue Zürcher Zeitung titled “Brauchen wir zu wissen, wie viele Arten es gibt?» Now, 2018, we are still discussing this question, and I am still convinced we should. Should, because we still don’t know know the answer. But must, because of the rapidly increasing, unprecendented loss of biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>200.000 deposits at the Biodiversity Literature Repository!</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/200000-deposits-at-blr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/200000-deposits-at-blr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/ocellus.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ocellus&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocellus: Search term &amp;ldquo;Perlidae&amp;rdquo;. All the images are provided with a link to the source.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wealth of data encapsulated in scientific publications is a well-guarded secret. The recent discussions around Open Access are centered around open access to the articles, and thus little effort is made to build an index, for example, of all the illustrations therein. This is even more astounding in descriptive sciences, such as biological taxonomy, dealing with discovering and describing the world’s biological diversity, where each article includes an average of 7.2 illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pensoft and Plazi join forces to expedite building the OpenBioDiv</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/building-openbiodiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/building-openbiodiv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/pensoft-plazi.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pensoft Plazi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pensoft - Plazi project to produce semantically enhanced data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Science is based on open data. Data &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt; is not copyrighted and thus freely accessible. However it is kept in well maintained prisons, such as hard disks on a scientist’s desk to large password protected databases to publications that lost all their semantic structure in transition from a scientists lab to the publishers print shop. To paraphrase, scientist do all to loose structure in their data in publications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2018</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/happy-new-year-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/happy-new-year-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 has been a productive year at Plazi.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9,601 articles have been processed from 173 different journals resulting in 82,082 taxonomic treatments, 62,958 scientific figures uploaded to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/communities/biosyslit/?page=1&amp;amp;size=20&#34;&gt;Biodiversity Literature Repository&lt;/a&gt; (BLR), including 314,881 bibliographic references of which 37,120 have a digital object identifier (DOI).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 3,177 articles published in 2017 that we mined for data  included one new family, 330 new genera and 5,145 new species, and a total of 30,091 taxonomic treatments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The TreatmentBank now includes  216,868 taxonomic treatments from 26,727 articles; of the 850,781 bibliographic references 79,205 have DOI.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://biolitrepo.org/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity Literature Repository&lt;/a&gt; now includes 167,681 open access figures and 12,586 open access publications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data is transferred on a daily base to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/publisher/7ce8aef0-9e92-11dc-8738-b8a03c50a862&#34;&gt;Global Biodiversity Information Facility&lt;/a&gt; (GBIF) and to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/projects/linkout/journals/htmllists.cgi?type_id=9&#34;&gt;NCBI&lt;/a&gt; making Plazi one of the largest name providers to the taxonomic backbone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Access to BLR has been greatly improved with the creation of  standards-compliant and well-documented &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/news/beitrag/expanded-access-to-images-in-the-biodiversity-literature-repository/b86d1880198c5c7315c2d38ae3a82820/&#34;&gt;Zenodeo API&lt;/a&gt;, a nodejs (server-side JavaScript) API that queries the Zenodo API with more BLR-specific queries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A new web application called  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocellus.punkish.org/&#34;&gt;Ocellus&lt;/a&gt;, now provides  improved access to the image store in the BLR.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 promises to be an exciting year at Plazi.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
