<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Plazi on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Plazi on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>2021
  Agosti D, Cornwell P, Bénichou L, Gonzalez J, Herren M, Ruch P 2021. Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data. iPRES 2021 - 17th International Conference on Digital Preservation, October 19-22, 2021, Beijing, China. manuscript
  Waterhouse RM, Adam-Blondon AF, Agosti D et al. Recommendations for connecting molecular sequence and biodiversity research infrastructures through ELIXIR [version 1; peer review: awaiting peer review].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi Members</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/members/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti
Taxonomic literature, systematics and conservation
President Plazi
Director Plazi GmbH
Research Associate
Naturhistorisches Museum, Bern
Berne, Switzerland
agosti@plazi.org  Klemens Böhm
Member of Board (2008-)
Professor
Lehrstuhl für Systeme der Informationsverwaltung
Karlsruher Institute of Technology
Karlsruhe, GERMANY
boehm@kit.edu  Terry Catapano
Lead developer of TaxonX XML schema and Taxpub Extension of the NLM/NCBI JATS DTD
Vice-President Plazi
Columbia University
New York, USA
catapano@plazi.org  Hong Cui
Natural language processing, character modeling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</guid>
      <description>Zenodo Zenodo, Plazi and Pensoft collaborate in developing the Biodiversity Literature Repository as an open access repository to articles and liberated open FAIR data including figures and taxonomic treatments related to biodiversity. A customized access is provided for all its content via the BLR website and to images via Ocellus.
read more
GBIF Plazi joined GBIF 2001 and is since 2015 an associate participant of GBIF. Plazi provides occurrences liberated and extracted from the scientific literature, especially from treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story behind Plazi</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</guid>
      <description>Placidus a Spescha was not only one of the first alpinists and naturalists but was also deeply committed to the ideals of the Enlightenment. He often ran afoul of his superiors who felt he neglected his priestly duties in favor of his scientific pursuits. Worse yet, he further upset the status quo through his sympathy and support of the French in the follow-up of the wars spurred by the French Revolution which brought invading French and Austrian troops into his home, Disentis, in the Vorderrhein Tal in Switzerland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
