<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Plazi on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Plazi on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Accessible Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/digital-accessible-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/digital-accessible-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Digital Accessible Knowledge, in the context of Plazi, describes data fit for use to understand the global biodiversity, to create a list of all known species on planet Earth, data that is machine-actionable and ready for use by anybody, anyhwere at any time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>All our publications are published under open licenses. If you are unable to locate a copy, please contact us and we will be happy to send it to you.
2022 Agosti D, Ruch P, Benito Gonzalez Lopez J, Penev L (2022) Enabling Published Taxonomic Data to be used to Address the Biodiversity Crisis: Biodiversity Literature Repository and TreatmentBank. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 6: e91167. doi Fawcett S, Agosti D, Cole SR, Wright CF 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi Members</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/members/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti
Taxonomic literature, systematics and conservation
President Plazi
Director Plazi GmbH
Research Associate
Naturhistorisches Museum, Bern
Berne, Switzerland
agosti@plazi.org Klemens Böhm
Member of Board (2008-)
Professor
Lehrstuhl für Systeme der Informationsverwaltung
Karlsruher Institute of Technology
Karlsruhe, GERMANY
boehm@kit.edu Terry Catapano
Lead developer of TaxonX XML schema and Taxpub Extension of the NLM/NCBI JATS DTD
Vice-President Plazi
Columbia University
New York, USA
catapano@plazi.org Hong Cui
Natural language processing, character modeling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</guid>
      <description>Zenodo Zenodo, Plazi and Pensoft collaborate in developing the Biodiversity Literature Repository as an open access repository to articles and liberated open FAIR data including figures and taxonomic treatments related to biodiversity. A customized access is provided for all its content via the BLR website and to images via Ocellus.
read more
GBIF Plazi joined GBIF 2001 and is since 2015 an associate participant of GBIF. Plazi provides occurrences liberated and extracted from the scientific literature, especially from treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ongoing and past projects</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/projects/</guid>
      <description>Current Projects Arcadia 2022-2025 The grant will help build on the momentum created in the first Arcadia supported project (years 2018-2021) by: (1) leading the data extraction effort and building a critical mass of FAIR scientific data and related tools involving the community; and (2) establishing a long lasting, self-sustaining research infrastructure.
BiCIKL (EU) Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library (BiCIKL) is building the Biodiversity Knowledge Hub (BKH). more
NIH-R21 Viral Spillover (NIH) The goal of this proposed project is to harness the collective power of bioinformatics, artificial intelligence (AI), and ecology to transform our understanding of taxon-specific zoonotic risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/lectures/</guid>
      <description>Lectures by Plazi team members are available at BLR and SlideShare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story behind Plazi</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</guid>
      <description>Placidus a Spescha was not only one of the first alpinists and naturalists but was also deeply committed to the ideals of the Enlightenment. He often ran afoul of his superiors who felt he neglected his priestly duties in favor of his scientific pursuits. Worse yet, he further upset the status quo through his sympathy and support of the French in the follow-up of the wars spurred by the French Revolution which brought invading French and Austrian troops into his home, Disentis, in the Vorderrhein Tal in Switzerland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
