<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Plazi</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Plazi&amp;rsquo;s Goal Plazi supports and promotes the development of persistent and openly accessible digital taxonomic literature. To this end Plazi:
 Maintains a digital taxonomic literature repository to enable archiving of taxonomic treatments. Enhances submitted taxonomic treatments by creating TaxonX and Taxpub XML versions. Participates in the development of new models for publishing taxonomic treatments in order to maximize interoperability with relevant cyberinfrastructure components (e.g., name servers, biodiversity resources, etc…) Advocates and educates about the vital importance of maintaining free and open access to scientific discourse and data  Plazi is a not-for-profit organization based in Bern, Switzerland and was founded on March 13th 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>2021   Miller JA, Agosti D, Guidoti M, Rivera Quiroz FA. 2021. Linking and the Role of the Material Citation. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75543. doi: 10.3897/biss.5.75543
  Agosti D, Egloff W. 2021. Herausfinden, was wir schon wissen. Gfbs Newsletter, 39, 24–31. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.5168465
  Guidoti M, Sokolowicz C, Simoes F, Gonçalves V, Ruschel T, Alvares DJ, Agosti D 2021. TreatmentBank: Plazi&amp;rsquo;s strategies and its implementation to most efficiently liberate data from scholarly publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plazi Members</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 19:17:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/members/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti
Taxonomic literature, systematics and conservation
President Plazi
Director Plazi GmbH
Research Associate
Naturhistorisches Museum, Bern
Berne, Switzerland
email
  Klemens Böhm
Member of Board (2008-)
Professor
Lehrstuhl für Systeme der Informationsverwaltung
Karlsruher Institute of Technology
Karlsruhe, GERMANY
email
  Terry Catapano
Lead developer of TaxonX XML schema and Taxpub Extension of the NLM/NCBI JATS DTD
Vice-President Plazi
Columbia University
New York, USA
email
  Hong Cui</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/partners/</guid>
      <description>Zenodo Zenodo, Plazi and Pensoft collaborate in developing the Biodiversity Literature Repository as an open access repository to articles and liberated open FAIR data including figures and taxonomic treatments related to biodiversity. A customized access is provided for all its content via the BLR website and to images via Ocellus.
read more
GBIF Plazi joined GBIF 2001 and is since 2015 an associate participant of GBIF. Plazi provides occurrences liberated and extracted from the scientific literature, especially from treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/projects/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing Projects 
Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library (BiCIKL) is building the Biodiversity Knowledge Hub (BKH) — a single knowledge portal to interlinked and machine-readable FAIR data (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable and Reusable) using unique stable identifiers on specimens, genomics, observations, taxonomy and publications. more https://bicikl-project.eu/
Past Projects Arcadia 
The Arcadia Fund supported a three-year project to liberate 300,000 taxonomic treatments, build together with Zenodo and Pensoft the Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) at Zenodo/CERN, and develop within TreatmentBank tools and services to liberate data and make them accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story behind Plazi</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/the-story-behind-plazi/</guid>
      <description>Placidus a Spescha was not only one of the first alpinists and naturalists but was also deeply committed to the ideals of the Enlightenment. He often ran afoul of his superiors who felt he neglected his priestly duties in favor of his scientific pursuits. Worse yet, he further upset the status quo through his sympathy and support of the French in the follow-up of the wars spurred by the French Revolution which brought invading French and Austrian troops into his home, Disentis, in the Vorderrhein Tal in Switzerland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
