<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 11:02:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All our publications are published under open licenses. If you are unable to locate a copy, please contact us and we will be happy to send it to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2025&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Cornelius J, Detering H, Lithgow-Serrano O, Agosti D, Rinaldi F, Waterhouse R (2025) From literature to biodiversity data: mining arthropod organismal traits with machine learning. Biodiversity Data Journal 13: e153070. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/BDJ.13.e153070&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/BDJ.13.e153070&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Buschbom, J., Bénichou, L., Agosti, D., Egloff, W., Herrmann, E., Kageyama, M., Kroh, A., &amp; Mergen, P. (2025). Open data in publications – non-copyrightability and attribution as drivers for equity, science and innovation. European Journal of Taxonomy, 1004(1), 120-143. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5852/ejt.2025.1004.2971&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5852/ejt.2025.1004.2971&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Cornelius J, Detering H, Lithgow-Serrano O, Agosti D, Rinaldi F, Waterhouse RM (2025) From literature to biodiversity data: mining arthropod organismal and ecological traits with machine learning. bioRxiv 2025.02.18.638830; doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.02.18.638830&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.02.18.638830&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2024&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Uetz, P., &amp; Agosti, D. (2024) Species descriptions go digital. Zenodo. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15291267&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15291267&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Arvanitidis C, Casino A, Kishor P, Mergen P, Nielsen LH, Penev L, Ruch P, Bénichou, L. (2024) Liberate the power of biodiversity literature as FAIR digital objects - Policy Brief. Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library (BiCIKL). doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15012681&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15012681&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Bénichou L, Casino A, Nielsen L, Ruch P, Kishor P, Penev L, Mergen P, Arvanitidis C (2024) Liberate the power of biodiversity literature as FAIR digital objects. Research Ideas and Outcomes 10: e126586. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.10.e126586&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.10.e126586&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Buschbom J, Bénichou L, Agosti D, Egloff W, Hermann E, Kageyama M, Kroh A, Mergen P (2024) Non-Copyrightability of Data in Scientific Publications: A Free-for-All or a Global Commons Partnership? Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 8: e138801. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.8.138801&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.8.138801&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Paupério J, Gupta V, Balavenkataraman Kadhirvelu V, Abarenkov K, Addink W, Agosti D, Bánki O, Burgin J, Ernst M, Frøslev T, Groom Q, Güntsch A, Jayathilaka S, Leeflang S, Kõljalg U, Miller J, Sautter G, Penev L, Cochrane G (2024) Linking Between Molecular and Biodiversity Data: A BiCIKL Perspective. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 8: e135646. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.8.135646&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.8.135646&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Penev L, Koureas D, Groom Q, Lanfear J, Agosti D, Casino A, Miller J, Cochrane G, Bánki O, Kõljalg U, Ruch P, Güntsch A, Benito Gonzalez Lopez J, Mergen P, Pauperio J, Kuhn T, Minadakis N, Smith V, Arvanitidis C (2024) Beyond BiCIKL: Towards Building an AI-Assisted “Biodiversity Supergraph”. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 8: e135550. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.8.135550&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.8.135550&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2023&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Penev L, Ruch P, Benichou L, Ioannidis-Pantopikos A (2023) The Ecosystem of Linked Biodiversity Publications: General Picture of Tools and Services Created by Plazi, Pensoft, MNHN, CETAF, Zenodo, and SIBiLS. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e110681. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.110681&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.110681&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Benichou L, Agosti D, Egloff W, Hermann E, Kageyama M, Mergen P, Rinaldo C, Buschbom J (2023) Joint statement by CETAF, SPNHC and BHL on DATA within scientific publications: clarification of [non]copyrightability. Research Ideas and Outcomes 9: e115466. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.9.e115466&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.9.e115466&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Caucheteur D, Pendlington ZM, Roncaglia P, Gobeill J, Mottin L, Matentzoglu N, Agosti D, Osumi-Sutherland D, Parkinson H, Ruch P 2000., COVoc and COVTriage: novel resources to support literature triage, Bioinformatics, 39 (1): btac800, doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btac800&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btac800&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Cornwell P (2023) Progress with Repository-based Annotation Infrastructure for Biodiversity Applications. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e112707. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.112707&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.112707&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Giora J, Agosti D, Ruschel T, Castro JB (2023) Engaging the Scientific Community, Authors and Publishers in FAIR Taxonomic Data Liberation: An Overview of Training Resources at Plazi. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e110695. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.110695&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.110695&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Pasche E, Gobeill J, Agosti D, Penev L, Groom Q, Georgiev T, Gaillac E, Flament A, Caucheteur D, Michel P-A, Ruch P (2023) From SIBiLS to Biodiversity PMC: Foundations for the One Health Library. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e111660. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.111660&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.111660&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Pasche E, Agosti D, Penev L, Groom Q, Flament A, Gobeill J, Ruch P (2023) Towards &#34;Biodiversity PMC&#34;. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e111647. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.111647&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.111647&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Penev L, Koureas D, Groom Q, Lanfear J, Agosti D, Casino A, Miller J, Cochrane G, Pauperio J, Bánki O, Addink W, Kõljalg U, Ruch P, Hristova K, Barov B, Madeira Scauri M, Montinaro S, Vaira L, Fiore N, Bamford E, Arvanitidis C (2023) The Biodiversity Knowledge Hub (BKH): A Crosspoint and Knowledge Broker for FAIR and Linked Biodiversity Data. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e111482. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.111482&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.111482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Sautter G, Agosti D (2023) Bidirectional Linking: Benefits, challenges, pitfalls, and solutions. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e112344. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.112344&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.112344&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Simoes F, Agosti D, Alvares DJ, Castro JB, Giora J, da Rosa Gonçalves V, Ruschel TP, Sokolowicz C, Wingert JM (2023) Post-Publication Linking. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e110692. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.110692&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.110692&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Baskauf SJ, Girón Duque JC, Nielsen M, Cobb NS, Singer R, Seltmann KC, Kachian Z, Pérez M, Agosti D, Klompen AML (2023) Implementation Experience Report for Controlled Vocabularies Used with the Audubon Core Terms subjectPart and subjectOrientation. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 7: e94188. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.7.94188&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.7.94188&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2022&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Benichou L, Addink W, Arvanitidis C, Catapano T, Cochrane G, Dillen M, Döring M, Georgiev T, Gérard I, Groom Q, Kishor P, Kroh A, Kvaček J, Mergen P, Mietchen D, Pauperio J, Sautter G, Penev L (2022) Recommendations for use of annotations and persistent identifiers in taxonomy and biodiversity publishing. Research Ideas and Outcomes 8: e97374. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.8.e97374&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.8.e97374&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Meeus S, Addink W, Agosti D, Arvanitidis C, Balech B, Dillen M, Dimitrova M, González-Aranda JM, Holetschek J, Islam S, Jeppesen TS, Mietchen D, Nicolson N, Penev L, Robertson T, Ruch P, Trekels M, Groom Q (2022) Recommendations for interoperability among infrastructures. Research Ideas and Outcomes 8: e96180. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.8.e96180&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.8.e96180&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W 2022. FAIR Works – Eckpunkte eines Urheberrechts für die digitale Welt. Sic!, 2022, 405–424. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7184216&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.7184216&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W 2022. FAIR Works - Cornerstones for a Copyright in the Digital World. Sic!, 2022, 405–424. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7181457&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.7181457&lt;/a&gt; (english translation of doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7184216&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.7184216&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Benichou L, Buschbom J, Campbell M, Hermann E, Kvacek J, Mergen P, Mitchell L, Rinaldo C, Agosti D (2022) Joint statement on best practices for the citation of authorities of scientific names in taxonomy by CETAF, SPNHC and BHL. Research Ideas and Outcomes 8: e94338. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.8.e94338&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.8.e94338&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Ioannidis-Pantopikos A (2022) Taxonomic Treatments as Open FAIR Digital Objects. Research Ideas and Outcomes 8: e93709. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.8.e93709&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.8.e93709&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Gmür R, Agosti D, Sautter G (2022) Synospecies, a Linked Data Application to Explore Taxonomic Names. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 6: e93707. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.6.93707&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.6.93707&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Benichou L, Penev L, Hyam R (2022) A Possible Workflow from New and Legacy Publications to keep the World Flora Online up to date with New Species and Augmenting Taxonomic Treatments. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 6: e91241. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.6.91241&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.6.91241&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Ruch P, Benito Gonzalez Lopez J, Penev L (2022) Enabling Published Taxonomic Data to be used to Address the Biodiversity Crisis: Biodiversity Literature Repository and TreatmentBank. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 6: e91167. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.6.91167&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.6.91167&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Fawcett S, Agosti D, Cole SR, Wright CF 2022. Digital accessible knowledge: Mobilizing legacy data and the future of taxonomic publishing. Bulletin of the Society of Systematic Biologists 1(1): 1-12. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.18061/bssb.v1i1.8296&#34;&gt;10.18061/bssb.v1i1.8296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Penev L, Koureas D, Groom Q, Lanfear J, Agosti D, Casino A, Miller J, Arvanitidis C, Cochrane G, Hobern D, Banki O, Addink W, Kõljalg U, Copas K, Mergen P, Güntsch A, Benichou L, Benito Gonzalez Lopez J, Ruch P, Martin CS, Barov B, Hristova K (2022) Biodiversity Community Integrated Knowledge Library (BiCIKL). Research Ideas and Outcomes 8: e81136. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.8.e81136&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.8.e81136&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2021&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Guidoti M, Simões FL, Ruschel TP, DA Rosa Gonçalves V, Sokolowicz C, Agosti D. 2021. Using taxonomic treatments to assess an author&#39;s career: the impactful Jocélia Grazia. Zootaxa 4958 (1): 12-33 doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.11646/zootaxa.4958.1.4&#34;&gt;10.11646/zootaxa.4958.1.4&lt;/a&gt;. BLR: &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/4692727&#34;&gt;Zenodo Record 4692727&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Bénichou, L., Guidoti, M., Gérard, I., Agosti, D., Robillard, T., &amp;amp; Cianferoni, F. (2021). European Journal of Taxonomy: a deeper look into a decade of data. European Journal of Taxonomy, 782(1), 173-196. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5852/ejt.2021.782.1597&#34;&gt;10.5852/ejt.2021.782.1597&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Abrahamse T, Andrade-Correa MG, Arida C, Galsim R, Häuser C, Price M, Sommerwerk N 2021. The Global Taxonomy Initiative in Support of the Post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework. CBD Technical Series No. 96. Secretariat of the Convention on Biological Diversity, Montreal, 103 pages. (Plazi: participant) doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5728812&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.5728812&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Cornwell P, Bénichou L, Gonzalez J, Herren M, Ruch P 2021. Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data. iPRES 2021 - 17th International Conference on Digital Preservation, October 19-22, 2021, Beijing, China. &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1M2Rui8KMhpw0xIGF1UcQJJJoH3scYAeo/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;manuscript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Waterhouse RM, Adam-Blondon AF, Agosti D et al. Recommendations for connecting molecular sequence and biodiversity research infrastructures through ELIXIR [version 1; peer review: awaiting peer review]. F1000Research 2021, 10(ELIXIR):1238. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.73825.1&#34;&gt;10.12688/f1000research.73825.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Souza JLP, Fernandes IO, Agosti D, Johnson NF, Baccaro FB 2021. Assessing the efficacy of higher-taxon approach for ant species surveys to improve biodiversity inventories. Animal Conservation 24 (early view) doi: 10.1111/acv.12758. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/acv.12758&#34;&gt;10.1111/acv.12758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Miller JA, Agosti D, Guidoti M, Rivera Quiroz FA. 2021. Linking and the Role of the Material Citation. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75543. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75543&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75543&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Egloff W. 2021. Herausfinden, was wir schon wissen. Gfbs Newsletter, 39, 24–31. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5168465&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.5168465&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Guidoti M, Sokolowicz C, Simoes F, Gonçalves V, Ruschel T, Alvares DJ, Agosti D 2021. TreatmentBank: Plazi&amp;rsquo;s strategies and its implementation to most efficiently liberate data from scholarly publications. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75690. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75690&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75690&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Van der Jeucht L, Groom Q, Agosti D, Phelps K, Reeder DM, Simmons NB 2021. Using iNaturalist to monitor adherence to best practices in bat handling. Biodiversity Data Journal 9: e68052. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/BDJ.9.e68052&#34;&gt;10.3897/BDJ.9.e68052&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Upham NS, Poelen JH, Paul D, Groom QJ, Simmons NB, Vanhove MPM, Bertolino S, Reeder DM, Bastos-Silveira C, Sen A, Sterner B, Franz NM, Guidoti M, Penev L, Agosti D 2021. Liberating host–virus knowledge from biological dark data. The Lancet Planetary Health. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/S2542-5196(21)00196-0&#34;&gt;10.1016/S2542-5196(21)00196-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Alvares DJ, Guidoti M, Simoes F, Sokolowicz C, Agosti D 2021. The BHL-Plazi Partnership: Getting data from the 1800s directly into 21st century, reused digital accessible knowledge. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75604. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75604&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75604&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Gmür R, Agosti D 2021. Synospecies, an application to reflect changes in taxonomic names based on a triple store based on taxonomic data liberated from publication. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75641. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75641&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75641&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D 2021. (Re)Discovering Known Biodiversity: Introduction. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75491. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75491&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75491&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Simoes F, Agosti D, Guidoti M 2021. Delivering Fit-for-Use Data: Quality control. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75432. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75432&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75432&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Ioannidis-Pantopikos A, Agosti D 2021. Biodiversity Literature Repository: Building the customized FAIR repository by using custom metadata. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e75147. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.75147&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.75147&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Sokolowicz C, Guidoti M, Agosti D 2021. Discovering Known Biodiversity: Digital accessible knowledge — Getting the community involved. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e74369. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.74369&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.74369&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Meeus S, Addink W, Agosti D, Arvanitidis C, Dimitrova M, González-Aranda JM, Holetschek J, Islam S, Jeppesen TS, Mietchen D, Robertson T, Sanchez Cano FM, Trekels M, Groom Q (2021) Hacking Infrastructures Together: Towards better interoperability of infrastructures. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e74325. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.74325&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.74325&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Penev L, Koureas D, Groom Q, Lanfear J, Agosti D, Casino A, Miller J, Arvanitidis C, Cochrane G, Barov B, Hobern D, Banki O, Addink W, Köljalg U, Ruch P, Copas K, Mergen P, Güntsch A, Benichou L, Gonzalez Lopez JB 2021. Towards Interlinked FAIR Biodiversity Knowledge: The BiCIKL perspective. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 5: e74233. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.5.74233&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.5.74233&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2020&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Mottin L, Ruch P, Mottaz A, Naderi N, Caucheteur D, Agosti D, Matentzoglu N, Michel PA, Pendlington Z, Roncaglia P 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ols/ontologies/covoc&#34;&gt;CoVoc Coronavirus Vocabulary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Rivera-Quiroz A, Petchaard B, Miller JA 2020. Mining data from legacy taxonomic literature and application for sampling spiders of the Teutamus group (Araneae; Liocranidae) in Southeast Asia. Scientific Reports 10: 15787. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-72549-8&#34;&gt;10.1038/s41598-020-72549-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Dimitrova M, Poelen J, Zhelezov G, Georgiev T, Agosti D, Penev L 2020. Semantic publishing enables text mining of biotic interactions. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 4: e95036. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.4.59036&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.4.59036&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Guidoti M, Sautter G 2020. Liberating the Richness of Facts implicit in taxonomic Publication: The Plazi Workflow . Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 4: e59179. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.4.59179&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.4.59179&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Guidoti M, Catapano T, Ioannidis-Pantopikos A, Sautter G 2020. The Standards behind the Scenes: Explaining data from the Plazi workflow. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 4: e59178. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.4.59178&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.4.59178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Upham NS, Agosti D, Poelen J, Penev L, Paul D, Reeder DM, Simmons NB, Csorba G, Groom Q, Dimitrova M, Miller JT 2020. Liberating Biodiversity Data From COVID-19 Lockdown: Toward a knowledge hub for mammal host-virus information. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 4: e59199. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.4.59199&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.4.59199&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2019&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Swiss Academies of Arts and Sciences (2019) Open Science in Switzerland: Opportunities and Challenges. Swiss Academies Factsheets 14 (2). &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.swiss-academies.ch/site/assets/files/6154/factsheet_open_science.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF &lt;img src=&#34;https://plazi.org/img/pdf.svg&#34; width=&#34;30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Chester C, Agosti D, Sautter G, Catapano T, Martens K, Gérard I, Bénicou L 2019. EJT editorial standard for the semantic enhancement of specimen data in taxonomy literature. European Journal of Taxonomy 586: 1-22. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5852/ejt.2019.586&#34;&gt;10.5852/ejt.2019.586&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Saarenma H, Agosti D, Dillen M, Egloff W, Gagnier P-Y, Groom Q, Hardisty A, Raes N. 2019. Open access implementation guidelines for DiSSCo. Deliverable D6.5. ICEDIG, Helsinki. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3465285&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.3465285&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Nielsen LH, Dillen M, Groom Q. 2019. Digitisation infrastructure design for Zenodo. Deliverable D6.3. ICEDIG, Helsinki. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3346782&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.3346782&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Plazi. 2019. Policy Component of ICEDIG Project Website. Deliberable D7.1. ICEDIG, Helsinki. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3484047&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.3484047&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Bénichou L, Gerard I, Chester C, Agosti D. 2019. The European Journal of Taxonomy: Enhancing taxonomic publications for dynamic data exchange and navigation. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 3: e37199. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.3.37199&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.3.37199&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Catapano T, Sautter G, Kishor P, Nielsen L, Ioannidis-Pantopikos A, Bigarella C, Georgiev T, Penev L, Egloff W. 2019. Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR), a repository for FAIR data and publications. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 3: e37197. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.3.37197&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.3.37197&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Nieva de la Hidalga A, Cazenave N, Agosti D, Wu Z, Dillen M, Nielsen L. 2019. Use of European Open Science Cloud and National e-Infrastructures for the Long-Term Storage of Digitised Assets from Natural History Collections. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 3: e37164. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.3897/biss.3.37164&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.3.37164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Dillen M, Groom Q, Agosti D, Nielsen L. 2019. Zenodo, an Archive and Publishing Repository: A tale of two herbarium specimen pilot projects. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 3: e37080. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.3897/biss.3.37080&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.3.37080&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Miller JA, Braumuller Y, Kishor P, Shorthouse DP, Dimitrova M, Sautter G, Agosti A. 2019. Mobilizing Data from Taxonomic Literature for an Iconic Species (Dinosauria, Theropoda, Tyrannosaurus rex). Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 3: e37078. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.3.37078&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.3.37078&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Catapano T, Sautter G, Egloff W. 2019. The Plazi Workflow: The PDF prison break for biodiversity data. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 3: e37046. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.3.37046&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.3.37046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Hardisty AR, Michener WK, Agosti D,Alonso García, E, Bastine L, Belbin L, Bowserg A, Buttigieg PL, Canhos DAL, Egloff W, De Giovanni R, Figueira R, Groomk Q, Guralnick, RP, Hobern D, Hugo W,Koureas D, Ji L, Kissling WD 2018. The Bari Manifesto: An interoperability framework for essential biodiversity variables. Ecological Informatics 49: 22-31. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoinf.2018.11.003&#34;&gt;10.1016/j.ecoinf.2018.11.003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2018&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D 2018. Bezahlschranken für Schnappschüsse? Neue Zürcher Zeitung, Gastkommentar, 29.11.2018. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nzz.ch/meinung/bezahlschranken-fuer-fotos-ld.1433968&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Penev L, Agosti D, Georgiev T, Senderov V, Sautter G, Catapano T, Stoev P 2018. The Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management (eco-)System: Tools and services for extraction, mobilization, handling and re-use of data from the published literature. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 2: e25748. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/biss.2.25748&#34;&gt;10.3897/biss.2.25748&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Hardisty AR, Michener WK, Agosti D, .. Egloff W, &amp;hellip; (26 authors) 2018. The Bari Manifesto: An interoperability framework for essential biodiversity variables. Ecological Informatics 49: 23-31. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoinf.2018.11.003&#34;&gt;10.1016/j.ecoinf.2018.11.003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W 2018. Copyright stories: Sketches on the political economy of copyright. Advocomplex, Bern, Switzerland. English translation of  Geschichten vom Urheberrecht oder: Skizzen zur politischen Ökonomie des Copyright&amp;quot; by Stämpfli Verlag AG Bern ISBN 978-3-033-06835-3. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1412365&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.1412365&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Kissling WD, Walls R, &amp;hellip; Agosti D, .. Egloff W, &amp;hellip; (29 authors) 2018. Towards global data products of Essential Biodiversity Variables on species traits. Nature Ecology and Evolution 2018DA. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41559-018-0667-3&#34;&gt;10.1038/s41559-018-0667-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Senderov V, Simov K, Franz N, Stoev P, Catapano T, Agosti D, Sautter G, Morris RA, Penev L 2018. OpenBiodiv-O: ontology of the OpenBiodiv knowledge management system. Journal of Biomedical Semantics 9: 5. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s13326-017-0174-5&#34;&gt;10.1186/s13326-017-0174-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Esterman B, Agosti D, Cretton F, Cochard J-L, Gmür R, Hellstern M, Hladky D, Mabbett A, Mastrandrea E, Plitzker M, Prongué N, Stinson A, Weinberg B 2018. eCH-0205 Linked Open Data. eCH E-Government Standards publication eCH-0205. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.2641710&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.2641710&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Côtez E, Mabille A, Chester C, Rocklin M, Deroin T, Desutter-Grandcolas L, Lesur J Merle D, Robillard R, Bénichou 2018. 1802-2018: a 220-year history of the Muséum periodicals. Adansonia 40(1): 1-42. (description of Plazi involvement on p.28 onwards) &lt;a href=&#34;https://sciencepress.mnhn.fr/sites/default/files/articles/hd/adan-40-1-2018-cotez_et_al-pdf-a.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF &lt;img src=&#34;https://plazi.org/img/pdf.svg&#34; width=&#34;30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5252/adansonia2018v40a1&#34;&gt;10.5252/adansonia2018v40a1 &lt;img src=&#34;https://plazi.org/img/closed-access.svg&#34; width=&#34;30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2017&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Bingham H, Doudin M, Weatherdon LV, Despot-Belmonte K, Wetzel FT, Groom Q, Lewis E, Appeltrans W, Güntsch A, Mergen P, Agosti D, Penev L, Hoffmann A, Saarenmaa H, Geller G, Kim K Kim H, Archambeau AS, Häuser C, Schmeller DS, Ilse Geijzendorffer, Camacho AG, Guerra C, Robertson T, Runnel V, Valland N, Martin CS 2017. The Biodiversity Informatics Landscape: Elements, Connections and Opportunities. Research Ideas and Outcome 3: e14059. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.3.e14059&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.3.e14059&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Despot-Belmonte K, Doudin M, Groom Q, Wetzel FT, Agosti D, Jacobsen K, Smirnova L, Weatherdon LV, Robertson T, Penev L, Regan E, Hoffmann A, MacSharry Y, Martin CS 2017. EU BON&amp;rsquo;s contributions towards meeting Aichi Biodiversity Target 19. Research Ideas and Outcome 3: e14013. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.3.e14013&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.3.e14013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Senderov V, Georgiev TA, Agosti D, Catapano T, Sautter G, Ó Tuama É, Franz N, Simov K, Stoev P, Penev L 2017. OpenBiodiv Computer Demo: an Implementation of a Semantic System Running on top of the Biodiversity Knowledge Graph. Proceedings of TDWG 1: e20193. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/tdwgproceedings.1.20193&#34;&gt;10.3897/tdwgproceedings.1.20193&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Kissling D (and 35 coauthors) 2017. Building essential biodiversity variables (EBVs) of species distribution and abundance at a global scale. Biological Reviews. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1111/brv.12359&#34;&gt;10.1111/brv.12359&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Despot-Belmonte K, Doudin M, Groom Q, Wetzel FT, Agosti D, Jacobsen K, Smirnova L, Weatherdon LV, Robertson T, Penev L, Regan E, Hoffmann A, MacSharry B, Shennan-Farpon Y, Martin CS 2017. EU BON’s contributions towards meeting Aichi Biodiversity Target 19. Research Ideas and Outcomes 3: e14013. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.3.e14013&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.3.e14013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Despot-Belmonte K, Bingham Heather, Doudin M, Weatherdon L, Regan E, Lewis E, Scrimgeour R, Bubb Ph, Pan X, Martin C, Wetzel F, Hoffmann A, Häuser Ch, Penner J, Vohland K, Geijzendorffer I, Schmeller D, Agosti D, Arvanitidis Ch, Thalmann A, Underwood E, Tucker G, Grace M, Rose D, Penev L, Jacobsen K 2017. Deliverable 7.4 (D7.4). Strategies and business plan for regional and global biodiversity information infrastructures. M52. EU BON, Museum für Naturkunde - Leibniz Institute for Research on Evolution and Biodiversity, Berlin Germany.  doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.569819&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.569819&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2016&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Senderov V, Georgiev TA, Agosti D, Catapano T, Sautter G, Ó Tuama É, Franz N, Simov K, Stoev P, Penev L 2016. The Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management System: A Semantic Suite Running on top of the Biodiversity Knowledge Graph. TDWG 2016 conference presentation abstract. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.841648&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.841648&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Faulwetter S, Pafilis E, Fanini L, Bailly N, Agosti D, Arvantidis C, Boicenco L, Catapano T, Claus S, Dekeyzer S, Georgiev T, Legaki A, Mavraki D, Oulas A, Papastefanou G, Penev L, Sautter G, Schigel, Senderov V, Teaca A, Tsompanou M 2016. EMODnet Workshop on mechanisms and guidelines to mobilise historical data into biogeographic databases. Research Ideas and Outcomes 2: e9774. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/rio.2.e9774&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.2.e9774&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Koureas D, Hardisty A, Vos R, Agosti D, Arvanitidis C, Bogatencov P, Buttigieg P, de Jong Y, Horvath F, Gkoutos G, Groom Q, Kliment T, Kõljalg U, Manakos I, Marcer A, Marhold K, Morse D, Mergen P, Penev L, Pettersson L, Svenning J, van de Putte A, Smith V 2016. Unifying European Biodiversity Informatics (BioUnify). Research Ideas and Outcomes 2: e7787. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.3897/rio.2.e7787&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.2.e7787&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W, Agosti D, Patterson D, Hoffmann A, Mietchen D, Kishor P, Penev L 2016. Data Policy Recommendations for Biodiversity Data. EU BON Project Report. Research Ideas and Outcomes 2: e8458. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/rio.2.e8458&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.2.e8458&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Alonso LA, Agosti D 2016. Ants. In: Larsen TH (ed.) 2016. Core Standardized Methods for Rapid Biological Field Assessment. Conservation International, Arlington, VA. pp. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.50824&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.50824&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Smirnova L, Mergen P, Groom QJ, De Wever, A, Penev L, Stoev P, Pe’er I, Runnel V, Camacho AC, Vincent T, Agosti D, Arvanitidis C, García FJB, Saarenmaa H 2016. Data sharing tools adopted by the European Biodiversity Observation Network Project. Research Ideas and Outcomes 2: 2: e9390 doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/rio.2.e9390&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.2.e9390&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;RDA-CODATA Legal Interoperability Interest Group. 2016. Legal Interoperability of Research Data: Principles and Implementation Guidelines. Zenodo. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.162241&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.162241&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D. (2016) Shuttleworth Fellowship Application 2016. Research Ideas and Outcomes 2: e11014. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.2.e11014&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.2.e11014&lt;/a&gt; .  &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/185657429&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Sautter G, Catapano T, Kishor P, Penev L 2016. Deliverable 3.3 (D3.3): Updated release and report on publication data-mining software. EU BON, Museum für Naturkunde - Leibniz Institute for Research on Evolution and Biodiversity, Berlin Germany.  doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.187446&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.187446&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Kohlbecker A, Güntsch A, Müller A, von Raab-Straube E, Wetzel F, Ring C, Kempa M, Stoev P, De Wever A, Sautter G, Agosti D 2016. Deliverable 1.4 (D1.4): Summary report of operational EU BON services and data provision for the European taxonomic backbone. EU BON, Museum für Naturkunde - Leibniz Institute for Research on Evolution and Biodiversity, Berlin Germany. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.182122&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.182122&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Ronquist F, Skyttner M, Kõljalg U, Röppert D, Penev L, Stoev P, Peer I, Stein M, Calabuig I, Agosti D, Kempa M 2016. Deliverable 1.3 (D1.3): Systems for mobilizing and managing collection-based data (specimen + DNA-data) fully integrated. EU BON, Museum für Naturkunde - Leibniz Institute for Research on Evolution and Biodiversity, Berlin Germany. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.189960&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.189960&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W, Agosti D, Kishor P, Patterson D, Miller JA 2016. Copyright and the Use of Images as Biodiversity Data. bioRxiv doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1101/087015&#34;&gt;10.1101/087015&lt;/a&gt;  (preprint submitted Nov 12; article submitted to PLoS Biology Nov 12; resubmitted Dec 3 to Rio Journal; accepted article doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/rio.3.e12502&#34;&gt;10.3897/rio.3.e12502&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2015&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Dikow T, Agosti D. 2015. Utilizing online resources for taxonomy: a cybercatalog of Afrotropical apiocerid flies (Insecta: Diptera: Apioceridae). Biodiversity Data Journal 3: e5707 (06 Oct 2015. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/BDJ.3.e5707&#34;&gt;10.3897/BDJ.3.e5707&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W, Agosti D, Patterson D, Penev L 2015. EU BON Policy Brief on Open Data. Website, doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.188391&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.188391&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Guralnick RP, Cellinese N, Deck J, Pyle RL, Kunze J, Penev L, Walls R, Hagedorn G, Agosti D, Wieczorek J, Catapano T, Page R. 2015 Community next steps for making globally unique identifiers work for biocollections data. ZooKeys 494: 133-154 doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://zookeys.pensoft.net/articles.php?id=5042&#34;&gt;10.3897/zookeys.494.9352&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Miller JA, Georgiev T, Stoev P, Sautter G, Penev L 2015. Corrected data re-harvested: curating literature in the era of networked biodiversity informatics. Biodiversity Data Journal 3: e4552. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/BDJ.3.e4552&#34;&gt;10.3897/BDJ.3.e4552&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Miller JA, Agosti D, Penev L, Sautter G, Georgiev T, Catapano T, Patterson D, King D, Pereira S, Vos RA, Sierra S 2015. Integrating and visualizing primary data from prospective and legacy taxonomic literature. Biodiversity Data Journal 3: e5063 (12 May 2015) doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/BDJ.3.e5063&#34;&gt;10.3897/BDJ.3.e5063&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2014&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W 2014. Access to scientific and technical information - between social needs and private interests. In: Gartska,H., und Coy,W. (Hg.), Wovon –für wen -wozu. Systemdenken wider die Diktatur der Daten.Helmholtz-Zentrum für Kulturtechnik und Humboldt-Universität Berlin 2014, S. 349 –373. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10597&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.10597&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D 2014. Some thoughts after the Cusco meeting. Hamuli 5 (2): 4-5. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.11671&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.11671&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W, Patterson D, Agosti D, Hagedorn G 2014. Open exchange of scientific knowledge and European copyright: The case of biodiversity information. ZooKeys 414, 109-135. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pensoft.net/journals/zookeys/issue/414/&#34;&gt;10.3897/zookeys.414.7717&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W, 2014. Der Zugang zu Fachinformationen – zwischen gesellschaftlicher Notwendigkeit und privatem Verwertungsinteresse In: Hansjürgen Garstka, Wolfgang Coy (Hg.), Wovon - für wen - wozu. Systemdenken wider die Diktatur der Daten, Helmholtz-Zentrum für Kulturtechnik, Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, S. 349-373, ISBN 978-3-86004-298-4. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/10378&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.10378&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Interview. Donat Agosti on big data, copyright and attribution in taxonomy. BIOME April 9, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biomedcentral.com/biome/donat-agosti-on-big-data-copyright-and-attribution-in-taxonomy/&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt; (This is a followup of the Patterson et al. paper. Though it is credited to Donat (because of his role as editor of BMC research notes?), it has a major input from Paddy and Willi.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Patterson DJ, Egloff W, Agosti D, Eades D, Franz N, Hagedorn G, Rees J, Remsen DP 2014. Scientific names of organisms: attribution, rights, and licensing . BMC Research Notes 2014, 7:79 doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biomedcentral.com/1756-0500/7/79&#34;&gt;10.1186/1756-0500-7-79&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biomedcentral.com/bmcresnotes/mostviewed/alltime?page=2&amp;amp;itemsPerPage=25&amp;amp;citation=true&amp;amp;summary=false&#34;&gt;most viewed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Vos R and 37 co-authors 2014. Enriched biodiversity data as a resource and service. Biodiversity Data Journal 2, e1125 doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3897/bdj.2.e1125&#34;&gt;10.3897/bdj.2.e1125&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Sautter G, Böhm K 2014. Improved bibliographic reference parsing based on repeated patterns. International Journal on Digital Libraries 14.1-2: 59-80. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/181625&#34;&gt;10.1007/s00799-014-0110-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;pro-iBiosphere 2014. Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management System (OBKMS). Final OBKMS brochure. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.191785&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.191785&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Saarenmaa H, Camacho A G, Ó Tuama É, Agosti D, Bailly N, Calderisi M, Drucker D, Güntsch A, Jacobsen K, Kempa M, Kõljalg U, Mergen P, Peer I, Penev L, Valland N, de Wever A 2014. Deliverable 2.1 (D2.1): Architectural design, review and guidelines for using standards. M14. EU BON FP7-308454. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.292208&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.292208&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Egloff W, Agosti D, Morris RA, Groom Q, Güntsch A, Hovenkamp P, Mantel J-W, Sierra S, Mietchen D, Paton A, Patterson D, Stoev P, Macklin J 2014. D2.4.2 Draft policy on Open Access for data and information. Pro-iBiosphere. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10879&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.10879&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2013&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Karol Marhold, Tod Stuessy, Mariam Agababian, Donat Agosti, Mac H. Alford, Ana Crespo, Jorge V. Crisci, Laurence J. Dorr, Zuzana Ferencová, David Frodin, Dmitry V. Geltman, Norbert Kilian, H. Peter Linder, Lucia G. Lohmann, Christoph Oberprieler, Lyubomir Penev, Gideon F. Smith, Wayt Thomas, Melissa Tulig, Nicholas Turland, Xian-Chun Zhang (2013) The Future of Botanical Monography: Report from an international workshop, 12–16 March 2012, Smolenice, Slovak Republic. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/tax.621003&#34;&gt;10.1002/tax.621003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Agosti D, Catapano T, Cora J, Güntsch A, Groom Q, Hagedorn G, Kirkup D, Macklin J, Mietchen Da, Miller J, Morris R, Patton A, Penev L, Patterson D, Sierra S 2013. D3.2.2 Report on the state and quality of biosystematics documents and survey reports. pro-IBiosphere. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6751676&#34;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Groom Q, Agosti D, Güntsch A, Hovenkamp P, Kralt E, Mietchen D, Paton A, Sierra S 2013. D2.3 The Use of e-Tools among Producers of Taxonomic Knowledge (Proof of concept report on the use of e-tools) Deliverable. pro-iBiosphere. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6752008&#34;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Hardisty A, Roberts D. and The Biodiversity Informatics Community, 2013. A decadal view of biodiversity informatics: challenges and priorities. BMC Ecology 2013, 13:16 doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6785/13/16&#34;&gt;10.1186/1472-6785-13-16&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Biodiversity informatics plays a central enabling role in the research community&amp;rsquo;s efforts to address scientific conservation and sustainability issues. Great strides have been made in the past decade establishing a framework for sharing data, where taxonomy and systematics has been perceived as the most prominent discipline involved. To some extent this is inevitable, given the use of species names as the pivot around which information is organised. To address the urgent questions around conservation, land-use, environmental change, sustainability, food security and ecosystem services that are facing Governments worldwide, we need to understand how the ecosystem works. So, we need a systems approach to understanding biodiversity that moves significantly beyond taxonomy and species observations. Such an approach needs to look at the whole system to address species interactions, both with their environment and with other species. It is clear that some barriers to progress are sociological, basically persuading people to use the technological solutions that are already available. This is best addressed by developing more effective systems that deliver immediate benefit to the user, hiding the majority of the technology behind simple user interfaces. An infrastructure should be a space in which activities take place and, as such, should be effectively invisible. This community consultation paper positions the role of biodiversity informatics, for the next decade, presenting the actions needed to link the various biodiversity infrastructures invisibly and to facilitate understanding that can support both business and policy-makers. The community considers the goal in biodiversity informatics to be full integration of the biodiversity research community, including citizens’ science, through a commonly-shared, sustainable e-infrastructure across all sub-disciplines that reliably serves science and society alike.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Smith V, Georgiev T, Stoev P, Biserkov J, Miller J, Livermore L, Baker E, Mietchen D, Couvreur T L P , Mueller G, Dikow T, Helgen K M, Frank J, Agosti D, Roberts D, Penev L. 2013. Beyond dead trees: integrating the scientific process in the Biodiversity Data Journal. Biodiversity Data Journal. 09/2013; 1. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;http://biodiversitydatajournal.com/articles.php?id=995&#34;&gt;10.3897/BDJ.1.e995&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;King D, Sautter G, Morse D, Penev L, Biserkov J, Georgiev T, Roberts D, Smith V 2013. Bibliography of live: a freely accessible bibliography of every paper ever published. Poster, TDWG 2013, Florence, Italy, October 28 - November 1, 2013. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.181364&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.181364&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Tschöppe O, Macklin JA, Morris RA, Suhrbier L, Berendsohn WG 2013. Annotating biodiversity data via the Internet. Taxon, 62(2): 1248-1258. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.12705/626.4&#34;&gt;10.12705/626.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Sautter G, Böhm K 2013. High-throughput crowdsourcing mechanisms for complex tasks. Social Network Analysis and Mining, 3(4): 873-888. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13278-013-0114-z&#34;&gt;10.1007/s13278-013-0114-z&lt;/a&gt;; doi (preprint): &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.188564&#34;&gt;10.5281/zenodo.188564&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Morris RA, Barve V, Carausu M, Chavan V, Cuadra J, Freeland C, Hagedorn G, Leary P, Mozzherin D, Olson A, Riccardi G, Teage I, Whitebread G 2013. Discovery and publishing of primary biodiversity data associated with multimedia resources: The Audubon Core strategies and approaches. Biodiversity Informatics 8(2): 185-197. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17161/bi.v8i2.4117&#34;&gt;10.17161/bi.v8i2.4117&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Sautter G, various 2013. D7.3 - Literature search. ViBRANT project deliverable d7.3, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.scratchpads.eu/w/D73report&#34;&gt;http://wiki.scratchpads.eu/w/D73report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Hobern et al., 2013. Global Biodiversity Informatics Outlook: Delivering Biodiversity Knowledge in the Information Age, GBIF. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gbif.org/resources/2251&#34;&gt;PDF &lt;img src=&#34;https://plazi.org/img/pdf.svg&#34; width=&#34;30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Abstract: Much progress has been made in the past ten years to fulfil the potential of biodiversity informatics. However, it is dwarfed by the scale of what is still required. The Global Biodiversity Informatics Outlook (GBIO) offers a framework for reaching a much deeper understanding of the world’s biodiversity, and through that understanding the means to conserve it better and to use it more sustainably. The GBIO identifies four major focal areas, each with a number of core components, to help coordinate efforts and funding. The co-authors, from a wide range of disciplines, agree these are the essential elements of a global strategy to harness biodiversity data for the common good.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;2012&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Penev L, Catapano T, Agosti D, Georgiev T, Sautter, G, Stoev P (2012). Implementation of TaxPub, an NLM DTD extension for domain-specific markup in taxonomy, from the experience of a biodiversity publisher. In: Journal Article Tag Suite Conference (JATS-Con) Proceedings 2012 [Internet]. Bethesda (MD): National Center for Biotechnology Information (US). doi: [10.5281/zenodo.804247](https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.804247); [Article](http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK100351/)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Miller J, Dikow T, Agosti D, Sautter G, Catapano T, Penev L, Zhang Z-Q, Pentcheff D, Pyle R, Blum S, Parr C, Freeland C, Garnett T, Ford LS, Muller B, Smith L, Strader G, Georgiev T &amp;amp; Bénichou L 2012. From taxonomic literature to cybertaxonomic content. BMC Biology, 10: 87. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/1741-7007-10-87&#34;&gt;10.1186/1741-7007-10-87&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Seltman KC, &amp;hellip; Agosti D., Johnson N and 35 co-authors. 2012. A hymenopterist&amp;rsquo;s guide to the Hymenoptera Anatomy Ontology: utility, clarification, and future directions. Journal of Hymenoptera Research 27: 67-88. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3897/jhr.27.2961&#34;&gt;10.3897/jhr.27.2961&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
