<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>All our publications are published under open licenses. If you are unable to locate a copy, please contact us and we will be happy to send it to you.
 2021 (17 publications) 2020 (6) 2019 (11) 2018 (8) 2017 (7) 2016 (12) 2015 (5) 2014 (11) 2013 (8) 2012 (4) 2011 (9) 2010 and earlier (19)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2011</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2011/</guid>
      <description>Catapano T, Hobern D, Lapp H, Morris RA, Morrison N, Noy N, Schildhauer M, Thau D 2011. Recommendations for the Use of Knowledge Organisation Systems by GBIF. Report
  Chavan V, Penev L 2011. The data paper: a mechanism to incentivize data publishing in biodiversity science. BMC Bioinformatics, 12 (Suppl 15): S2. doi: 10.1186/1471-2105-12-S15-S2 highly accessed
  Hagedorn G, Mietchen D, Morris RA, Agosti D, Penev L, Berendsohn W, Hobern D 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2012</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2012/</guid>
      <description>Penev L, Catapano T, Agosti D, et al. Implementation of TaxPub, an NLM DTD extension for domain-specific markup in taxonomy, from the experience of a biodiversity publisher. In: Journal Article Tag Suite Conference (JATS-Con) Proceedings 2012 [Internet]. Bethesda (MD): National Center for Biotechnology Information (US); 2012. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.804247; Article
  Miller J, Dikow T, Agosti D, Sautter G, Catapano T, Penev L, Zhang Z-Q, Pentcheff D, Pyle R, Blum S, Parr C, Freeland C, Garnett T, Ford LS, Muller B, Smith L, Strader G, Georgiev T &amp;amp; Bénichou L 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2013</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2013/</guid>
      <description>Hardisty A, Roberts D. and The Biodiversity Informatics Community, 2013. A decadal view of biodiversity informatics: challenges and priorities. BMC Ecology 2013, 13:16 doi: 10.1186/1472-6785-13-16. Abstract: Biodiversity informatics plays a central enabling role in the research community&amp;rsquo;s efforts to address scientific conservation and sustainability issues. Great strides have been made in the past decade establishing a framework for sharing data, where taxonomy and systematics has been perceived as the most prominent discipline involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2014</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2014/</guid>
      <description>Egloff W 2014. Access to scientific and technical information - between social needs and private interests. In: Gartska,H., und Coy,W. (Hg.), Wovon –für wen -wozu. Systemdenken wider die Diktatur der Daten.Helmholtz-Zentrum für Kulturtechnik und Humboldt-Universität Berlin 2014, S. 349 –373. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.10597
  Agosti D 2014. Some thoughts after the Cusco meeting. Hamuli 5 (2): 4-5. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.11671
  Egloff W, Patterson D, Agosti D, Hagedorn G 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2015</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2015/</guid>
      <description>Dikow T, Agosti D. 2015. Utilizing online resources for taxonomy: a cybercatalog of Afrotropical apiocerid flies (Insecta: Diptera: Apioceridae). Biodiversity Data Journal 3: e5707 (06 Oct 2015. doi: 10.3897/BDJ.3.e5707
  Egloff W, Agosti D, Patterson D, Penev L 2015. EU BON Policy Brief on Open Data. Website, doi: 10.5281/zenodo.188391
  Guralnick RP, Cellinese N, Deck J, Pyle RL, Kunze J, Penev L, Walls R, Hagedorn G, Agosti D, Wieczorek J, Catapano T, Page R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2016</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2016/</guid>
      <description>Senderov V, Georgiev TA, Agosti D, Catapano T, Sautter G, Ó Tuama É, Franz N, Simov K, Stoev P, Penev L 2016. The Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management System: A Semantic Suite Running on top of the Biodiversity Knowledge Graph. TDWG 2016 conference presentation abstract. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.841648
  Faulwetter S, Pafilis E, Fanini L, Bailly N, Agosti D, Arvantidis C, Boicenco L, Catapano T, Claus S, Dekeyzer S, Georgiev T, Legaki A, Mavraki D, Oulas A, Papastefanou G, Penev L, Sautter G, Schigel, Senderov V, Teaca A, Tsompanou M 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2017</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2017/</guid>
      <description>Bingham H, Doudin M, Weatherdon LV, Despot-Belmonte K, Wetzel FT, Groom Q, Lewis E, Appeltrans W, Güntsch A, Mergen P, Agosti D, Penev L, Hoffmann A, Saarenmaa H, Geller G, Kim K Kim H, Archambeau AS, Häuser C, Schmeller DS, Ilse Geijzendorffer, Camacho AG, Guerra C, Robertson T, Runnel V, Valland N, Martin CS 2017. The Biodiversity Informatics Landscape: Elements, Connections and Opportunities. Research Ideas and Outcome 3: e14059.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2018</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2018/</guid>
      <description>Agosti D 2018. Bezahlschranken für Schnappschüsse? Neue Zürcher Zeitung, Gastkommentar, 29.11.2018. link
  Penev L, Agosti D, Georgiev T, Senderov V, Sautter G, Catapano T, Stoev P 2018. The Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management (eco-)System: Tools and services for extraction, mobilization, handling and re-use of data from the published literature. Biodiversity Information Science and Standards 2: e25748. doi: 10.3897/biss.2.25748
  Hardisty AR, Michener WK, Agosti D, .. Egloff W, &amp;hellip; (26 authors) 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2019</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2019/</guid>
      <description>Chester C, Agosti D, Sautter G, Catapano T, Martens K, Gérard I, Bénicou L 2019. EJT editorial standard for the semantic enhancement of specimen data in taxonomy literature. European Journal of Taxonomy 586: 1-22. doi: 10.5852/ejt.2019.586
  Saarenma H, Agosti D, Dillen M, Egloff W, Gagnier P-Y, Groom Q, Hardisty A, Raes N. 2019. Open access implementation guidelines for DiSSCo. Deliverable D6.5. ICEDIG, Helsinki. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.3465285
  Agosti D, Nielsen LH, Dillen M, Groom Q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2020</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2020/</guid>
      <description>Mottin L, Ruch P, Mottaz A, Naderi N, Caucheteur D, Agosti D, Matentzoglu N, Michel PA, Pendlington Z, Roncaglia P 2020. CoVoc Coronavirus Vocabulary
  Rivera-Quiroz A, Petchaard B, Miller JA 2020. Mining data from legacy taxonomic literature and application for sampling spiders of the Teutamus group (Araneae; Liocranidae) in Southeast Asia. Scientific Reports 10: 15787. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-72549-8
  Dimitrova M, Poelen J, Zhelezov G, Georgiev T, Agosti D, Penev L 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications 2021</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2021/</guid>
      <description>Abrahamse T, Andrade-Correa MG, Arida C, Galsim R, Häuser C, Price M, Sommerwerk N 2021. The Global Taxonomy Initiative in Support of the Post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework. CBD Technical Series No. 96. Secretariat of the Convention on Biological Diversity, Montreal, 103 pages. (Plazi: participant) doi: https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5728812
  Agosti D, Cornwell P, Bénichou L, Gonzalez J, Herren M, Ruch P 2021. Progress with improving preservation and reuse of scientific research data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications from 2010 and earlier</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2010-and-earlier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/about/publications/2010-and-earlier/</guid>
      <description>2010
  Catapano T 2010. TaxPub: An Extension of the NLM/NCBI Journal Publishing DTD for Taxonomic Descriptions. Proceedings of the Journal Article Tag Suite Conference 2010 doi: 10.5281/zenodo.3484285 Article
  Penev L, Roberts D, Smith VS, Agosti D, Erwin T. 2010. Taxonomy shifts up a gear: New publishing tools to accelerate biodiversity research. ZooKeys 50: i-iv. doi: 10​.3897/zookeys.50.543
  Penev L, Agosti D, Georgiev T, Catapano T, Miller J, Blagoderov V, Roberts D, Smith VS, Brake I, Ryrcroft S, Scott B, Johnson NF, Morris RA, Sautter G, Chavan V, Robertson T, Remsen D, Stoev P, Parr C, Knapp S, Kress WJ, Thompson FC, Erwin T.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
