<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>projects on Plazi</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/tags/projects/</link><description>Recent content in projects on Plazi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stage.plazi.org/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building the European Biodiversity Observation Network</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/ongoing/eu-bon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/ongoing/eu-bon/</guid><description>EU BON (2012) stands for “Building the European Biodiversity Observation Network” and is an European research project, financed by the 7th EU framework programme for research and development (FP7). EU BON seeks ways to better integrate biodiversity information and implement into policy and decision-making of biodiversity monitoring and management in the EU.
Plazi’s activities:
Develop and provide access to biodiversity content from the published - scientific record develop data standards and exchange protocols develop the legal framework for data publishing and dissemination explore ways to involve citizen science to mobilize biodiversity data</description></item><item><title>LinkD</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/past/linkd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/past/linkd/</guid><description>LinkD (pronounced &amp;lsquo;linked&amp;rsquo;) will unite European biodiversity scientists behind a common set of infrastructures and goals leveraging existing investment in biodiversity science infrastructures in support of the long-term community inspired vision of modelling the biosphere.
Submitted to EU Horizon 2020, EINFRA-9-2015 | e-Infrastructures for Virtual Research Environments (VRE), January 2015. Participation: Partner</description></item><item><title>pro-iBiosphere</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/past/pro-ibiosphere/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/past/pro-ibiosphere/</guid><description>The aim of pro-iBiosphere is to prepare (= pro), through a coordination action, the ground for an integrative system (= sphere) for intelligent (= i) management of biodiversity (= bio) knowledge. Once it becomes operational, the European Open Biodiversity Knowledge Management System will play a major role in facilitating the synthesis of core biodiversity data by creating an authoritative framework including, discovery of new species, naming of specimens and species, identification tools, descriptions, and various other basic types of information.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/resources/services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/resources/services/</guid><description>Plazi offers services and consultancies in the areas of developing and maintaining schemas related to scientific literature, legal analyses and policies in area of scientific literature and data sharing, and brokering and providing data conversion. Publications and lectures are also available. For inquiries, please contact us via email.</description></item><item><title>Wiki4R</title><link>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/past/wiki4r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:16:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://stage.plazi.org/projects/past/wiki4r/</guid><description>Wiki4R will create an innovative virtual research environment (VRE) for Open Science at scale, engaging both professional researchers and citizen data scientists in new and potentially transformative forms of collaboration.
It is based on the realizations that (1) the structured parts of the Web itself can be regarded as a VRE, (2) such environments depend on communities, (3) closed environments are limited in their capacity to nurture thriving communities.
Wiki4R will therefore integrate Wikidata, the multilingual semantic backbone behind Wikipedia, into existing research processes to enable transdisciplinary research and reduce fragmentation of research in and outside Europe.</description></item></channel></rss>