<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 Post Archives on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 Post Archives on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 11:54:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plazi.org/posts/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Biodiversity Literature Repository — Open By Design</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</guid>
      <description>The Open Definition version 2.1 prescribes four conditions for openness of a work &amp;ndash;
it must be published under an open license or be in the public domain, it must be accessible easily and at no more than the cost of reproduction, preferably be downloadable via the internet it must be readily readable by a computer, and it must be available in an open format. It is clear that openness is not just a matter of sticking an open license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcadia Fund supports Plazi in its endeavor to rediscover known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:25:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</guid>
      <description>The Swiss-based Plazi NGO has received a grant of EUR 1.5 million from Arcadia Fund – a charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin – to further develop its Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR) established in collaboration with Zenodo, the open science repository hosted and managed by the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), and the open-access scholarly publisher and technology provider Pensoft.
Source: Eurekalert
Figure left: A figure extracted from a scholarly article and made accessible via BLR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einen Einblick und Einstieg in die versteckte Vielfalt der 2021 publizierten Hymenopteren</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</guid>
      <description> Program Presentation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberation of data from taxonomic treatments</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:50:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</guid>
      <description>Plazi will present its groundbreaking approach to the &amp;ldquo;liberation&amp;rdquo; of data from taxonomic treatments within scholarly publications at the World Biodiversity Forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</guid>
      <description>Donat Agosti will provide the lecture Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense except in the light of treatments at the conference of the Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections (SPNHC).
The goal of taxonomic literature is to describe taxonomic diversity as a result of charting the Earth&amp;rsquo;s biological diversity. As research adds to our knowledge, our understanding of taxa increases with additional published results. This is how it has happened since the standard publications by Linnaeus in 1753 and 1758 in the format of taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of text about a particular taxon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Known Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>We will take you on a journey into the world of biodiversity data standards and tools and will inform you on the latest developments in the world of Biodiversity Informatics, both internationally and locally. What is the state of the art in initiatives like GBIF, LifeWatch and DiSSCo, etc and how can we let them work for us? We have invited some very interesting international speakers and will inform you on the progress made by these projects in Belgium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to taxonomic treatments mentioned in press releases</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</guid>
      <description>At year-end, it is common to review the past year’s highlights as we (Plazi) too did, highlighting a few of the almost 9000 species discovered in 2021. A few of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading taxonomic institutions did so as well with their recent discoveries. Since we are interested in not just finding about the species discovered but also learning more in detail about them, we decided to test how easy it was to locate their original taxonomic treatments in the scientific papers that described the species mentioned in the press releases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
