<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 Post Archives on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 Post Archives on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 16:04:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/posts/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TDWG 2022</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/10/tdwg2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 12:57:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/10/tdwg2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt;&#xA;    &lt;summary&gt;Enabling Published Taxonomic Data to Address the Biodiversity Crisis&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The use-case of Biodiversity Literature Repository and TreatmentBank&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date and Time:&lt;/b&gt; Oct 17, 2022, 2:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt; To understand the loss of species, a benchmark is needed, e.g. the status of biodiversity in 1992 when the Convention on Biological Diversity recognized biodiversity crisis to compare to its status in the successive year. Though we are far from knowning how many species there are on planet Earth, we keep track of their descriptions and number through the information kept in our libraries. Each species discovered is represented therein by at least one taxononic treatment. The library includes an estimated 500 million pages and is updated daily with an estimated 17–18,000 new species annually and over 100,000 treatments augmenting the knowledge of existing species. &lt;a href=&#34;https://biss.pensoft.net/article/91167/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Day on Open/FAIR Natural History Data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/09/glamhack-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 17:54:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/09/glamhack-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The Workshop Day on Open/FAIR Natural History Data is intended for curators, managers, and users of natural history collections in Switzerland. It serves as a forum to draw up an overview of the current situation regarding data management and digitization in Swiss institutions and sets the collections and their data in the wider context of the emerging ecosystem of open/FAIR natural history data with its various infrastructures, stakeholders, initiatives, usage scenarios, value-added services, and governance structures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomic Treatments as Open FAIR Digital Objects</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/fair-digital-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:11:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/fair-digital-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy is the science of charting and describing the worlds biodiversity. Organisms are grouped into taxa which are given a given rank building the taxonomic hierarchy. The taxa are described in taxonomic treatments, well defined sections of scientific publications (Catapano 2019). They include a nomenclatural section and one or more sections including descriptions, material citations referring to studied specimens, or notes ecology and behavior. In case the treatment does not describe a new discovered taxon, previous treatments are cited in the form of treatment citations. This citation can refer to a previous treatment and add additional data, or it can be a statement synonymizing the taxon with another taxon. This allows building a citation network, and ultimately is a constituent part of the catalogue of life. Thus treatments play an important role to understand the diversity of life on Earth by providing the scientific argument why group of organism is a new species, or a synonym, and the data provided will increasingly be important to analyze and compare whole genomes of individual genomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Copyright-Free Taxonomic Treatments as New Resources for Biodiversity Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/divisive-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/divisive-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Divisive Power of Citizenship, one of our Institute’s SNSF-funded project, concludes this year with its closing international conference on 22/23 September 2022 in Basel, Switzerland. This event will offer a broad platform for debate about citizenship in a global context, addressing scholars working in the fields of Global History, Asian Studies, International Law and Digital Humanities, at a time of terrifying topicality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The central themes of discussion will be expat communities in Asia, and civil internment camps during the Second World War in Asia, which have been rarely studied until now. An additional methodological component will investigate the potential of digital methods in this field, which will analyse the impact of access to precise data at scale relating to networks of foreign residents—addressing interferences with citizenship, statelessness and denaturalisation. The conference will also form the launch for new data resources which have been created during the course of the project, covering Foreign Residents in East Asia between 1863 and 1941.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>400 Years of Botanical Collections – Implications for Present-Day Research</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/400-years-of-botanical-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/400-years-of-botanical-collections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bauhin’s pioneering Flora of Basel „Catalogus Plantarum circa Basileam sponte nascentium“ exactly 400 years ago is a precursor to the artificially identified beginning of taxonomic publishing with Linnaeus Systema plantarum … 1753. Indeed, botanical publishing existed far before Linnaeus’, however his contribution has not only been the Latin Binomen, but the highly structured way he published the taxonomic treatments for each species, and to cite previous works. In the digital age, this kind of structuring of the information and the existing implicit citation links allows building the biodiversity knowledge graph, opening up the entire corpus of taxonomic treatments imprisoned in publications by providing it in a format that can be found and reused, cited and linked to data referenced in the publications. This provides access to all the published data about a specimen in a natural history collection, to trace back the history of a taxonomic name or the traits used to describe and deliminit the species. The Swiss based Biodiversity Literature Repository and TreatmentBank provide access to over 750,000 taxonomic treatments, over 1M material citations and are the largest data set provider to the Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF). This highly automated workflow has and continues to liberate data from over 70,000 publications, which are further converted to RDF and structured into Linked Open Data via the OpenBiodiv Biodiversity Knowledge Graph. At the same time new ways to structure publications so that their resident data can immediately be reused upon publication are being developed in collaboration with Pensoft publishers, the Muséum d’histoire naturelle, Paris and the CETAF publishing group. The Swiss NGO Plazi, Zenodo at CERN and SIBiLS at the Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics are involved in the EU Horizon 2020 project BiCIKL and the Swissuniversities funded project eBioDiv to develop ways to link data in publications to specimens, taxonomic names and genes and vice versa. This lecture will explain the concept and state of the art in taxonomic publishing, access and reuse of its data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do we not know – quantifying data gaps and biases in knowledge of bat co-roosting</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/what-we-dont-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 13:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/08/what-we-dont-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Improved understanding of co-habitation of roosts by multiple species of bats is essential for estimating the risks of zoonotic disease transmission. However, ecological data on roosting environments, species richness, bat-bat interactions, viral infections, and other species interactions are scattered throughout the literature, making them difficult to study on a global scale. The research scope for most roost studies has been narrow, focusing on roost type, bat abundance, and locality data while failing to investigate interspecific roosting interactions. To meet this need, we have collaboratively built an open-access dataset of ecological interactions (including co-roosting, trophic, anthropogenic, and parasitic) extracted from the literature to improve our understanding of roost dynamics on a global scale, and to elucidate the role of shared roosts in disease transmission. As of April 2022, &amp;gt; 11,500 interaction records involving &amp;gt; 360 bat species from &amp;gt; 137 countries encompassing a variety of habitats have been extracted from &amp;gt; 175 publications spanning from 1860-2020, all accessible via the Coronavirus-Host community at Zenodo. With this benchmark dataset of open-access digitized interaction data, tools, and workflows, we provide evidence of co-roosting events that we aligned with multiple ontologies (interaction terms, taxonomies, administrative regions) and phylogenies suitable for high-throughput analysis We followed open access and FAIR (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable) data principles for extracting data and choosing methodologies. We identify biases in the coverage of bat interaction records, suggest new tools for biodiversity informatics, and explore obstacles and opportunities in the mining of eco-interactions previously lost in the annals of scientific literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biodiversity Literature Repository — Open By Design</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/blr-open-by-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Open Definition version 2.1 prescribes four conditions for openness of a work &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be published under an open license or be in the public domain,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be accessible easily and at no more than the cost of reproduction, preferably be downloadable via the internet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be readily readable by a computer, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it must be available in an open format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is clear that openness is not just a matter of sticking an open license. Openness has to be a fundamental goal and part of the design. This becomes all the more important for complicated endeavors such as scientific data that need to exist in a stable form far into the future (&amp;ldquo;forever&amp;rdquo;). At Plazi we have been extracting data from biodiversity literature and making it FAIR and open for more than a decade. To do this, we have built (or helped build) the tools, the procedures, the repositories, the standards, and the partnerships to extract, clean, archive and disseminate data for perpetuity. &lt;a href=&#34;https://punkish.org/Biodiversity-Literature-Repository/&#34;&gt;In this presentation&lt;/a&gt; we will share our experience building a lasting research infrastructure that is open by design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arcadia supports Plazi in its endeavor to rediscover known biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:25:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/05/arcadia-fund-supports-plazi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Swiss-based &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt; NGO has received a grant of EUR 1.5 million from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt; – a charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin – to further develop its &lt;a href=&#34;https://biolitrepo.org/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity Literature Repository (BLR)&lt;/a&gt; established in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;, the open science repository hosted and managed by the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), and the open-access scholarly publisher and technology provider &lt;a href=&#34;https://pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Pensoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/952793&#34;&gt;Eurekalert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/hero.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure left:&lt;/b&gt; A figure extracted from a scholarly article and made accessible via BLR. The image in preview mode can be downloaded inclusive of source in the metadata. Visible are links to other data elements from the article citing the figure, the source publication, a machine readable license and download alternatives. A deposit of a figure extracted from a scholarly article and made accessible via the Biodiversity Literature Repository. The image in preview mode can be downloaded inclusive of source in the metadata. On the right, there are links to other data elements from the article citing the figure, the source publication, a machine readable license and alternatives to download the data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.253091&#34;&gt;DOI: 10.5281/zenodo.253091&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Einen Einblick und Einstieg in die versteckte Vielfalt der 2021 publizierten Hymenopteren</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/schweizer-hymenopterologen-tagung/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1QSdEGwgAIH2_ntZ4sHtMRE26-PTeLF9r/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5916757&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberation of data from taxonomic treatments</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:50:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/world-biodiversity-forum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donat Agosti will present &lt;a href=&#34;https://wbf2022.abstractserver.com/program/#/details/presentations/173&#34;&gt;Beyond the Print and PDF Prison: Data About Biodiveristy Want to be Free&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing Plazi’s groundbreaking approach to the liberation of data from taxonomic treatments within scholarly publications at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbiodiversityforum.org/en/welcome-to-wbf-2022&#34;&gt;World Biodiversity Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Most of what scientists discovered about biodiversity and published, totaling a corpus of an estimated 500 million printed pages stacked up in our libraries  and more recently, in digital format, is not known. It is an amount of information that can not be processed by humans, but even machines can’t cope with it because the publications are either not scanned, or are behind paywalls, or in formats that machines can’t read at scale. It is a tragedy that in this digital age we can’t make use of this data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:48:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/spnhc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donat Agosti will provide the lecture &lt;em&gt;Nothing in (taxonomic) publishing makes sense except in the light of treatments&lt;/em&gt; at the conference of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://spnhc2022.com/about/&#34;&gt;Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections (SPNHC)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of taxonomic literature is to describe taxonomic diversity as a result of charting the Earth&amp;rsquo;s biological diversity. As research adds to our knowledge, our understanding of taxa increases with additional published results. This is how it has happened since the standard publications by Linnaeus in 1753 and 1758 in the format of taxonomic treatments, clearly delimited sections of text about a particular taxon. Later, material citations were added, providing an explicit link to the material that led to the published research result. Each treatment has a nomenclatural section including the referenced taxonomic name representing the usage of a specific citable name. Thus, the taxonomic name Apis mellifera L, 1758 refers to the taxonomic treatment published by Linnaeus 1758 on page 576. Later usage of the name cites this treatment thereby adding new research to the scientific corpus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Known Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 21:45:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/empowering-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will take you on a journey into the world of biodiversity data standards and tools and will inform you on the latest developments in the world of Biodiversity Informatics, both internationally and locally. What is the state of the art in initiatives like GBIF, LifeWatch and DiSSCo, etc and how can we let them work for us? We have invited some very interesting international speakers and will inform you on the progress made by these projects in Belgium. During this conference we will build a bridge between Biodiversity informatics and its older relative “Bioinformatics” and investigate what a crossover of these two worlds can bring to Biodiversity Research. Genomic information meets digital taxonomy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access to taxonomic treatments mentioned in press releases</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2022/01/access-to-data-in-press-releases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At year-end, it is common to review the past year’s highlights as we (Plazi) too did, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/posts/2021/12/new-species-2021/&#34;&gt;highlighting a few of the almost 9000 species discovered in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. A few of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading taxonomic institutions did so as well with their recent discoveries. Since we are interested in not just finding about the species discovered but also learning more in detail about them, we decided to test how easy it was to locate their original taxonomic treatments in the scientific papers that described the species mentioned in the press releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
