<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Training on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 16:31:21 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enabling South African scientists to convert taxonomic publications into digitally accessible knowledge</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/training-s-african-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 18:18:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/training-s-african-scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/participants.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Group photo of the participants&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sanbi.org/&#34;&gt;SANBI &lt;/a&gt;(South African National Biodiversity Institute) conducted a training Course in Pretoria April 18 to 21, 2023, to teach local scientists how to facilitate the access and reuse of scholarly published taxonomic data by themselves as well as the scientific community at large.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course had the participation of 21 researchers, curators, technicians, and Postgraduate students from different South Africa&amp;rsquo;s biodiversity institutions and Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specimen - material citation matching service training course</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/specimen-material-citation-matching-service-training-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/03/specimen-material-citation-matching-service-training-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;img/participants.jpg&#34; width=&#34;960&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Participants in the training course&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plazi’s first online two day training course “&lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity and Digital Media: linking material citations in publications to specimens&lt;/a&gt;” organized by Julia Giora and Jonas Castro has successfully ended. The Training school happened online from the 27th to the 28th of February 2023. It is part of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://plazi.org/posts/2023/02/expanding-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/&#34;&gt;series of training courses&lt;/a&gt; in which Plazi expects to teach interested parties how to use data preparation tools to become a data liberator. It was organized in collaborations with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobilise-action.eu/&#34;&gt;Mobilise COST Action&lt;/a&gt; – Mobilising Data, Policies and Experts in Scientific Collections – providing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobilise-action.eu/2023/01/24/plazi-mobilise-online-training-school-ts-announcement-27-28-feb-2023/&#34;&gt;Training School&lt;/a&gt; (TS) “&#xA;This hands-on and interactive training initiative gave the opportunity to 20 participants, from 11 countries, and representing 14 institutions of natural history research to get informed and exercised on the accessibility and reuse of taxonomic data using digital platforms and repositories.&#xA;The main theoretical topics addressed were the concept of findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://force11.org/info/the-fair-data-principles/&#34;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt;) and Plazi workflow, the repositories for taxonomic data, and an outlook on how to convert data from missing publications aiming a future of publishing according to FAIR data requirements. The practical activities were focused on the learning and use of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://prod.ebiodiv.org/&#34;&gt;eBioDiv Matching Service&lt;/a&gt;, with participants linking specimens in Global Biodiversity Information Facility (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gbif.org/&#34;&gt;GBIF&lt;/a&gt;) to materials citations extracted from scholarly publications and made available through Plazi&amp;rsquo;s TreatmentBank.&#xA;The development of tools and learning module is co-funded through &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training course</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/01/training-biodiv-digital-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 16:18:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/01/training-biodiv-digital-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This hands-on and interactive training will give students and professionals of natural history institutions an opportunity to get informed about and practice the liberation and reuse of taxonomic data using digital platforms and repositories. Applicants need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/W14eqekgN1NYuB29A&#34;&gt;register online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
