<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TDWG on Plazi</title>
    <link>https://plazi.org/tags/tdwg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TDWG on Plazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 17:47:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://plazi.org/tags/tdwg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publishing: Extending the biodiversity knowledge graph</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/extending-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/extending-the-biodiv-knowledge-graph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A goal of natural history institutions is contributing to the understanding of biodiversity and disseminating this knowledge by becoming scientific publishers. Through this, they joined the growing field of scholarly publishing established in 1665 by the Journal des sçavans to publish work from the sciences. One of the characteristics of scientific publishing is to cite previous works and thus linking existing knowledge with new discoveries. To provide access to the growing corpus of publications, libraries began to index individual works. With the advent of the digital age, full text search and text and data mining provide access to the content using machines analysing large corpora of works. The development of the semantic web enabled creating a knowledge graph. A typical example is the growth of knowledge related to a species, including synonyms, cited specimens, figures or DNA sequences. During this symposium the state and recent developments of biodiversity publishing, linking and providing increased access to data by &lt;a href=&#34;https://pensoft.net/&#34;&gt;Pensoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cetaf.org/&#34;&gt;CETAF&lt;/a&gt;-publishing group, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mnhn.fr/en&#34;&gt;MNHN Paris&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;, including over 50 journals in a semantic enhanced format, and supported by a series of projects (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ebiodiv.org/&#34;&gt;eBioDiv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcadiafund.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Arcadia fund&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ouvrirlascience.fr/metostem-2/&#34;&gt;MétoSTeM&lt;/a&gt;) will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The BiCIKL toolbox to link biodiversity data</title>
      <link>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/toolbox-to-link-biodiv-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://plazi.org/posts/2023/05/toolbox-to-link-biodiv-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will demonstrate tools and infrastructure from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bicikl-project.eu/&#34;&gt;BiCIKL&lt;/a&gt; project to find and establish links between entities. These include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure to create and manage machine actionable persistent identifiers (PIDs) for digital specimens. This allows the creation and annotation of digital specimens as new actionable objects on the internet, which provide a surrogate for physical specimens.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openbiodiv.net/&#34;&gt;OpenBiodiv&lt;/a&gt; is a linked open data (LOD) knowledge graph extracted from the biodiversity literature. OpenBiodiv can discover hidden links, e.g., between authors, taxa, sequences, material citations, publications and others using general search, SPARQL (query language), user applications and API.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/treatmentbank/&#34;&gt;TreatmentBank&lt;/a&gt; liberates data from within publications, and converts, enhances, links, stores, and disseminates it as findable, accessible, interoperable and reusable (FAIR) data. The API has been enhanced allowing better data linkages through identifiers, matching services, and avenues for annotation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/resources/sibils&#34;&gt;SIBiLS&lt;/a&gt; custom search services provide access to biomedical literature, including PubMed Central (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/&#34;&gt;PMC&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nlm.nih.gov/medline/index.html&#34;&gt;MEDLINE&lt;/a&gt;. It also provides access to half a million taxonomic treatments curated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://plazi.org/&#34;&gt;Plazi&lt;/a&gt;. BICIKL has helped aggregate more publications, enabling the creation of an all-inclusive “One Health” library, the BiodiversityPMC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.checklistbank.org/&#34;&gt;ChecklistBank&lt;/a&gt; is an open data repository with a focus on taxonomy and nomenclature. It has tools for name matching, dataset comparison, and for linking taxonomic names from literature.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
